<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<searchresult>
<query>Global</query>
<document id="1">
<title>Using mixed objects in the training of object-based image classifications</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.rse.2016.12.017</url>
<snippet>Image classification for thematic mapping is a very common application in remote sensing, which is sometimes realized through object-based image analysis. In these analyses, it is common for some of the objects to be mixed in their class composition and thus violate the commonly made assumption of object purity that is implicit in a conventional object-based image analysis. Mixed objects can be a problem throughout a classification analysis, but are particularly challenging in the training stage as they can result in degraded training statistics and act to reduce mapping accuracy. In this paper the potential of using mixed objects in training object-based image classifications is evaluated. Remotely sensed data were submitted to a series of segmentation analyses from which a range of under- to over-segmented outputs were intentionally produced. Training objects were then selected from the segmentation outputs, resulting in training data sets that varied in terms of size (i.e. number of objects) and proportion of mixed objects. These training data sets were then used with an artificial neural network and a generalized linear model, which can accommodate objects of mixed composition, to produce a series of land cover maps. The use of training statistics estimated based on both pure and mixed objects often increased classification accuracy by around 25&#37; when compared with accuracies obtained from the use of only pure objects in training. So rather than the mixed objects being a problem, they can be an asset in classification and facilitate land cover mapping from remote sensing. It is, therefore, desirable to recognize the nature of the objects and possibly accommodate mixed objects directly in training. The results obtained here may also have implications for the common practice of seeking an optimal segmentation output, and also act to challenge the widespread view that object-based classification is superior to pixel-based classification. (C) 2016 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.
WOS:000394399300015
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="2">
<title>DEEP CONTEXTUAL DESCRIPTION OF SUPERPIXELS FOR AERIAL URBAN SCENES CLASSIFICATION</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>This paper proposes a new approach for contextual feature extraction from superpixels in aerial urban scenes. Our method extracts features with many levels of context from superpixels by exploiting different layers of a pre-trained convolutional neural network. Experimental results show the effectiveness of the proposed approach, which outperforms traditional methods based on handcrafted feature extraction algorithms.
WOS:000426954603031
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="3">
<title>Integrating Object Boundary in Super-Resolution Land-Cover Mapping</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2016.2533571</url>
<snippet>This paper proposes a novel class allocation strategy in units of object (UOO) for soft-then-hard super-resolution mapping (STHSRM). STHSRM involves two processes: 1) subpixel sharpening and 2) class allocation. The UOO is implemented in the second process by integrating the object boundaries as an additional structural constraint. First, UOO obtains the object boundaries from remote-sensing images by image segmentation. The number of subpixels within an object is then calculated for each class to meet the coherence constraint of fractional images imposed by soft classification. Finally, a linear optimization model is built for each object to obtain the optimal hard class labels of subpixels. A synthetic image and two real remote-sensing images are used to evaluate the effectiveness of UOO. The results are compared visually and quantitatively with two existing class allocation methods: 1) the highest attribute values first (HAVF) and 2) units of class (UOC). The experimental results show that UOO performs better than these twomethods. UOO can better reduce the salt and pepper effect in resultant maps than both HAVF and UOC when dealing with real remote-sensing images. Moreover, UOO can better maintain the structure of land-cover patches, with smoother boundaries as compared with the two methods.
WOS:000391719900020
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="4">
<title>Incorporating Open Source Data for Bayesian Classification of Urban Land Use From VHR Stereo Images</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2017.2737702</url>
<snippet>This study investigates the incorporation of open source data into a Bayesian classification of urban land use from very high resolution (VHR) stereo satellite images. The adopted classification framework starts from urban land cover classification, proceeds to building-type characterization, and results in urban land use. For urban land cover classification, a preliminary classification distinguishes trees, grass, and shadow objects using a random forest at a fine segmentation level. Fuzzy decision trees derived from hierarchical Bayesian models separate buildings from other man-made objects at a coarse segmentation level, where an open street map provides prior building information. A Bayesian network classifier combining commonly used land use indicators and spatial arrangement is used for the urban land use classification. The experiments were conducted on GeoEye stereo images over Oklahoma City, USA. Experimental results showed that the urban land use classification using VHR stereo images performed better than that using a monoscopic VHR image, and the integration of open source data improved the final urban land use classification. Our results also show a way of transferring the adopted urban land use classification framework, developed for a specific urban area in China, to other urban areas. The study concludes that incorporating open source data by Bayesian analysis improves urban land use classification. Moreover, a pretrained convolutional neural network fine tuned on the UC Merced land use dataset offers a useful tool to extract additional information for urban land use classification.
WOS:000415719000022
</snippet>
</document>

</searchresult>
