<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<searchresult>
<query>Global</query>
<document id="1">
<title>Land parcel-based digital soil mapping of soil nutrient properties in an alluvial-diluvia plain agricultural area in China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geoderma.2019.01.018</url>
<snippet>The ability to accurately and precisely perform soil nutrient mapping over large areas is essential in the decision-making processes for precision agriculture. However, existing grid-based or non-grid-based digital soil mapping (DSM) can lead to the problem of mixed units of input information, which causes the mapping results to be unsuitable for direct use in guiding the implementation of precision agriculture. Instead, the goal of this study was to achieve DSM based on land parcels, which are the basic units of agricultural management and have practical geographical significance for precision mapping in agricultural areas. This study established a convolutional neural network-based automatic extraction model to extract land parcels from high resolution remote sensing images. Thirty environmental covariates were chosen and calibrated at land parcels to establish the relationships between soils and landscapes. Four prediction algorithms, namely, ordinary kriging, cokriging, random forest and artificial neural network, were combined with the land-parcel-based DSM framework to develop and evaluate their effectiveness in predicting four topsoil nutrient properties in an alluvial-diluvia plain agricultural region located in Ningxia province, China. The results of comparisons show that, overall, the land-parcel-based RF model achieved the best prediction accuracy; its relative improvement (RMSE&#37;) values over the competing models were 1.27, 4.23, 3.19 and 9.01 for soil organic matter, soil total nitrogen, available phosphorus and available potassium, respectively. In addition, land-parcel-based mapping can improve algorithmic efficiency by approximately 4 times by effectively reducing the mapping units for complex agricultural areas compared with the grid-based mapping results when using the same algorithm, and it also achieves a better performance at the detail level. Overall, the land-parcel-based DSM approach achieved good results in plain agricultural areas, but the model still needs improvement for land-parcel-based DSM in mountainous and hilly agricultural areas, and a challenge remains in selecting the most appropriate environmental covariates.
WOS:000457949200023
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="2">
<title>Digital soil mapping algorithms and covariates for soil organic carbon mapping and their implications: A review</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geoderma.2019.05.031</url>
<snippet>This article reviews the current research and applications of various digital soil mapping (DSM) techniques used to map Soil Organic Carbon (SOC) concentration and stocks following a systematic mapping approach from 2013 until present (18 February 2019). It is intended that this review of relevant literature will assist prospective researchers by identifying knowledge clusters and gaps in relation to the digital mapping of SOC. Of 120 studies, most were clustered in some specific countries such as China, Australia and the USA. The highest number publications were in 2016 and 2017. Regarding the predictive models, there was a progression from Linear Models towards Machine Learning (ML) techniques, and hybrid models in Regression Kriging (RK) framework performed better than individual models. Multiple Linear Regression (MLR) was the most frequently used method for predicting SOC, although it was outperformed by other ML techniques in most studies. Random Forest (RF) was found to perform better than MLR and other ML techniques in most comparative studies. Other common and competitive techniques were Cubist, Neural Network (NN), Boosted Regression Tree (BRT), Support Vector Machine (SVM) and Geographically Weighted Regression (GWR). Due to the inconsistency in various comparative studies, it would be advisable to calibrate the competitive algorithms using specific experimental datasets. This review also reveals the environmental covariates that have been identified as the most important by RF technique in recent years in regard to digital mapping of SOC, which may assist in selecting optimum sets of environmental covariates for mapping SOC. Covariates representing organism/organic activities were among the most frequent among top five covariates, followed by the variables representing climate and topography. Climate was reported to be influential in determining the variation in SOC level at regional scales, followed by parent materials, topography and land use. However, for mapping at a resolution that represents smaller areas such as a farm- or plot-scale, land use and vegetation indices were stated to be more influential in predicting SOC. Furthermore, unlike a previous review work, all recent studies in this review incorporated validation and 41&#37; of them estimated spatially explicit prediction of uncertainty. Only 9.16&#37; studies performed external validation, whereas most studies used data-splitting and cross-validation techniques which may not be the best options for datasets obtained through non-probability sampling.
WOS:000485207300038
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="3">
<title>Digital soil mapping and its implications in the extrapolation of soil-landscape relationships in detailed scale</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1590/S0100-204X2017000800009</url>
<snippet>The objective of this work was to test the extrapolation of soil-landscape relationships in a reference area (RA) to a topographic map (scale 1:50,000), using digital soil mapping (DSM), and to compare these results to those obtained in similar studies previously conducted in Brazil. A soil survey in a 10 km(2) RA, using conventional mapping techniques (scale 1:10,000), was made in order to map a 678 km(2) physiographically similar area (scale 1:50,000) using DSM. The decision tree technique was employed to build a predictive extrapolation model based on soil classes and eight terrain attributes in the RA. The validation of DSM by application of field observation points resulted in a 66.1&#37; global accuracy and in 0.36 kappa index. The most representative soils in the area were correctly predicted, whereas the less representative and less frequent soils in the landscape (and consequently with reduced sampling) had their prediction compromised. The RA proportion, which equals 1.5&#37; of the total area, is a limiting factor in the formulation of soil-landscape relationships to precisely represent the mapped area by DSM.
WOS:000412277200009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="4">
<title>Spatial prediction of rainfall-induced landslides for the Lao Cai area (Vietnam) using a hybrid intelligent approach of least squares support vector machines inference model and artificial bee colony optimization</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10346-016-0711-9</url>
<snippet>The main objective of this study is to produce a landslide susceptibility map for the Lao Cai area (Vietnam) using a new hybrid intelligent method based on least squares support vector machines (LSSVM) and artificial bee colony (ABC) optimization, namely LSSVM-BC. LSSVM and ABC are state-of-the-art soft computing techniques that have been rarely utilized in landslide susceptibility assessment. LSSVM is adopted to develop landslide prediction model whereas ABC was used to optimize the prediction model by identifying an appropriate set of the LSSVM hyper-parameters. To establish the hybrid intelligent method, a GIS database with ten landslide-influencing factors and 340 landslide locations that occurred mainly during the last 20-years was constructed. These historical landslide locations were collected from the existing inventories that sourced from (i) five landslide projects carried out in this study areas before and (ii) interpretations of SPOT satellite images with resolution of 2.5 m. The study area was geographically split into two different parts, with landslides located in the first part was used for building models whereas the other landslides in the second part was used for the model validation. Performance of the LSSVM-BC model was assessed using the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve and area under the curve (AUC). Result shows that the prediction power of the model is good with the area under the curve (AUC) = 0.900. Experiments have pointed out the prediction power of the LSSVM-BC is better than that obtained from the popular support vector machines. Therefore, the proposed model is a promising tool for spatial prediction of landslides at the study area. The landslide susceptibility map is useful for landuse planning for the Lao Cai area.
WOS:000398889900001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="5">
<title>Spatial prediction of landslide hazard at the Luxi area (China) using support vector machines</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-015-4866-9</url>
<snippet>The main objective of this study is to investigate the potential application of GIS-based Support Vector Machines (SVM) with four kernel functions, i.e., radial basis function (RBF), polynomial (PL), sigmoid (SIG), and linear (LN) for landslide susceptibility mapping at Luxi city in Jiangxi province, China. At the first stage of the study, a landslide inventory map with 282 landslide locations was identified using aerial photographs, satellite images, and field surveys. Of this, 70 &#37; of the landslides (196 landslide locations) are used as a training dataset and the rest (86 landslide locations) were used as the validation dataset. Then, 15 landslide conditioning factors were prepared, i.e., altitude, aspect, slope, stream power index (SPI), topographic wetness index (TWI), sediment transport index (STI), plan curvature, profile curvature, distance from river, distance from road, distance from fault, lithology, land use, NDVI, and rainfall. Using these conditioning factors, landslide susceptibility indexes were calculated using SVM with the four kernel functions. Subsequently, the results were exported and plotted in ArcGIS and four landslide susceptibility maps were produced. The four susceptibility maps were validated and compared using the landslide locations and the success rate and prediction rate methods. The validation results showed that success rates for the four SVM models are 82.0 &#37; (RBF), 83.0 &#37; (PL), 45.0 &#37; (SIG), and 70.0 &#37; (LN). The prediction rates for the four SVM models are 81.0 &#37; (RBF), 71.0 &#37; (PL), 40.0 &#37; (SIG), and LN 63.0 &#37; (SIG). The result shows that the RBF-SVM model has the highest overall performance. The produced susceptibility maps may be useful for general land-use planning in landslides.
WOS:000370239800040
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="6">
<title>Predicting and mapping of soil particle-size fractions with adaptive neuro-fuzzy inference and ant colony optimization in central Iran</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/ejss.12382</url>
<snippet>In arid regions, knowledge of the variation in soil texture is crucial for land management because it affects soil physical, chemical, biological and most importantly hydrological properties. The availability of information on soil texture is scarce even though it is required to support land-use management and sustainable development. Because it is costly to obtain information about the individual particle-size fractions (PSFs), we used digital soil mapping methods (DSM) with environmental covariates that are less costly to obtain. Specifically, we explored the use of a digital elevation model and remote sensing data as environmental covariates to predict the vertical (i.e. 0-0.15, 0.15-0.3, 0.3-0.6 and 0.6-1m) and lateral variation in PSFs over a 150-km(2) area in central Iran. We used a combination of equal-area spline depth functions and three data-mining techniques: multiple linear regression (MLR), artificial neural networks (ANN) and the neuro-fuzzy inference system (ANFIS). In addition, we explored the effect of the reduction in dimension of feature space with ant colony optimization (ACO) and correlation-based feature selection (CFS) on the accuracy of prediction of spatial models for each PSF. The results showed that the prediction of clay at 0-0.15-m depth with ACO indicated the importance of including Landsat ETM+, the digital numbers of band 7 of Landsat images (B7) and clay index, whereas at 0.60-1-m depth the wetness index and multi-resolution valley bottom flatness index (MRVBF) were important. Model evaluation by leave-one-out cross-validation with 191 soil observations indicated that the predictions by the ACO-based ANFIS model (RMSE=4.51&#37; and R-2=0.74 for clay at 0-0.15-m) were more accurate than those by MLR and ANN. Spatial prediction was also better for the topsoil (0-0.15-m) than at depth (RMSE=7.1&#37; for clay at 0.6-1m); therefore, we conclude that the environmental covariates tested cannot resolve subsurface variation as accurately. Nevertheless, we recommend prediction by the ACO-based ANFIS model and splines of lateral and vertical distribution of PSFs in other arid regions of Iran with the same agro-ecological conditions. Digital soil mapping of particle size-fractions (PSF) by adaptive neuro-fuzzy inference and ant colony optimization. Use of ant colony optimization (ACO) to assist in feature selection of environmental covariates. Neuro-fuzzy inference system (ANFIS) superior to multiple linear regression (MLR) and artificial neural networks (ANN). PSF prediction by ACO-based ANFIS model and splines is optimal.
WOS:000388477100001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="7">
<title>Artificial bee colony feature selection algorithm combined with machine learning algorithms to predict vertical and lateral distribution of soil organic matter in South Dakota, USA</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/17583004.2017.1330593</url>
<snippet>The main purpose of this study, is to evaluate an advanced feature selection technique, artificial bee colony (ABC) algorithm; to reduce the number of auxiliary variables derived from a digital elevation model (DEM) and remotely sensed data (e.g. Landsat images). A combination of depth functions (e.g. power, logarithmic and spline) and data miner methods (artificial neural network: ANN and support vector regression: SVR) were applied for three-dimensional mapping of soil organic matter (SOM) in Big Sioux River watershed, South Dakota, USA. Unsurprisingly, the ABC feature selection algorithm indicated that remote sensing data (e.g. NDVI) are powerful predictors at soil surface, however, with the increasing soil depth, the terrain parameters (e.g. wetness index) became more relevant. Our findings from this study demonstrated that both the spatial models generally performed well. The mean R2 values calculated by 10-fold cross validation suggested that SVR and ANN models could explain approximately 50 and 57&#37; of total SOM variability, respectively. However, predictive power of both models increased when ABC feature selection algorithm applied, particularly when it combined with the ANN model. Results showed that DSM approaches are very important and powerful tool to explain the 3D spatial distribution of SOM across the study watershed.
WOS:000404616700006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="8">
<title>Biomass estimation of Sonneratia caseolaris (l.) Engler at a coastal area of Hai Phong city (Vietnam) using ALOS-2 PALSAR imagery and GIS-based multi-layer perceptron neural networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/15481603.2016.1269869</url>
<snippet>This study tested the use of machine learning techniques for the estimation of above-ground biomass (AGB) of Sonneratia caseolaris in a coastal area of Hai Phong city, Vietnam. We employed a GIS database and multi-layer perceptron neural networks (MLPNN) to build and verify an AGB model, drawing upon data from a survey of 1508 mangrove trees in 18 sampling plots and ALOS-2 PALSAR imagery. We assessed the models performance using root-mean-square error, mean absolute error, coefficient of determination (R-2), and leave-one-out cross-validation. We also compared the models usability with four machine learning techniques: support vector regression, radial basis function neural networks, Gaussian process, and random forest. The MLPNN model performed well and outperformed the machine learning techniques. The MLPNN model-estimated AGB ranged between 2.78 and 298.95Mgha(-1) (average=55.8Mgha(-1)); below-ground biomass ranged between 4.06 and 436.47Mgha(-1) (average=81.47Mgha(-1)), and total carbon stock ranged between 3.22 and 345.65Mg C ha(-1) (average=64.52Mg C ha(-1)). We conclude that ALOS-2 PALSAR data can be accurately used with MLPNN models for estimating mangrove forest biomass in tropical areas.
WOS:000399475800004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="9">
<title>Prediction of Soil Organic Carbon based on Landsat 8 Monthly NDVI Data for the Jianghan Plain in Hubei Province, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/rs11141683</url>
<snippet>High-precision maps of soil organic carbon (SOC) are beneficial for managing soil fertility and understanding the global carbon cycle. Digital soil mapping plays an important role in efficiently obtaining the spatial distribution of SOC, which contributes to precision agriculture. However, traditional soil-forming factors (i.e., terrain or climatic factors) have weak variability in low-relief areas, such as plains, and cannot reflect the spatial variation of soil attributes. Meanwhile, vegetation cover hinders the acquisition of the direct information of farmland soil. Thus, useful environmental variables should be utilized for SOC prediction and the digital mapping of such areas. SOC has an important effect on crop growth status, and remote sensing data can record the apparent spectral characteristics of crops. The normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI) is an important index reflecting crop growth and biomass. This study used NDVI time series data rather than traditional soil-forming factors to map SOC. Honghu City, located in the middle of the Jianghan Plain, was selected as the study region, and the NDVI time series data extracted from Landsat 8 were used as the auxiliary variables. SOC maps were estimated through stepwise linear regression (SLR), partial least squares regression (PLSR), support vector machine (SVM), and artificial neural network (ANN). Ordinary kriging (OK) was used as the reference model, while root mean square error of prediction (RMSEP) and coefficient of determination of prediction (R-P(2)) were used to evaluate the model performance. Results showed that SOC had a significant positive correlation in July and August (0.17, 0.29) and a significant negative correlation in January, April, and December (-0.23, -0.27, and -0.23) with NDVI time series data. The best model for SOC prediction was generated by ANN, with the lowest RMSEP of 3.718 and highest R-P(2) of 0.391, followed by SVM (RMSEP = 3.753, R-P(2) = 0.361) and PLSR (RMSEP = 4.087, R-P(2) = 0.283). The SLR model was the worst model, with the lowest R-P(2) of 0.281 and highest RMSEP of 3.930. ANN and SVM were better than OK (RMSEP = 3.727, R-P(2) = 0.372), whereas PLSR and SLR were worse than OK. Moreover, the prediction results using single-data NDVI or short time series NDVI showed low accuracy. The effect of the terrain factor on SOC prediction represented unsatisfactory results. All these results indicated that the NDVI time series data can be used for SOC mapping in plain areas and that the ANN model can maximally extract additional associated information between NDVI time series data and SOC. This study presented an effective method to overcome the selection of auxiliary variables for digital soil mapping in plain areas when the soil was covered with vegetation. This finding indicated that the time series characteristics of NDVI were conducive for predicting SOC in plains.
WOS:000480527800053
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="10">
<title>Predicting soil properties in the Canadian boreal forest with limited data: Comparison of spatial and non-spatial statistical approaches</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geoderma.2017.06.016</url>
<snippet>Digital soil mapping (DSM) involves the use of georeferenced information and statistical models to map predictions and uncertainties related to soil properties. Many remote regions of the globe, such as boreal forest ecosystems, are characterized by low sampling efforts and limited availability of field soil data. Although DSM is an expanding topic in soil science, little guidance currently exists to select the appropriate combination of statistical methods and model formulation in the context of limited data availability. Using the Canadian managed forest as a case study, the main objective of this study was to investigate to which extent the choice of statistical method and model specification could improve the spatial prediction of soil properties with limited data. More specifically, we compared the cross-product performance of eight statistical approaches (linear, additive and geostatistical models, and four machine-learning techniques) and three model formulations ("covariates only": a suite of environmental covariates only; "spatial only": a function of geographic coordinates only; and "covariates + spatial": a combination of both covariates and spatial functions) to predict five key forest soil properties in the organic layer (thickness and C:N ratio) and in the top 15 cm of the mineral horizon (carbon concentration, percentage of sand, and bulk density). Our results show that 1) although strong differences in predictive performance occurred across all statistical approaches and model formulations, spatially explicit models consistently had higher R-2 and lower RMSE values than non-spatial models for all soil properties, except for the C:N ratio; 2) Bayesian geostatistical models were among the best methods, followed by ordinary kriging and machine-learning methods; and 3) comparative analyses made it possible to identify the more performant models and statistical methods to predict specific soil properties. We make modeling tools and code available (e.g., Bayesian geostastical models) that increase DSM capabilities and support existing efforts toward the production of improved digital soil products with limited data.
WOS:000409291000022
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="11">
<title>Heuristic cellular automaton model for simulating soil organic carbon under land use and climate change: A case study in eastern China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.agee.2018.09.034</url>
<snippet>The concentration of soil organic carbon (SOC) is one of the most important soil properties, and its spatio-temporal variability greatly affects the global climate and agroecology. To investigate the effects of land use and climate change on SOC, a heuristic cellular automaton (HCA) model was proposed and applied to a plains area in eastern China with a high population density and rapid urbanization rate. The HCA model was designed to simulate the geographical variation in SOC dynamics over the long term (2080), and lateral carbon (C) migration is represented by revised neighbourhood variables at the macro scale. Three widely used soil mapping techniques were applied for comparison: multiple linear regression (MLR), support vector machine (SVM) and kriging with external drift (KED). The HCA model enhanced the accuracy of the predicted SOC by 15.27&#37; over MLR, 12.31&#37; over SVM and 10.98&#37; over KED. Future land use maps were produced using legacy land use data and artificial neural network-based cellular automata (CA), and the simulation results showed the rapid urbanization of this area, where the percentage of cropland declined by 23.75&#37; and that of village/urban areas increased by 22.90&#37; from 2010 to 2080. The overall SOC concentrations are anticipated to increase by 2080 given the rising mean annual air temperature and mean annual precipitation. Our results also suggested that land use change clearly influenced the change in soil C, with village/urban areas exhibiting higher SOC than cropland. To provide stakeholders with accurate soil information, it is important to understand the comprehensive impacts of land use and climate change on soil evolution; this study illustrates the value of integrating pedogenetic information in soil C simulation models.
WOS:000457948300017
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="12">
<title>A Novel Evolutionary Genetic Optimization-Based Adaptive Neuro-Fuzzy Inference System and Geographical Information Systems Predict and Map Soil Organic Carbon Stocks Across an Afromontane Landscape</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S1002-0160(17)60461-2</url>
<snippet>Soil organic carbon (SOC) pool has the potential to mitigate or enhance climate change by either acting as a sink, or a source of atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2) and also plays a fundamental role in the health and proper functioning of soils to sustain life on Earth. As such, the objective of this study was to investigate the applicability of a novel evolutionary genetic optimization-based adaptive neuro-fuzzy inference system (ANFIS-EG) in predicting and mapping the spatial patterns of SOC stocks in the Eastern Mau Forest Reserve, Kenya. Field measurements and auxiliary data reflecting the soil-forming factors were used to design an ANFIS-EG model, which was then implemented to predict and map the areal differentiation of SOC stocks in the Eastern Mau Forest Reserve. This was achieved with a reasonable level of uncertainty (i.e., root mean square error of 15.07 Mg C ha(-1)), hence demonstrating the applicability of the ANFIS-EG in SOC mapping studies. There is potential for improving the model performance, as indicated by the current ratio of performance to deviation (1.6). The mapping also revealed marginally higher SOC stocks in the forested ecosystems (i.e., an average of 109.78 Mg C ha(-1)) than in the agro-ecosystems (i.e., an average of 95.9 Mg C ha(-1)).
WOS:000416880300009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="13">
<title>Proximal and remote sensing techniques for mapping of soil contamination with heavy metals</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/05704928.2018.1442346</url>
<snippet>Heavy metal soil contamination is a severe environmental problem globally, and its mapping is vital for environmental managers and policymakers to determine its distributions and hotspots. This paper reviewed multiple proximal and remote sensing spectroscopy for convenient and inexpensive method of obtaining soil reflectance spectroscopy or environmental covariates, which can be used for mapping heavy metal soil contamination. Furthermore, spatial prediction using proximal remote-sensed data and environmental covariates was discussed. We suggested that mapping of the spatial distributions of metal species may be important due to the different bioavailabilities and toxicities of various species. The assimilation of multiple proximal/remote-sensed sensors may promote the horizontal and vertical mapping of soil heavy metals. Moreover, combining the advantages of satellite and unmanned aerial vehicle-based hyperspectral imaging systems will facilitate the development of a space-aeronautic incorporation hyperspectral observation technology that can monitor soil environment rapidly and accurately at a large scale.
WOS:000438280100002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="14">
<title>Assessing the performance of decision tree and neural network models in mapping soil properties</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11629-019-5409-8</url>
<snippet>To build any spatial soil database, a set of environmental data including digital elevation model (DEM) and satellite images beside geomorphic landscape description are essentials. Such a database, integrates field observations and laboratory analyses data with the results obtained from qualitative and quantitative models. So far, various techniques have been developed for soil data processing. The performance of Artificial Neural Network (ANN) and Decision Tree (DT) models was compared to map out some soil attributes in Alborz Province, Iran. Terrain attributes derived from a DEM along with Landsat 8 ETM+, geomorphology map, and the routine laboratory analyses of the studied area were used as input data. The relationships between soil properties (including sand, silt, clay, electrical conductivity, organic carbon, and carbonates) and the environmental variables were assessed using the Pearson Correlation Coefficient and Principle Components Analysis. Slope, elevation, geomforms, carbonate index, stream network, wetness index, and the bands number 2, 3, 4, and 5 were the most significantly correlated variables. ANN and DT did not show the same accuracy in predicting all parameters. The DT model showed higher performances in estimating sand (R-2=0.73), silt (R-2=0.70), clay (R-2=0.72), organic carbon (R-2=0.71), and carbonates (R-2=0.70). While the ANN model only showed higher performance in predicting soil electrical conductivity (R-2=0.95). The results showed that determination the best model to use, is dependent upon the relation between the considered soil properties with the environmental variables. However, the DT model showed more reasonable results than the ANN model in this study. The results showed that before using a certain model to predict variability of all soil parameters, it would be better to evaluate the efficiency of all possible models for choosing the best fitted model for each property. In other words, most of the developed models are site-specific and may not be applicable to use for predicting other soil properties or other area.
WOS:000478892900008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="15">
<title>Geo-Object-Based Soil Organic Matter Mapping Using Machine Learning Algorithms With Multi-Source Geo-Spatial Data</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2019.2902375</url>
<snippet>Soil is a complicated historical natural continuum that presents gradual changes in its properties and geographic area. Conventional soil survey and cartography methods on a macroscopic scale based on grids with a coarse resolution are inadequate for the rapid development of precision agriculture. The demand for soil mapping content and accuracy has increased as more convenient methods of acquiring multi-source geo-spatial data have been developed, and such data are commonly employed to extract basic mapping units and environmental variables in related algorithms. We employ geo-objects as basic units of soil property mapping, which are extracted from high-resolution remote sensing images using a convolutional neural network based learning algorithm. Multi-source geo-spatial data are transferred into each geo-object as environmental variables, and the relationships between soil properties and environmental variables are mined using powerful tree-based machine learning algorithms, including regressions with random forests and XGBoost. A data set that includes soil sample points and multi-source geo-spatial data is used to evaluate the effectiveness of the proposed method. The experimental results demonstrate that the method allows for better soil organic matter mapping than state-of-the-art interpolation-based and linear-regression-based methods. The proposed procedure has potential to be a general method for mapping other soil properties. Its advantages are embodied in the modeling of relatively miscellaneous data with implicitly associated non-linear relationships between soil properties and environmental variables. The spatial scale and accuracy of the finer maps capture more detailed characteristics of the soil properties and are applicable to the micro-domain fields required for refined soil mapping with small variations.
WOS:000464756600004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="16">
<title>Mapping Lorey's height over Hyrcanian forests of Iran using synergy of ICESat/GLAS and optical images</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/22797254.2017.1405717</url>
<snippet>Loreys height, representative of mean height in uneven-aged forest stands, is a valuable parameter for forest ecosystem management. While in situ measures provide the most precise information, remote-sensing techniques may provide less expensive but denser and more operational alternative of Loreys height estimation over highly mountainous areas. This research aims first to evaluate the performances of two nonparametric data mining methods, random forest (RF) and artificial neural network (ANN), for estimation of Loreys height using ice, cloud and land elevation satellite/geoscience laser altimeter system (ICESat/GLAS) in Hyrcanian forests of Iran and then to provide Loreys height map using a synergy of ICESat/GLAS and optical images (TM and SPOT). RF and ANN GLAS height models were developed using waveform deterministic metrics, principal components (PCs) from principal component analysis (PCA) and terrain index (TI) extracted from a digital elevation model (DEM). The best result was obtained using an ANN combining first three PCs of PCA and waveform extent "W-ext" (RMSE = 3.4 m, RMSE&#37; = 12.4). In order to map Loreys height, GLAS-estimated heights were regressed against indices derived from optical images and also topographic information. The best model (RF regression with RMSE = 5.5 m and = 0.59) was applied on the entire study area, and a wall-to-wall height map was generated. This map showed relatively good compatibility with in situ measurements collected in part of the study area.
WOS:000431815800009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="17">
<title>Recent progress and future prospect of digital soil mapping: A review</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S2095-3119(17)61762-3</url>
<snippet>To deal with the global and regional issues including food security, climate change, land degradation, biodiversity loss, water resource management, and ecosystem health, detailed accurate spatial soil information is urgently needed. This drives the worldwide development of digital soil mapping. In recent years, significant progresses have been made in different aspects of digital soil mapping. The main purpose of this paper is to provide a review for the major progresses of digital soil mapping in the last decade. First, we briefly described the rise of digital soil mapping and outlined important milestones and their influence, and main paradigms in digital soil mapping. Then, we reviewed the progresses in legacy soil data, environmental covariates, soil sampling, predictive models and the applications of digital soil mapping products. Finally, we summarized the main trends and future prospect as revealed by studies up to now. We concluded that although the digital soil mapping is now moving towards mature to meet various demands of soil information, challenges including new theories, methodologies and applications of digital soil mapping, especially for highly heterogeneous and human-affected environments, still exist and need to be addressed in the future.
WOS:000418345800020
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="18">
<title>Soil Erosion Spatial Prediction using Digital Soil Mapping and RUSLE methods for Big Sioux River Watershed</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/soilsystems3030043</url>
<snippet>A recent conversion of the grasslands to cropland degrading the soil quality (SQ), and impacting the soil erosion and crop productivity in the West Corn Belt (WCB) of the USA. The current study was conducted to estimate the spatial distribution of soil erosion at Big Sioux River (BSR) watershed scale using the Geographical Information System (GIS)-enabled Revised Universal Soil Loss Equation (RUSLE). Spatial data such as weather, a digital elevation model (DEM), land use maps and soils were used for assessment of soil erosion was downloaded from the easily available online sources. Data showed that about 7&#37; of grassland acreage reduced from 2008 (24&#37;) to 2015 (17&#37;), whereas, about 7.4&#37; of cropland acreage increased from 2008 (64.6&#37;) to 2015 (72&#37;) in the BSR watershed. This grassland conversion to cropland increased the soil erosion (estimated using the RUSLE model) from 12.2 T ha(-1) year(-1) in 2008 to 14.8 T ha(-1) year(-1) in 2015. The present study concludes that grassland conversion to cropland in the BSR watershed increased the soil erosion, therefore, management practices essential to be applied to reduce the erosion risk and various other ecosystem services.
WOS:000492988900013
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="19">
<title>Spatial Mapping of the Groundwater Potential of the Geum River Basin Using Ensemble Models Based on Remote Sensing Images</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/rs11192285</url>
<snippet>This study analyzed the Groundwater Productivity Potential (GPP) of Okcheon city, Korea, using three different models. Two of these three models are data mining models: Boosted Regression Tree (BRT) model and Random Forest (RF) model. The other model is the Logistic Regression (LR) model. The three models are based on the relationship between groundwater-productivity data (specific capacity (SPC) and transmissivity (T)) and the related hydro-geological factors from thematic maps, such as topography, lineament, geology, land cover, and etc. The thematic maps which are generated from the remote sensing images. Groundwater productivity data were collected from 86 wells locations. The resulting GPP maps were validated through area-under-the-curve (AUC) analysis using wells data that had not been used for training the model. When T was used in the BRT, RF, and LR models, the obtained GPP maps had 81.66&#37;, 80.21&#37;, and 85.04&#37; accuracy, respectively, and when SPC was used, the maps had 81.53&#37;, 78.57&#37;, and 82.22&#37; accuracy, respectively. The LR model, which is a statistical model, showed the highest verification accuracy, also the other two models showed high accuracies. These observations indicate that all three models can be useful for groundwater resource development.
WOS:000496827100099
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="20">
<title>Digital mapping of soil organic carbon at multiple depths using different data mining techniques in Baneh region, Iran</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geoderma.2015.12.003</url>
<snippet>This study aimed to map SOC lateral, and vertical variations down to 1 m depth in a semi-arid region in Kurdistan Province, Iran. Six data mining techniques namely; artificial neural networks, support vector regression, k-nearest neighbor, random forests, regression tree models, and genetic programming were combined with equal-area smoothing splines to develop, evaluate and compare their effectiveness in achieving this aim. Using the conditioned Latin hypercube sampling method, 188 soil profiles in the study area were sampled and soil organic carbon content (SOC) measured. Eighteen ancillary data variables derived from a digital elevation model and Landsat 8 images were used to represent predictive soil forming factors in this study area. Findings showed that normalized difference vegetation index and wetness index were the most useful ancillary data for SOC mapping in the upper (0-15 cm) and bottom (60-100 cm) of soil profiles, respectively. According to 5-fold cross validation, artificial neural networks (ANN) showed the highest performance for prediction of SOC in the four standard depths compared to all other data mining techniques. ANNs resulted in the lowest root mean square error and highest Lins concordance coefficient which ranged from 0.07 to 020 log (kg/m(3)) and 0.68 to 0.41, respectively, with the first value in each range being for the top of the profile and second for the bottom. Furthermore, ANNs increased performance of spatial prediction compared to the other data mining algorithms by up to 36, 23, 21 and 13&#37; for each soil depth, respectively, starting from the top of the profile. Overall, results showed that prediction of subsurface SOC variation needs improvement and the challenge remains to find appropriate covariates that can explain it. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000369682100010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="21">
<title>Performance evaluation of the GIS-based data mining techniques of best-first decision tree, random forest, and naive Bayes tree for landslide susceptibility modeling</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2018.06.389</url>
<snippet>The main aim of the present study is to explore and compare three state-of-the art data mining techniques, best-first decision tree, randomforest, and naive Bayes tree, for landslide susceptibility assessment in the Longhai area of China. First, a landslide inventory map with 93 landslide locations was randomly divided, with 70&#37; of the area used for training landslide models and 30&#37; used for the validation process. A spatial database of 14 conditioning factors was constructed under a geographic information system environment. Subsequently, the ReliefF method was employed to assess the prediction capability of the conditioning factors in landslide models. Multicollinearity of these factors was verified using the variance inflation factor, tolerance, and Pearsons correlation coefficient. Finally, the three resulting models were evaluated and compared using the area under the receiver operating characteristic (AUROC) curve, standard error, 95&#37; confidence interval, accuracy, precision, recall, and F-measure. The random forest model showed the AUROC values (0.869), smallest standard error (0.025), narrowest 95&#37; confidence interval (0.819-0.918), highest accuracy value (0.774), highest precision (0.662), and highest F-measure (0.662) for the training dataset. Thus, the random forest model is a promising technique that could be used for landslide susceptibility mapping. 
WOS:000445164000104
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="22">
<title>Estimation of Forest Above-Ground Biomass by Geographically Weighted Regression and Machine Learning with Sentinel Imagery</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/f9100582</url>
<snippet>Accurate forest above-ground biomass (AGB) is crucial for sustaining forest management and mitigating climate change to support REDD+ (reducing emissions from deforestation and forest degradation, plus the sustainable management of forests, and the conservation and enhancement of forest carbon stocks) processes. Recently launched Sentinel imagery offers a new opportunity for forest AGB mapping and monitoring. In this study, texture characteristics and backscatter coefficients of Sentinel-1, in addition to multispectral bands, vegetation indices, and biophysical variables of Sentinal-2, based on 56 measured AGB samples in the center of the Changbai Mountains, China, were used to develop biomass prediction models through geographically weighted regression (GWR) and machine learning (ML) algorithms, such as the artificial neural network (ANN), support vector machine for regression (SVR), and random forest (RF). The results showed that texture characteristics and vegetation biophysical variables were the most important predictors. SVR was the best method for predicting and mapping the patterns of AGB in the study site with limited samples, whose mean error, mean absolute error, root mean square error, and correlation coefficient were 4 x 10(-3), 0.07, 0.08 Mgha(-1), and 1, respectively. Predicted values of AGB from four models ranged from 11.80 to 324.12 Mgha(-1), and those for broadleaved deciduous forests were the most accurate, while those for AGB above 160 Mgha(-1) were the least accurate. The study demonstrated encouraging results in forest AGB mapping of the normal vegetated area using the freely accessible and high-resolution Sentinel imagery, based on ML techniques.
WOS:000448550700001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="23">
<title>A Comparative Assessment of Geostatistical, Machine Learning, and Hybrid Approaches for Mapping Topsoil Organic Carbon Content</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijgi8040174</url>
<snippet>Accurate digital soil mapping (DSM) of soil organic carbon (SOC) is still a challenging subject because of its spatial variability and dependency. This study is aimed at comparing six typical methods in three types of DSM techniques for SOC mapping in an area surrounding Changchun in Northeast China. The methods include ordinary kriging (OK) and geographically weighted regression (GWR) from geostatistics, support vector machines for regression (SVR) and artificial neural networks (ANN) from machine learning, and geographically weighted regression kriging (GWRK) and artificial neural networks kriging (ANNK) from hybrid approaches. The hybrid approaches, in particular, integrated the GWR from geostatistics and ANN from machine learning with the estimation of residuals by ordinary kriging, respectively. Environmental variables, including soil properties, climatic, topographic, and remote sensing data, were used for modeling. The mapping results of SOC content from different models were validated by independent testing data based on values of the mean error, root mean squared error and coefficient of determination. The prediction maps depicted spatial variation and patterns of SOC content of the study area. The results showed the accuracy ranking of the compared methods in decreasing order was ANNK, SVR, ANN, GWRK, OK, and GWR. Two-step hybrid approaches performed better than the corresponding individual models, and non-linear models performed better than the linear models. When considering the uncertainty and efficiency, ML and two-step approach are more suitable than geostatistics in regional landscapes with the high heterogeneity. The study concludes that ANNK is a promising approach for mapping SOC content at a local scale.
WOS:000467499300015
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="24">
<title>Integration of high resolution remotely sensed data and machine learning techniques for spatial prediction of soil properties and corn yield</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compag.2018.07.016</url>
<snippet>Widespread adoption of precision agriculture requires timely acquisition of low-cost, high quality soil and crop yield maps. Integration of remotely sensed data and machine learning algorithms offers cost-and time-effective approach for spatial prediction of soil properties and crop yield compared to conventional approaches. The objectives of this study were to: (i) evaluate the role of remotely sensed images; (ii) compare the performance of various machine learning algorithms; and (iii) identify the importance of remotely sensed image-derived variables, in spatial prediction of soil properties and corn yield. This study integrated field based data on five soil properties (i.e., soil organic matter (SOM), cation exchange capacity (CEC), magnesium (Mg), potassium (K), and pH) and yield monitor based corn yield data with multispectral aerial images and topographic data, both collected in 2013, from seven fields at the Molly Caren Farm near London, Ohio. Digital elevation model data, at a resolution of 1 m, was used to derive topographic properties of the fields. Multispectral images collected at bare-soil conditions, at a resolution 0.30 m, were used to derive soil and vegetation indices. Models developed for prediction of soil properties and corn yield using linear regression (LM) and five machine learning algorithms (i.e., Random Forest (RF); Neural Network (NN); Support Vector Machine (SVM) with radial and linear kernel functions; Gradient Boosting Model (GBM); and Cubist (CU)) were evaluated in terms of coefficient of determination (R-2) and root mean square error (RMSE). Machine learning algorithms were found to outperform LM algorithm for most of the times with a higher R-2 and lower RMSE. Based on models for seven fields, on average, NN provided the highest accuracy for SOM (R-2 = 0.64, RMSE = 0.44) and CEC (R-2 = 0.67, RMSE = 2.35); SVM for K (R-2 = 0.21, RMSE = 0.49) and Mg (R-2 = 0.22, RMSE = 4.57); and GBM for pH (R-2 = 0.15, RMSE = 0.62). For corn yield, RF consistently outperformed other models and provided higher accuracy (R-2 = 0.53, RMSE = 0.97). Soil and vegetation indices based on bare-soil imagery played a more significant role in demonstrating in-field variability of corn yield and soil properties than topographic variables. The accuracy of the models developed for prediction of soil properties and corn yield observed in this study suggested that the approach of integrating remotely sensed data and machine learning algorithms are promising for mapping soil properties and corn yield at a local scale, which can be useful in locating areas of potential concerns and implementing site-specific farming practices.
WOS:000446284900021
</snippet>
</document>

</searchresult>
