<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<searchresult>
<query>Global</query>
<document id="1">
<title>Evaluation and comparison of bivariate and multivariate statistical methods for landslide susceptibility mapping (case study: Zab basin)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-012-0650-2</url>
<snippet>Landslides are among the great destructive factors which cause lots of fatalities and financial losses all over the world every year. Studying of the factors affecting occurrence of landslides in a region and zoning the resulting damages will certainly play a crucial role in mitigating such phenomena. In this research, through geological maps and field studies, we primarily prepared a map for landslide distributions in Zab basin-an area of 520 km(2) in the southwest mountainsides of West Azerbaijan Province. By applying other source of information such as the existing thematic maps, we studied and defined the factors (slope, slope aspect, distance to road, distance to drainage network, distance to fault, land use and land cover, geological factors, horizontal gravity acceleration of earthquakes, and climatic condition of the studied area) that affect occurrence of the landslides. To get better precision and higher speed and facility in our analysis, all descriptive and spatial information were entered into geographic information system (GIS) system and Ilwis software. We also used Satellite images (Landsat ETM+ and SPOT 5), producing land cover and landslide-inventory maps, respectively. After preparation of the influential parameters on landslides, we drew the zoning maps of slide hazard via four different statistical methods and then evaluated and compared them. By analyzing the obtained index and by comparing landslide distribution map and zoning map of landslide susceptibility prepared by each of the methods in GIS environment, we found that bivariate method of information value analysis, bivariate method of density-area, multivariate method with linear regression analysis, and multivariate method of discriminate analysis take priority, respectively. Finally, as this research shows, despite their simplicity, bivariate statistical methods have more acceptable precision than multivariate methods, and consequently, they are more compatible with landslide susceptibility of the region. From the results, lithology, slope, annual rainfall, land cover, slope aspect, distance to waterway, distance to road, horizontal gravity acceleration, and distance to fault are very influential to landslides in the region.
WOS:000324320400024
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="2">
<title>GIS based frequency ratio and index of entropy models to landslide susceptibility mapping (Daguan, China)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-016-5580-y</url>
<snippet>The main goal of this study is to produce landslide susceptibility maps by frequency ratio (FR) and index of entropy (IoE) models based on geographic information system (GIS) for the Daguan county of Yunnan province, China. At first, landslide locations were identified by earlier reports and aerial photographs as well as by carrying out field surveys, and a total of 194 landside locations were constructed from various sources. Then the landslide inventory map was randomly split into a training dataset 70 &#37; (136 landslide locations) for training the FR and IoE models and the remaining 30 &#37; (58 landslides locations) were used for validation purposes. Fifteen landslide conditioning factors were constructed in GIS. The susceptibility maps produced using FR and IoE models were divided into five different susceptibility classes such as very low, low, moderate, high, and very high. Finally, the validation of landslide susceptibility maps was carried out based on training dataset and the validation data using the area under the curve (AUC) method. The success rate curve showed that the area under the curve for FR and IoE models were 0.8191 and 0.8109 accuracy, respectively. Similarly, the validation result showed that the prediction accuracy of the two models was 81.75 &#37; for FR model and 81.44 &#37; for IoE model, respectively. The maps produced by both models exhibits better satisfactory properties. The landslide susceptibility maps may be useful for planning purposes for environmental protection and natural hazard mitigation studies in the near future.
WOS:000376030100057
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="3">
<title>Assessment of susceptibility to earth-flow landslide using logistic regression and multivariate adaptive regression splines: A case of the Bence River basin (western Sicily, Italy)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2014.09.020</url>
<snippet>In this paper, terrain susceptibility to earth-flow occurrence was evaluated by using geographic information systems (GIS) and two statistical methods: Logistic regression (LR) and multivariate adaptive regression splines (MARS). LR has been already demonstrated to provide reliable predictions of earth-flow occurrence, whereas MARS, as far as we know, has never been used to generate earth-flow susceptibility models. The experiment was carried out in a basin of western Sicily (Italy), which extends for 51 km(2) and is severely affected by earth-flows. In total, we mapped 1376 earth-flows, covering an area of 4.59 km(2). To explore the effect of pre-failure topography on earth-flow spatial distribution, we performed a reconstruction of topography before the landslide occurrence. This was achieved by preparing a digital terrain model (DTM) where altitude of areas hosting landslides was interpolated from the adjacent undisturbed land surface by using the algorithm topo-to-raster. This DTM was exploited to extract 15 morphological and hydrological variables that, in addition to outcropping lithology, were employed as explanatory variables of earth-flow spatial distribution. The predictive skill of the earth-flow susceptibility models and the robustness of the procedure were tested by preparing five datasets, each including a different subset of landslides and stable areas. The accuracy of the predictive models was evaluated by drawing receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves and by calculating the area under the ROC curve (AUC). The results demonstrate that the overall accuracy of LR and MARS earth-flow susceptibility models is from excellent to outstanding. However, AUC values of the validation datasets attest to a higher predictive power of MARS-models (AUC between 0.881 and 0.912) with respect to LR-models (AUC between 0.823 and 0.870). The adopted procedure proved to be resistant to overfitting and stable when changes of the learning and validation samples are performed. In conclusion, the highly acceptable predictive skill of the statistical models confirms the reliability of the procedure adopted to reconstruct the pre-failure topographic conditions. Such a method solves the conceptual problem arising when post-failure elevation data are the only source of topographic information available to model landslide susceptibility. Furthermore, with respect to other solutions proposed in the past, which identify as unstable the conditions of landslide surroundings, our approach allows for more accurate measurement of those variables (e.g. curvature, convergence index, topographic position index) that depend on the relative position of a cell with respect to its nearby pixels. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000357145400007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="4">
<title>Landslide hazard assessment: recent trends and techniques</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1186/2193-1801-2-523</url>
<snippet>Landslide hazard assessment is an important step towards landslide hazard and risk management. There are several methods of Landslide Hazard Zonation (LHZ) viz. heuristic, semi quantitative, quantitative, probabilistic and multicriteria decision making process. However, no one method is accepted universally for effective assessment of landslide hazards. In recent years, several attempts have been made to apply different methods of LHZ and to compare results in order to find the best suited model. This paper presents the review of researches on landslide hazard mapping published in recent years. The advanced multivariate techniques are proved to be effective in spatial prediction of landslides with high degree of accuracy. Physical process based models also perform well in LHZ mapping even in the areas with poor database. Multi-criteria decision making approach also play significant role in determining relative importance of landslide causative factors in slope instability process. Remote Sensing and Geographical Information System (GIS) are powerful tools to assess landslide hazards and are being used extensively in landslide researches since last decade. Aerial photographs and high resolution satellite data are useful in detection, mapping and monitoring landslide processes. GIS based LHZ models helps not only to map and monitor landslides but also to predict future slope failures. The advancements in Geo-spatial technologies have opened the doors for detailed and accurate assessment of landslide hazards.
WOS:000209465100095
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="5">
<title>Landslide susceptibility delineation in the Ar-Rayth area, Jizan, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, using analytical hierarchy process, frequency ratio, and logistic regression models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-014-4008-9</url>
<snippet>Mountain areas in the southern western corner of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia (KSA) frequently suffer from various types of landsides induced by rainstorms and anthropogenic activities. To mitigate these problems, landslide susceptibility mapping and classification is important to develop quick and safe mitigation or remediation measures and to help the decision making in future planning by identifying the most vulnerable areas. This paper summarizes the findings of a landslide susceptibility analysis in the Ar-Rayth area, Jizan, KSA, using an analytical hierarchy process (AHP), frequency ratio (FR), and logistic regression (LR) models with the aid of GIS tools and remote sensing data. The landslide inventory map was prepared according to historical data, interpretation of high-resolution satellite images (Geo-Eye 0.5 m resolution and QuickBird 0.6 m resolution), topographic maps (1:10,000), and verified by field investigations. An inventory map with 253 landslides locations was extracted from many sources. The landslide inventory was randomly divided into two datasets: 75 &#37; for training the models and 25 &#37; for validation. An enhanced thematic mapper plus 15 m satellite image acquired in 2006 was used for determining the Normalized Difference Vegetation Index. A contour map (1:10,000 with a 10 m contour interval) was converted to digital elevation model 10 m resolution and subsequently converted to slope, slope aspect, curvature, elevation, and drainage networks. Geological data obtained with the help of satellite images were used to prepare lithological units and lineaments. Roads were digitized from the high-resolution image and a rainfall map was prepared from the rainfall gauges distributed throughout the study area. All these data were used to construct a spatial database using GIS and image processing. Three landslide susceptibility maps were constructed; one on the basis of a heuristic method using an AHP, the other two on the basis of landslide inventories and causative factors, using FR and LR. Furthermore, each causative factors weight was determined according to these three models and landslide susceptibility indices were calculated. For verification, receiver operating characteristic curves were calculated and the areas under the curve (AUC) for success rate are 0.755, 0.828, and 0.749 and for prediction rate are 0.708, 0.781, and 0.727 for the AHP, FR, and LR, respectively. In addition, the percentage of existing training landslides data in high and very high zones of the susceptibility maps is of 73.2, 85.31, and 88.59 &#37; and for the validation landslides data is 73.2, 85.31, and 88.59 &#37; for the AHP, FR, and LR, respectively. The findings indicated that the values of AUC are above 0.7 for both success and prediction rate which indicate these three models are suitable for susceptibility analysis. Also, percent of training and validation landslides data of high and very high zones indicate that LR model is more accurate followed by FR model and AHP model.
WOS:000355142800068
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="6">
<title>A Novel Evolutionary Genetic Optimization-Based Adaptive Neuro-Fuzzy Inference System and Geographical Information Systems Predict and Map Soil Organic Carbon Stocks Across an Afromontane Landscape</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/S1002-0160(17)60461-2</url>
<snippet>Soil organic carbon (SOC) pool has the potential to mitigate or enhance climate change by either acting as a sink, or a source of atmospheric carbon dioxide (CO2) and also plays a fundamental role in the health and proper functioning of soils to sustain life on Earth. As such, the objective of this study was to investigate the applicability of a novel evolutionary genetic optimization-based adaptive neuro-fuzzy inference system (ANFIS-EG) in predicting and mapping the spatial patterns of SOC stocks in the Eastern Mau Forest Reserve, Kenya. Field measurements and auxiliary data reflecting the soil-forming factors were used to design an ANFIS-EG model, which was then implemented to predict and map the areal differentiation of SOC stocks in the Eastern Mau Forest Reserve. This was achieved with a reasonable level of uncertainty (i.e., root mean square error of 15.07 Mg C ha(-1)), hence demonstrating the applicability of the ANFIS-EG in SOC mapping studies. There is potential for improving the model performance, as indicated by the current ratio of performance to deviation (1.6). The mapping also revealed marginally higher SOC stocks in the forested ecosystems (i.e., an average of 109.78 Mg C ha(-1)) than in the agro-ecosystems (i.e., an average of 95.9 Mg C ha(-1)).
WOS:000416880300009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="7">
<title>Coupling of DEM and remote-sensing-based approaches for semi-automated detection of regional geostructural features in Zagros mountain, Iran</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-011-0361-0</url>
<snippet>In recent years, remote-sensing data have increasingly been used for the interpretation of objects and mapping in various applications of engineering geology. Digital elevation model (DEM) is very useful for detection, delineation, and interpretation of geological and structural features. The use of image elements for interpretation is a common method to extract structural features. In this paper, linear features were extracted from the Landsat ETM satellite image and then DEM was used to enhance those objects using digital-image-processing filtering techniques. The extraction procedures of the linear objects are performed in a semi-automated way. Photographic elements and geotechnical elements are used as main keys to extract the information from the satellite image data. This paper emphasizes on the application of DEM and usage of various filtering techniques with different convolution kernel size applied on the DEM. Additionally, this paper discusses about the usefulness of DEM and satellite digital data for extraction of structural features in SW of Zagros mountain, Iran.
WOS:000313069000008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="8">
<title>Landslide susceptibility assessment using object mapping units, decision tree, and support vector machine models in the Three Gorges of China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-013-2863-4</url>
<snippet>Due to the particular geographical location and complex geological conditions, the Three Gorges of China suffer from many landslide hazards that often result in tragic loss of life and economic devastation. To reduce the casualty and damages, an effective and accurate method of assessing landslide susceptibility is necessary. Object-based data mining methods were applied to a case study of landslide susceptibility assessment on the Guojiaba Town of the Three Gorges. The study area was partitioned into object mapping units derived from 30 m resolution Landsat TM images using multi-resolution segmentation algorithm based on the landslide factors of engineering rock group, homogeneity, and reservoir water level. Landslide locations were determined by interpretation of Landsat TM images and extensive field surveys. Eleven primary landslide-related factors were extracted from the topographic and geologic maps, and satellite images. Those factors were selected as independent variables using significance testing and correlation coefficient analysis, including slope, profile curvature, engineering rock group, slope structure, distance from faults, land cover, tasseled cap transformation wetness index, reservoir water level, homogeneity, and first and second principal components of the images. Decision tree and support vector machine (SVM) models with the optimal parameters were trained and then used to map landslide susceptibility, respectively. The analytical results were validated by comparing them with known landslides using the success rate and prediction rate curves and classification accuracy. The object-based SVM model has the highest correct rate of 89.36 &#37; and a kappa coefficient of 0.8286 and outperforms the pixel-based SVM, object-based C5.0, and pixel-based SVM models.
WOS:000335754100010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="9">
<title>Subsidence Hazard Assessment at the Samcheok Coalfield, South Korea: A Case Study Using GIS</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.2113/gseegeosci.19.1.69</url>
<snippet>This paper presents a case study of subsidence hazard assessment using geographic information systems (GIS) in an abandoned coal mine area in South Korea. A spatial database was constructed using mine drift maps, topographic maps, geologic maps, borehole data, and subsidence inventory maps representing the locations of past subsidence occurrences. Eight factor layers (drift depth, drift density, distance from nearest drift, distance from nearest railroad, rock mass rating, groundwater depth, slope, and surface runoff accumulation) were extracted from the spatial database to examine the relationships between the factors and past subsidence occurrences (training data set). A frequency ratio (FR) model was used to establish rating classes for each factor, and an analytic hierarchy process (AHP) model was used to establish weightings for the factors. The two models were integrated to combine multiple factor layers into a subsidence hazard map. When the area under the curve technique was used to verify the subsidence hazard map, by comparing the determined hazard rankings with past subsidence occurrences (validation data set), the FR model and FR-AHP integrated model showed 97 percent and 94 percent accuracies, respectively, in predicting subsidence occurrences. Finally, the subsidence hazard map based on the FR model was overlain with exposure intensity and vulnerability maps to generate a priority setting map, representing the relative risk of mine subsidence to buildings. The priority setting map can be used by planners and developers to identify and prioritize areas requiring more detailed investigations of mine subsidence hazards and risks.
WOS:000327862900004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="10">
<title>GIS-based landslide susceptibility assessment in Seoul, South Korea, applying the radius of influence to frequency ratio analysis</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-015-5149-1</url>
<snippet>The objective of this paper is to map landslide susceptibility using a statistical analysis model and the radius of influence within a geographic information systems environment. The statistical analysis included triggering factors (e.g., topography, land cover, forest, and soil properties) of adjacent areas, in addition to the landslide sites themselves. To estimate the probability of landslide occurrence using the radius of influence, and to produce a landslide susceptibility index (LSI), we performed frequency radio (FR) analysis by applying the radius of influence to the domain of specific training sites. Landslide susceptibility maps were generated for each radius of influence, ranging from 0 to 300 m in 30 m increments. We observed enhanced FR index values corresponding to reduced exaggeration of statistical anomalies within the proper radius of influence. It is referred that by adopting the radius of influence the classes that not only affect the landslide occurrence from the adjacent areas but also make anomaly errors can be taken into account in FR analysis. Moreover, comparing the FR values between adopting the optimum radius of influence or not, we inferred that the greater the gap, the bigger influence of adjacent areas the classes have. In the validation stage, we identified the optimum radius of influence by measuring the area beneath the relative operating characteristics curve. We found that the optimum radius of influence in the study area is 240 m, for which the LSI map is 5.95 &#37; points more accurate than when not considering the radius of influence.
WOS:000371393400032
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="11">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping based on GIS and information value model for the Chencang District of Baoji, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-014-1369-z</url>
<snippet>The main objective of this study was to apply a statistical (information value) model using geographic information system (GIS) to the Chencang District of Baoji, China. Landslide locations within the study area were identified using reports and aerial photographs, and a field survey. A total of 120 landslides were mapped, of which 84 (70 &#37;) were randomly selected for building the landslide susceptibility model. The remaining 36 (30 &#37;) were used for model validation. We considered a total of 10 potential factors that predispose an area to a landslide for the landslide susceptibility mapping. These included slope degree, altitude, slope aspect, plan curvature, geomorphology, distance from faults, lithology, land use, mean annual rainfall, and peak ground acceleration. Following an analysis of these factors, a landslide susceptibility map was produced using the information value model with GIS. The resulting landslide susceptibility index was divided into five classes (very high, high, moderate, low, and very low) using the natural breaks method. The corresponding distribution area percentages were 29.22, 25.14, 15.66, 15.60, and 14.38 &#37;, respectively. Finally, landslide locations were used to validate the results of the landslide susceptibility map using areas under the curve (AUC). The AUC plot showed that the susceptibility map had a success rate of 81.79 &#37; and a prediction accuracy of 82.95 &#37;. Based on the results of the AUC evaluation, the landslide susceptibility map produced using the information value model exhibited good performance.
WOS:000344476700004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="12">
<title>The spatial prediction of landslide susceptibility applying artificial neural network and logistic regression models: A case study of Inje, Korea</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1515/geo-2016-0010</url>
<snippet>The aim of this study is to predict landslide susceptibility caused using the spatial analysis by the application of a statistical methodology based on the GIS. Logistic regression models along with artificial neutral network were applied and validated to analyze landslide susceptibility in Inje, Korea. Landslide occurrence area in the study were identified based on interpretations of optical remote sensing data (Aerial photographs) followed by field surveys. A spatial database considering forest, geophysical, soil and topographic data, was built on the study area using the Geographical Information System (GIS). These factors were analysed using artificial neural network (ANN) and logistic regression models to generate a landslide susceptibility map. The study validates the landslide susceptibility map by comparing them with landslide occurrence areas. The locations of landslide occurrence were divided randomly into a training set (50&#37;) and a test set (50&#37;). A training set analyse the landslide susceptibility map using the artificial network along with logistic regression models, and a test set was retained to validate the prediction map. The validation results revealed that the artificial neural network model (with an accuracy of 80.10&#37;) was better at predicting landslides than the logistic regression model (with an accuracy of 77.05&#37;). Of the weights used in the artificial neural network model, slope yielded the highest weight value (1.330), and aspect yielded the lowest value (1.000). This research applied two statistical analysis methods in a GIS and compared their results. Based on the findings, we were able to derive a more effective method for analyzing landslide susceptibility.
WOS:000371283300012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="13">
<title>Application of frequency ratio, statistical index, and index of entropy models and their comparison in landslide susceptibility mapping for the Baozhong Region of Baoji, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-014-1554-0</url>
<snippet>The main goal of this study was to produce landslide susceptibility mapping by frequency ratio (FR), statistical index (SI), and index of entropy (IOE) models based on geographic information system (GIS) for the Baozhong region of Baoji, China. At first, a landslide inventory map was prepared using earlier reports and aerial photographs as well as by carrying out a field survey. A total of 79 landslides were mapped and out of which, 55 (70 &#37;) were randomly selected for building landslide susceptibility models, while the remaining 24 (30 &#37;) were used for validating the models. In this case study, the following landslide conditioning factors were evaluated: slope degree, slope aspect, plan curvature, altitude, geomorphology, lithology, distance from faults, distance from rivers, and precipitation. Subsequently, landslide susceptibility maps were produced using FR, SI, and IOE models. Finally, the validation of landslide susceptibility map was carried out using areas under the curve (AUC). The AUC plot estimation results showed that the susceptibility map using FR model has the highest prediction accuracy of 82.49 &#37;, followed by the SI model (81.43 &#37;) and the IOE model (79.62 &#37;). Similarly, the AUC plot showed that the success rate of the three models was 84.95 &#37; for FR model, 82.37 &#37; for SI model, and 82.05 &#37; for IOE model, respectively. According to the validation results of the AUC evaluation, the map produced by the FR model exhibits the most satisfactory properties. These landslide susceptibility maps can be used for preliminary land use planning and hazard mitigation purpose.
WOS:000352640900001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="14">
<title>A comparative study on the landslide susceptibility mapping using logistic regression and statistical index models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-017-2961-9</url>
<snippet>The logistic regression and statistical index models are applied and verified for landslide susceptibility mapping in Daguan County, Yunnan Province, China, by means of the geographic information system (GIS). A detailed landslide inventory map was prepared by literatures, aerial photographs, and supported by field works. Fifteen landslide-conditioning factors were considered: slope angle, slope aspect, curvature, plan curvature, profile curvature, altitude, STI, SPI, and TWI were derived from digital elevation model; NDVI was extracted from Landsat ETM7; rainfall was obtained from local rainfall data; distance to faults, distance to roads, and distance to rivers were created from a 1: 25,000 scale topographic map; the lithology was extracted from geological map. Using these factors, the landslide susceptibility maps were prepared by LR and SI models. The accuracy of the results was verified by using existing landslide locations. The statistical index model had a predictive rate of 81.02&#37;, which is more accurate prediction in comparison with logistic regression model (80.29&#37;). The models can be used to land-use planning in the study area.
WOS:000400266200003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="15">
<title>Landslide Susceptibility Zonation Mapping Using Logistic Regression and its Validation in Hashtchin Region, Northwest of Iran</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12594-014-0111-5</url>
<snippet>Landslide susceptibility zonation mapping assists researchers greatly to understand the spatial distribution of slope failure probability in a region. Being extremely useful in reducing landslide hazards, such maps could simply be produced using both qualitative and quantitative methods. In the present study, a multivariate statistical method called logistic regression was used to assess landslide susceptibility in Hashtchin region, situated in west of Alborz Mountains-northwest of Iran. In this study, two independent variables, categorical (predictor) and continuous, were drawn on together in the model. To identify the regions landslides use was made of aerial photographs, field studies and topographic maps. To prepare the database of factors affecting the regions landslides and to determine landslide zones, geographic information system (GIS) was used. Using such information, landslide susceptibility modeling was accomplished. The data related to factors causing landslides were extracted as independent variables in each cell (in 50 mx50 m cells). Then, the whole data were input into the SPSS, Version 18. The prepared database was later analyzed using logistic regression, the forward stepwise method and based on maximum likelihood estimation. Regression equation was determined using obtained constants and coefficients and the landslide susceptibility of the area in grid-cells (pixels) was computed between 0 and 0.9954. The Receiver Operating Characteristic (ROC) curve was used to assess the accuracy of the logistic regression model. The predicting ability of the model was 84.1&#37; given the area under ROC curve. Finally, the degree of success of landslide susceptibility zonation mapping was estimated to be 79&#37;.
WOS:000339319800006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="16">
<title>Different landslide sampling strategies in a grid-based bi-variate statistical susceptibility model</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2015.10.030</url>
<snippet>This study had three aims. The first was to assess the performance of the weights-of-evidence (WofE) landslide susceptibility model in areas that are very different in terms of size, geoenvironmental settings, and landslide types. The second was to test the appropriate strategies to sample the mapped landslide polygon. The final aim was to evaluate the performance of the method to changes in the landslide sample size used to train the model. The method was applied to two areas: the Fella River basin (eastern Italian Alps) containing debris flows, and Buzau County (Romanian Carpathians) with shallow landslides. The three landslide sampling strategies used were: (1) the landslide scarp centroid, (2) points populating the scarp on a 50-m grid, and (3) the entire scarp polygon. The highest success rates were obtained when sampling shallow landslides as 50-m grid-points and debris flow scarps as polygons. Prediction rates were highest when using the entire scarp polygon method for both landslide types. The sample size test using the landslide centroids showed that a sample of 104 debris flow scarps was sufficient to predict the remaining 941 debris flows in the Fella River basin, while 161 shallow landslides was the minimum required number to predict the remaining 1451 scarps in Buzau County. Below these landslide sample thresholds, model performance was too low. However, using more landslides than the threshold produced a plateau effect with little to no increase in the model performance rates. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000367114100041
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="17">
<title>Modeling urban evolution using neural networks, fuzzy logic and GIS: The case of the Athens metropolitan area</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cities.2012.03.006</url>
<snippet>This paper presents an artificial intelligence approach integrated with geographical information systems (GISs) for modeling urban evolution. Fuzzy logic and neural networks are used to provide a synthetic spatiotemporal methodology for the analysis, prediction and interpretation of urban growth. The proposed urban model takes into account the changes over time in population and building use patterns. A GIS is used for handling the spatial and temporal data, performing contingency analysis and mapping the results. Spatial entities with similar characteristics are grouped together in clusters by the use of a fuzzy c-means algorithm. Each cluster represents a specific level of urban growth and development. A two-layer feed-forward multilayer perceptron artificial neural network is then used to predict urban growth. The model, applied to the prefecture of Attica, Greece, delineates the current and future evolution trends of the Athens metropolitan area, which are illustrated by maps of the urban growth dynamics. The proposed methodology aims to assist planners and decision makers in gaining insight into the transition from rural to urban. (C) 2012 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000313232300020
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="18">
<title>Macrobenthos habitat potential mapping using GIS-based artificial neural network models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.marpolbul.2012.10.023</url>
<snippet>This paper proposes and tests a method of producing macrobenthos habitat potential maps in Hwangdo tidal flat, Korea based on an artificial neural network. Samples of macrobenthos were collected during field work, and eight control factors were compiled as a spatial database from remotely sensed data and GIS analysis. The macrobenthos habitat potential maps were produced using an artificial neural network model. Macrobenthos habitat potential maps were made for Macrophthalmus dilatatus, Cerithideopsilla cingulata, and Armandia lanceolata. The maps were validated by compared with the surveyed habitat locations. A strong correlation between the potential maps and species locations was revealed. The validation result showed average accuracies of 74.9&#37;, 78.32&#37;, and 73.27&#37; for M. dilatatus, C. cingulata, and A. lanceolata, respectively. A GIS-based artificial neural network model combined with remote sensing techniques is an effective tool for mapping the areas of macrobenthos habitat potential in tidal flats. 
WOS:000316526300034
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="19">
<title>GIS-based Landslide Susceptibility analyses and Cross-Validation using a Probabilistic Model on Two Test Areas in Korea</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>Landslides are major natural geological hazards that are responsible each year for a high amount of property damage involving both direct and indirect costs. Over the last few decades, many researchers have produced landslide susceptibility maps using various techniques. This paper presents the results of the cross-validation of a probability model using remote sensing and geographic information system for landslide susceptibility on the Wumyon and Inje areas in South Korea. Landslide locations were identified from aerial photographs. The 13 landslide-related factors, slope, aspect, curvature, soil thickness, soil drainage, soil texture, soil material, soil topography, timber type, timber age, timber density, timber diameter, land cover, were calculated and extracted from the spatial database. Using 13 factors, landslide susceptibility was analyzed by probability model. For validation and cross-validation, analytical results were compared in each study area with actual landslide locations. Wumyon based on its frequency ratio presented the base prediction accuracy (76.38&#37;) whereas Wumyon based on the Inje frequency ratio presented the worst (70.11&#37;). Qualitatively, the cross application model yields reasonable results which can be used for preliminary landslide hazard mapping.
WOS:000324777400007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="20">
<title>Earthquake induced landslide susceptibility mapping using an integrated ensemble frequency ratio and logistic regression models in West Sumatera Province, Indonesia</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.catena.2014.02.005</url>
<snippet>An 8 Richter Scale (RS) earthquake struck West Sumatra on Wednesday, 30 September 2009, at 17.16 pm which led to huge number of landslides. Hence a comprehensive landslide susceptibility mapping (LSM) should be produced in order to reduce the damages to people and infrastructures. In the international landslide literature, various statistical methods such as frequency ratio (FR) and logistic regression (LR) have been widely used individually for LSM, but they have some weaknesses. FR which is able to perform bivariate statistical analysis (BSA) assesses the influence of classes of each conditioning factor on landslide occurrence. However, the correlation between the factors is mostly neglected. On the other hand, LR is able to analyze the relationship among the factors while it is not capable to evaluate the classes of each landslide conditioning factor. This paper aims to propose an ensemble method of FR and LR in order to overcome their weak points. For LSM, a landslide inventory map with a total of 87 landslide locations was extracted from various sources. Then the landslide inventory was randomly divided into two datasets 70&#37; for training the models and the remaining 30&#37; was used for validation purpose. The landslide conditioning factors consist of: altitude, curvature, river, SPI, rainfall, soil type, soil texture, land use/cover (LULC), peak ground acceleration (PGA), geology, slope, aspect, lineament and topographic wetness index (TWI). Four PGA of 7.5, 8, 8.6 and 9 were acquired and PGA 8 which was related to the 2009 earthquake was used to generate the model. Finally, the produced landslide susceptibility maps were validated using an area under the (ROC) curve method. For the model which was derived by PGA 8, the validation results showed 84&#37; and 78&#37; success and prediction rates respectively. Furthermore, the prediction rates for the models made by PGA 7.2, 8.6 and 9 are 79&#37;, 78&#37; and 81&#37; respectively. The result proved the reasonable efficiency of the proposed method for earthquake induced landslide susceptibility mapping. Also the proposed ensemble method can be used in other hazard studies as it is capable to produce rapid and accurate assessment for disaster management and decision making. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000347598000012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="21">
<title>A hybrid fuzzy weight of evidence method in landslide susceptibility analysis on the Wuyuan area, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2017.04.002</url>
<snippet>The present study proposed a hybrid fuzzy weight of evidence model for constructing a landslide susceptibility map in the Wuyuan area, China, where disastrous landslide events have occurred. The model combines the knowledge of experts obtained through a fuzzy logic approach and a hybrid weight of evidence method. The estimated knowledge-based fuzzy membership value of each environmental variable is combined with data based conditional probabilities to derive fuzzy posterior probabilities and landslide susceptibility. The developed model was compared with a landslide susceptibility map produced using the data-driven weight of evidence method, based on 510 landslide and non-landslide sites. The sites were identified by analyzing airborne imagery, field investigation and previous studies. Landside susceptibility for these sites was analyzed using 10 geoenvironmental variables: slope, aspect, lithology, soil, rainfall, plan curvature, the normalized difference vegetation index, distance to roads, distance to rivers and distance to faults. The resultant hybrid fuzzy weight of evidence method showed high predictive power, with the area under the success and predictive curves being 0.770 and 0.746, respectively. Additional analyses showed that the developed model could work effectively even with limited data.
WOS:000405056100001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="22">
<title>Biomass estimation of Sonneratia caseolaris (l.) Engler at a coastal area of Hai Phong city (Vietnam) using ALOS-2 PALSAR imagery and GIS-based multi-layer perceptron neural networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/15481603.2016.1269869</url>
<snippet>This study tested the use of machine learning techniques for the estimation of above-ground biomass (AGB) of Sonneratia caseolaris in a coastal area of Hai Phong city, Vietnam. We employed a GIS database and multi-layer perceptron neural networks (MLPNN) to build and verify an AGB model, drawing upon data from a survey of 1508 mangrove trees in 18 sampling plots and ALOS-2 PALSAR imagery. We assessed the models performance using root-mean-square error, mean absolute error, coefficient of determination (R-2), and leave-one-out cross-validation. We also compared the models usability with four machine learning techniques: support vector regression, radial basis function neural networks, Gaussian process, and random forest. The MLPNN model performed well and outperformed the machine learning techniques. The MLPNN model-estimated AGB ranged between 2.78 and 298.95Mgha(-1) (average=55.8Mgha(-1)); below-ground biomass ranged between 4.06 and 436.47Mgha(-1) (average=81.47Mgha(-1)), and total carbon stock ranged between 3.22 and 345.65Mg C ha(-1) (average=64.52Mg C ha(-1)). We conclude that ALOS-2 PALSAR data can be accurately used with MLPNN models for estimating mangrove forest biomass in tropical areas.
WOS:000399475800004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="23">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping by geographical information system-based multivariate statistical and deterministic models: in an artificial reservoir area at Northern Turkey</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-015-2142-7</url>
<snippet>In Turkey, landslide phenomenon is one of the most important natural hazards. Due to landslide occurrence, several landforms and man-made structures are adversely affected and may cause many injuries and loss of life. In this context, landslide susceptibility assessment is an important task to determine susceptible areas to landslide occurrence. Especially, several dam reservoir areas in Turkey are threatened by landslide phenomena. For this reason, in this study, a dam reservoir area, located in the northern part of Turkey, was selected and investigated in the point of view of landslide susceptibility assessment. A landslide susceptibility assessment for Kurtun Dam reservoir area (Gumushane, North Turkey) was carried out by geographical information system (GIS)-based statistical and deterministic models. For this purpose, logistic regression (LR) and stability index mapping (SINMAP) methodologies were applied. In this context, eight contributing factors such as altitude, lithology, slope gradient, slope aspect, distance to drainage, distance to lineament, stream power index (SPI) and topographical wetness index (TWI) were considered. After assessment of these parameters by LR and SINMAP methods in a GIS environment, two landslide susceptibility maps were obtained. Then, the produced maps were analyzed for validation purpose. For this purpose, area under curvature (AUC) approach was used. At the end of this process, the AUC values of 0.73 and 0.65 were found for LR and SINMAP models, respectively. For the performance of the SINMAP model, statistical results produced by the model were also considered. In this context, landslide density of the stability index (SI) classes were taken into account, and it was determined that 89.5 &#37; of the landslides fall into lower and upper threshold classes which almost correspond to moderate and high susceptibility classes. These two validation values indicate that the accuracy of landslide susceptibility maps is acceptable, and the maps are feasible for further natural hazard management affairs in the area.
WOS:000371380500083
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="24">
<title>Flood susceptibility mapping using integrated bivariate and multivariate statistical models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-014-3289-3</url>
<snippet>Flooding can have catastrophic effects on human lives and livelihoods and thus comprehensive flood management is needed. Such management requires information on the hydrologic, geotechnical, environmental, social, and economic aspects of flooding. The number of flood events that took place in Busan, South Korea, in 2009 exceeded the normal situation for that city. Mapping the susceptible areas helps us to understand flood trends and can aid in appropriate planning and flood prevention. In this study, a combination of bivariate probability analysis and multivariate logistic regression was used to produce flood susceptibility maps of Busan City. The main aim of this research was to overcome the weakness of logistic regression regarding bivariate probability capabilities. Aflood inventory map with a total of 160 flood locations was extracted from various sources. Then, the flood inventory was randomly split into a testing dataset 70 &#37; for training the models and the remaining 30 &#37;, which was used for validation. Independent variables datasets included the rainfall, digital elevation model, slope, curvature, geology, green farmland, rivers, slope, soil drainage, soil effect, soil texture, stream power index, timber age, timber density, timber diameter, and timber type. The impact of each independent variable on flooding was evaluated by analyzing each independent variable with the dependent flood layer. The validation dataset, which was not used for model generation, was used to evaluate the flood susceptibility map using the prediction rate method. The results of the accuracy assessment showed a success rate of 92.7 &#37; and a prediction rate of 82.3 &#37;.
WOS:000344477800021
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="25">
<title>Including root reinforcement variability in a probabilistic 3D stability model</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/esp.4127</url>
<snippet>Forests play a significant role in protecting people, settlements in mountainous terrains from hydrogeomorphic hazards, including shallow landslides. Although several studies have investigated the interactions between forests and slope instabilities, a full understanding of them has not yet been obtained. Additionally, models that incorporate forest stand properties into slope failure probability analyses have not been developed. In principle, physical-based models, which are powerful tools for landslide hazard analyses, represent an appropriate approach to linking stand properties and slope stability. However, the reliability of these models depends on numerous parameters that describe highly complex geotechnical and hydrological processes (e.g. potential failure depth, saturation ratio, root reinforcement, etc.) that are difficult to measure and model. In particular, the spatial heterogeneity of root reinforcement remains a problem, and the use of physically based models from a forest management perspective has been limited. This paper presents a procedure for assessing slope stability in terms of the Factor of Safety that accounts for forest stand characteristics such as tree density, average diameter at breast height and minimum distance between trees. The procedure combines a three-dimensional (3D) slope stability model with an evaluation of the variability of root reinforcement in terms of a probability distribution, according to forest characteristics. Monte Carlo simulation is used to account for the residual uncertainties in both stand characteristics and 3D stability model parameters. The proposed method was applied in a subalpine catchment in the Italian Alps, mainly covered by coniferous forest and characterized by steep slopes and high landslide risk. The results suggest that the procedure is highly reliable, according to landslide inventory maps [area under the ROC curve (AUC) is 0.82 and modified success rate (MSR) is 0.70]. Thus, it represents a promising tool for studying the role of root reinforcement in landslide hazard mapping and guiding forest management from a slope stability perspective. Copyright 
WOS:000411021500003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="26">
<title>Combined use of statistical and DInSAR data analyses to define the state of activity of slow-moving landslides</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10346-016-0722-6</url>
<snippet>Statistical analyses have been often used for landslide susceptibility zoning at small to medium scale when relevant base and thematic maps are available. Since the beginning of the last decade, images remotely acquired by spaceborne Synthetic Aperture Radar (SAR) and processed via Differential SAR Interferometry (DInSAR) proved extremely useful for non-invasive and non-destructive monitoring of displacements of the topographic surface. The present paper proposes an original procedure for the definition of the state of activity of slow-moving landslides via the combined use of multivariate statistical analyses and DInSAR data. The procedure is based on the following essential elements: distinction between terrain units used for computational purposes and the final zoning units; independent statistical and DInSAR analyses and activity models leading to first-level state of activity zoning maps; a consistency model between statistical and DInSAR analyses; two confidence and combination models leading, respectively, to second- or third-level state of activity zoning maps. The application in a test area including 19 municipalities in southern Italy, where slow-moving landslides are widespread and accurately mapped by using geomorphological criteria, allowed the generation of the three above-mentioned levels of zoning maps. The results were successfully crosschecked by exploiting a different DInSAR dataset and the results of previous works based on the use of slow-moving landslide-induced damage to facilities surveys.
WOS:000398889900003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="27">
<title>Assessment of the effects of training data selection on the landslide susceptibility mapping: a comparison between support vector machine (SVM), logistic regression (LR) and artificial neural networks (ANN)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/19475705.2017.1407368</url>
<snippet>Landslide is a natural hazard that results in many economic damages and human losses every year. Numerous researchers have studied landslide susceptibility mapping (LSM), each attempting to improve the accuracy of the final outputs. However, few studies have been published on the training data selection effects on the LSM. Thus, this study assesses the training landslides random selection effects on support vector machine (SVM) accuracy, logistic regression (LR) and artificial neural networks (ANN) models for LSM in a catchment at the Dodangeh watershed, Mazandaran province, Iran. A 160 landslide locations inventory was collected by Geological Survey of Iran for this investigation. Different methods were implemented to define the landslide locations, such as inventory reports, satellite images and field survey. Moreover, 14 landslide conditioning factors were considered in the analysis of landslide susceptibility. These factors include curvature, plan curvature, profile curvature, altitude, slope angle, slope aspect, distance to faults, distance to stream, topographic wetness index, stream power index, terrain roughness index, sediment transport index, lithology and land use. The results show that the random landslide training data selection affected the parameter estimations of the SVM, LR and ANN algorithms. The results also show that the training samples selection had an effect on the accuracy of the susceptibility model because landslide conditioning factors vary according to the geographic locations in the study area. The LR model was found to be less sensitive than the SVM and ANN models to the training samples selection. Validation results showed that SVM and LR models outperformed the ANN model for all scenarios. The average overall accuracy of LR, SVM and ANN models are 81.42&#37;, 79.82&#37; and 70.2&#37;, respectively.
WOS:000428252700004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="28">
<title>APPLICATION OF ARTIFICIAL NEURAL NETWORK SYSTEM BASED ON ANFIS USING GIS FOR PREDICTING FOREST ROAD NETWORK SUITABILITY MAPPING</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>There are different factors which affect the well-planning of forest road networks and originated from both general and regional characteristics. It is necessary to support the decision maker effectively by considering the selected criteria during the process of planning the forest roads in the forest areas which are located in the mountainous regions. So, first of all these factors need to be ranked according to the significance. This study is intended to reveal the forest road network plan alternatives which have a high predictive power in planning by considering the criteria that affect the planning when the forest road planning is made. To this end, the forest management chief, which is the smallest forest management unit within Turkey, has been selected as the sample area. Nine criteria affecting the forest road network planning of this units were evaluated via Geographic Information Systems (GIS) and Adaptive Network Fuzzy Inference System (ANFIS) and six different forest road network models were established. The AUC values of the generated models are between the range of 0,654 and 0,845. The most appropriate ANFIS model was determined as model 4 which comprises elevation, slope, distance village and NDVI criteria. The multi-directional approach was used to reflect the effect of factors on forest network planning via GIS, artificial neural networks and fuzzy logic. Furthermore, the factors employed in the developed models can be diversified at the regional level and utilized by the implementers or decision makers in forest road network planning.
WOS:000429081700039
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="29">
<title>Prioritization of landslide conditioning factors and its spatial modeling in Shangnan County, China using GIS-based data mining algorithms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10064-017-1004-9</url>
<snippet>The main objective of the current study is to apply a random forest (RF) data-driven model and prioritization of landslide conditioning factors according to this method and its comparison to a multivariate adaptive regression spline (MARS) model for landslide susceptibility mapping in China. For this purpose, at first, landslide locations were identified by earlier reports, aerial photographs, and field surveys and a total of 348 landslides were mapped from various sources in GIS. Then, the landslide inventory was randomly split into a training dataset (70&#37; = 244 landslides) and the remaining (30&#37; = 104 landslides) were used for validation. In this study, 12 landslide conditioning factors were applied to detect the most susceptible areas. These factors were slope aspect, altitude, distance to faults, lithology, normalized difference vegetation index, plan curvature, profile curvature, distance to rivers, distance to roads, slope angle, stream power index, and topographic wetness index. The relationship between each conditioning factor and landslide was finalized using a frequency ration (FR) model. Subsequently, landslide-susceptible areas were mapped using the MARS and RF models. The results revealed that the most important conditioning factors according to the accuracy measure (mean decrease) of the RF model are lithology (23.47&#37;), distance to faults (22.21&#37;), and altitude (19.58&#37;). We also notice that altitude (19.04&#37;), distance to faults (18.83&#37;), and distance to roads (15.29&#37;) have the highest importance according to the Gini measure. Finally, the accuracy of the landslide susceptibility maps produced from the two models was verified using a receiver operating characteristics curve. The results showed that the landslide susceptibility map produced using the MARS model has a higher prediction rate than RF by area under the curve values of 87.51 and 77.32&#37;, respectively. According to the validation results, the map produced by the MARS model exhibits the better accuracy and could be proposed for land-use planning in the study area.
WOS:000431300600012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="30">
<title>A comparative study for landslide susceptibility mapping using GIS-based multi-criteria decision analysis (MCDA), logistic regression (LR) and association rule mining (ARM)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.enggeo.2015.09.007</url>
<snippet>Landslide susceptibility mapping is one of the crucial stages of landslide hazard and risk assessment. Moreover, the susceptibility maps assist planners, local administrations, and decision makers in disaster planning. Various approaches have been applied in the literature to increase the accuracy of landslide susceptibility maps. The determination of suitable susceptibility mapping method plays critical role for obtaining required accuracy. In this study, the performances of three quantitative susceptibility mapping methods are evaluated. The logistic regression (LR) analysis is the typical example of statistical methods, while GIS-based multi-criteria decision analyses (MCDA) and association rule mining (ARM) are the examples of heuristic and data mining methods, respectively. The susceptibility maps based on the three methods are obtained for Savsat in Artvin province (NE Turkey) where the region has intense landslides. The landslide influencing parameters for the study area are lithology, land use/land cover, soil type, erosion, altitude, slope, aspect, distance to drainage, soil depth, distance to fault, distance to road. The models for the three methods are then compared and evaluated by using pixel-based evaluation metrics. Results showed that ARM provides a higher quality percent (QP), whereas percent of damage detection (PDD) is higher for LR method. The lowest QP is obtained by GIS-based MCDA. It is found that LR and ARM methods are better than GIS-based MCDA in modeling the landslide susceptibility and they can be integrated to obtain better performance. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000372688600005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="31">
<title>A novel hybrid integration model using support vector machines and random subspace for weather-triggered landslide susceptibility assessment in the Wuning area (China)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-017-6981-2</url>
<snippet>This study proposed a hybrid modeling approach using two methods, support vector machines and random subspace, to create a novel model named random subspacebased support vector machines (RSSVM) for assessing landslide susceptibility. The newly developed model was then tested in the Wuning area, China, to produce a landslide susceptibility map. With the purpose of achieving the objective of the study, a spatial dataset was initially constructed that includes a landslide inventory map consisting of 445 landslide regions. Then, various landslide-influencing factors were defined, including slope angle, aspect, altitude, topographic wetness index, stream power index, sediment transport index, soil, lithology, normalized difference vegetation index, land use, rainfall, distance to roads, distance to rivers, and distance to faults. Next, the result of the RSSVM model was validated using statistical index-based evaluations and the receiver operating characteristic curve approach. Then, to evaluate the performance of the suggested RSSVM model, a comparison analysis was performed to other existing approaches such as artificial neural network, Naive Bayes (NB) and support vector machine (SVM). In general, the performance of the RSSVM model was better than the other models for spatial prediction of landslide susceptibility. The AUC results of the applied models are as follows: RSSVM (AUC = 0.857), followed by MLP (AUC = 0.823), SVM (AUC = 0.814) and NB (AUC = 0.783). The present study indicates that RSSVM can be used for landslide susceptibility evaluation, and the results are very useful for local governments and people living in the Wuning area.
WOS:000412736700008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="32">
<title>A comparative assessment of prediction capabilities of Dempster-Shafer and Weights-of-evidence models in landslide susceptibility mapping using GIS</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/19475705.2012.662915</url>
<snippet>In a country with diverse geologic, topographic and climatic conditions such as Iran, landslides are frequent phenomena. The aim of this study is to perform a landslide susceptibility assessment at Haraz watershed, Iran using two different approaches such as Dempster-Shafer and Weights-of-evidence models in GIS. First, a landslide inventory map was prepared using the landslide occurrence data by interpreting aerial photographs and field surveys. Second, thematic maps including lithology, altitude, and land-use are prepared in GIS. A total 11 landslide conditioning factors are considered such as slope angle, aspect, altitude, distance from drainage, distance from road, distance from river, lithology, land use, topographic wetness index, stream power index and slope-length (LS). The relationship between the conditional factors and the landslides were calculated using both Dempster-Shafer and Weights-of-evidence models. Using the predicted values, landslide susceptibility maps of the study area is produced. For verification, the results of the analyses were then compared with the field-verified landslide locations. Additionally, the receiver operating characteristics (ROC) curves for all landslide susceptibility models were drawn and the area under curve values was calculated. The AUC value of the produced landslide susceptibility maps has been obtained as 72.87&#37; and 79.87&#37; for Dempster-Shafer and Weights-of-evidence models, respectively. The resulting susceptibility maps would be useful for landuse planning and prioritization of efforts for the reduction and mitigation of future landslide hazards in Haraz watershed.
WOS:000319559600001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="33">
<title>A NEW FRAMEWORK FOR GEOSPATIAL SITE SELECTION USING ARTIFICIAL NEURAL NETWORKS AS DECISION RULES: A CASE STUDY ON LANDFILL SITES</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.5194/isprsannals-II-2-W2-131-2015</url>
<snippet>This paper briefly introduced the theory and framework of geospatial site selection (GSS) and discussed the application and framework of artificial neural networks (ANNs). The related literature on the use of ANNs as decision rules in GSS is scarce from 2000 till 2015. As this study found, ANNs are not only adaptable to dynamic changes but also capable of improving the objectivity of acquisition in GSS, reducing time consumption, and providing high validation. ANNs make for a powerful tool for solving geospatial decision-making problems by enabling geospatial decision makers to implement their constraints and imprecise concepts. This tool offers a way to represent and handle uncertainty. Specifically, ANNs are decision rules implemented to enhance conventional GSS frameworks. The main assumption in implementing ANNs in GSS is that the current characteristics of existing sites are indicative of the degree of suitability of new locations with similar characteristics. GSS requires several input criteria that embody specific requirements and the desired site characteristics, which could contribute to geospatial sites. In this study, the proposed framework consists of four stages for implementing ANNs in GSS. A multilayer feed-forward network with a backpropagation algorithm was used to train the networks from prior sites to assess, generalize, and evaluate the outputs on the basis of the inputs for the new sites. Two metrics, namely, confusion matrix and receiver operating characteristic tests, were utilized to achieve high accuracy and validation. Results proved that ANNs provide reasonable and efficient results as an accurate and inexpensive quantitative technique for GSS.
WOS:000380584800019
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="34">
<title>GIS-based landslide susceptibility mapping with logistic regression, analytical hierarchy process, and combined fuzzy and support vector machine methods: a case study from Wolong Giant Panda Natural Reserve, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10064-015-0786-x</url>
<snippet>Landslides, as one of the most destructive natural phenomena, distribute extensively in Wolong Giant Panda Natural Reserve and cause damage to both humans and endangered species. Therefore, landslide susceptibility zonation (LSZ) mapping is necessary for government agencies and decision makers to select suitable locations for giant pandas. The main purpose of this study is to produce landside susceptibility maps using logistic regression (LR), analytical hierarchy process (AHP), and a combined fuzzy and support vector machine (F-SVM) hybrid method based on geographic information systems (GIS). A total of 1773 landslide scarps larger than one cell (25 9 25 m(2)) were selected in the landslide inventory mapping, 70 &#37; of which were selected at random to be used as test data, and the other 30 &#37; were used as validation. Topographical, geological, and hydrographical data were collected, processed, and constructed into a spatial database. Nine conditioning factors were chosen as influencing factors related to landslide occurrence: slope degree, aspect, altitude, profile curvature, geology and lithology, distance from faults, distance from rivers, distance from roads, and normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI). Landslide susceptible areas were analyzed and mapped using the landslide occurrence factors by different methods. For conventional assessment, weights and rates of the affecting factors were assigned based on experience and knowledge of experts. In order to reduce the subjectivity, a combined fuzzy and SVM hybrid model was generated for LSZ in this paper. In this approach, the rates of each thematic layer were generated by the fuzzy similarity method, and weights were created by the SVM method. To confirm the practicality of the susceptibility map produced by this improved method, a comparison study with LR, AHP was assessed by means of their validation. The outcome indicated that the combined fuzzy and SVM method (accuracy is 85.73 &#37;) is better than AHP (accuracy is 78.84 &#37;), whereas it is relatively similar to LR (accuracy is 84.55 &#37;). The susceptibility map based on combined the fuzzy and SVM approach also shows that 5.8 &#37; of the study area is assigned as very highly susceptible areas, and 17.8 &#37; of the study area is assigned as highly susceptible areas.
WOS:000384816300004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="35">
<title>Comparative analysis of product-level fusion, support vector machine, and artificial neural network approaches for land cover mapping</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-015-1915-3</url>
<snippet>Increasing the accuracy of thematic maps generated using satellite imagery is a crucial task in remote sensing. In this study, a product-level fusion (PLF) approach based on integration of different land-type maps generated using various satellite-derived indices including normalized difference water index (NDWI), normalized difference built-up index (NDBI), enhanced vegetation index (EVI), and normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI) is proposed to improve the accuracy of land cover mapping. The suitability of the proposed approach for land cover mapping is evaluated in comparison with two high-performance image classification techniques including support vector machine (SVM) and artificial neural network (ANN). The results show that the overall accuracy and kappa values of about 95.95 &#37; and 0.95, 94.91 &#37; and 0.94, and 85.32 &#37; and 0.82 are achieved for the PLF, SVM, and ANN approaches, respectively. The results indicate superiority of the PLF approach than SVM and ANN techniques for land cover classification of Advanced Spaceborne Thermal Emission and Reflection Radiometer (ASTER) imagery, especially for the extraction of forest, rice, and citrus classes. However, SVM technique also provided reliable result for land cover mapping.
WOS:000363719600057
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="36">
<title>Landslide detection and susceptibility mapping in the Sagimakri area, Korea using KOMPSAT-1 and weight of evidence technique</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-013-2385-0</url>
<snippet>The purpose of this study is to detect landslide locations from satellite images and use them for landslide susceptibility mapping in the Sagimakri area, Korea using a geographic information system and a data-driven weight of evidence model. The landslide location areas were identified from Korea multipurpose satellite images by means of change detection technique and further verified by extensive field survey. Subsequently, landslide locations were randomly selected in a 70:30 ratio for training and validation of the model, respectively. A spatial database was constructed, which is composed of topography, forest, soil, and land cover, and 14 landslide-related factors were extracted from the database. The relationships between the detected landslide locations and the factors were identified and quantified by weights of evidence model. Tests of conditional independence were performed for the selection of factors, allowing five different combinations of factors to be analyzed. The relationships were used as the contrast values, W (+) and W (-) of factor ratings in the overlay analysis to create landslide susceptibility indexes and maps. The results of the analysis were validated by comparison with known landslide locations that were not used directly in the analysis.
WOS:000326928600025
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="37">
<title>Construction of knowledge-based spatial decision support system for landslide mapping using fuzzy clustering and KPSO analysis</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-013-1226-5</url>
<snippet>A spatial decision support system, incorporating a geographic information system and a data interpreter based on Data Mining, is developed to analyze the landslide distributions and locations. Satellite remote sensing (RS) can offer an advancing scientific-based knowledge of the landslide problem that, directly and instantly adopt to present the disaster area. However, integrating the RS data into a decision system seems quite difficult. Therefore, this study is decided to develop unsupervised clustering techniques with an improved translation platform to extract some image knowledge on landslide occurrence. More specifically, this study used spatial information technology to attain the vegetation cover and landforms. Conditioning factors are also adopted to attain the further vegetation information. Then, two parallel spatial decision support systems are generated: (a) fuzzy c-means (FCM) is used to analyze the feature of their attributes; (b) the KPSO (k-means + Particle Swam Optimization) is used to approach a parallel study of FCM. Various levels of m values (different fuzzy degrees) are presented with regards to the accuracy of the image classification. While m = 2 the accuracy is 81 &#37; which is lower than m = 3.6 the accuracy is 86 &#37;. Similar results are obtained through KPSO and verifications are made. Finally, the EKTP (Expert Knowledge Translation Platform) is applied to enhance the performance of accuracy.
WOS:000350489900034
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="38">
<title>Landslide-susceptibility analysis using light detection and ranging-derived digital elevation models and logistic regression models: a case study in Mizunami City, Japan</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1117/1.JRS.7.073561</url>
<snippet>To mitigate the damage caused by landslide disasters, different mathematical models have been applied to predict landslide spatial distribution characteristics. Although some researchers have achieved excellent results around the world, few studies take the spatial resolution of the database into account. Four types of digital elevation model (DEM) ranging from 2 to 20 m derived from light detection and ranging technology to analyze landslide susceptibility in Mizunami City, Gifu Prefecture, Japan, are presented. Fifteen landslide-causative factors are considered using a logistic-regression approach to create models for landslide potential analysis. Pre-existing landslide bodies are used to evaluate the performance of the four models. The results revealed that the 20-m model had the highest classification accuracy (71.9&#37;), whereas the 2-m model had the lowest value (68.7&#37;). In the 2-m model, 89.4&#37; of the landslide bodies fit in the medium to very high categories. For the 20-m model, only 83.3&#37; of the landslide bodies were concentrated in the medium to very high classes. When the cell size decreases from 20 to 2 m, the area under the relative operative characteristic increases from 0.68 to 0.77. Therefore, higher-resolution DEMs would provide better results for landslidesusceptibility mapping. (C) 2013 Society of Photo-Optical Instrumentation Engineers (SPIE)
WOS:000319497100005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="39">
<title>Landslide susceptibility assessment by using a neuro-fuzzy model: a case study in the Rupestrian heritage rich area of Matera</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.5194/nhess-13-395-2013</url>
<snippet>The complete assessment of landslide susceptibility needs uniformly distributed detailed information on the territory. This information, which is related to the temporal occurrence of landslide phenomena and their causes, is often fragmented and heterogeneous. The present study evaluates the landslide susceptibility map of the Natural Archaeological Park of Matera (Southern Italy) (Sassi and area Rupestrian Churches sites). The assessment of the degree of "spatial hazard" or "susceptibility" was carried out by the spatial prediction regardless of the return time of the events. The evaluation model for the susceptibility presented in this paper is very focused on the use of innovative techniques of artificial intelligence such as Neural Network, Fuzzy Logic and Neuro-fuzzy Network. The method described in this paper is a novel technique based on a neuro-fuzzy system. It is able to train data like neural network and it is able to shape and control uncertain and complex systems like a fuzzy system. This methodology allows us to derive susceptibility maps of the study area. These data are obtained from thematic maps representing the parameters responsible for the instability of the slopes. The parameters used in the analysis are: plan curvature, elevation (DEM), angle and aspect of the slope, lithology, fracture density, kinematic hazard index of planar and wedge sliding and toppling. Moreover, this method is characterized by the network training which uses a training matrix, consisting of input and output training data, which determine the landslide susceptibility. The neuro-fuzzy method was integrated to a sensitivity analysis in order to overcome the uncertainty linked to the used membership functions. The method was compared to the landslide inventory map and was validated by applying three methods: a ROC (Receiver Operating Characteristic) analysis, a confusion matrix and a SCAI method. The developed neuro-fuzzy method showed a good performance in the determination of the landslide susceptibility map.
WOS:000317006600016
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="40">
<title>Comparison of Logistic Regression and Random Forests techniques for shallow landslide susceptibility assessment in Giampilieri (NE Sicily, Italy)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2015.06.001</url>
<snippet>The aim of this work is to define reliable susceptibility models for shallow landslides using Logistic Regression and Random Forests multivariate statistical techniques. The study area, located in North-East Sicily, was hit on October 1st 2009 by a severe rainstorm (225 mm of cumulative rainfall in 7 h) which caused flash floods and more than 1000 landslides. Several small villages, such as Giampilieri, were hit with 31 fatalities, 6 missing persons and damage to buildings and transportation infrastructures. Landslides, mainly types such as earth and debris translational slides evolving into debris flows, were triggered on steep slopes and involved colluvium and regolith materials which cover the underlying metamorphic bedrock. The work has been carried out with the following steps; i) realization of a detailed event landslide inventory map through field surveys coupled with observation of high resolution aerial colour orthophoto; ii) identification of landslide source areas; iii) data preparation of landslide controlling factors and descriptive statistics based on a bivariate method (Frequency Ratio) to get an initial overview on existing relationships between causative factors and shallow landslide source areas; iv) choice of criteria for the selection and sizing of the mapping unit; v) implementation of 5 multivariate statistical susceptibility models based on Logistic Regression and Random Forests techniques and focused on landslide source areas; vi) evaluation of the influence of sample size and type of sampling on results and performance of the models; vii) evaluation of the predictive capabilities of the models using ROC curve, AUC and contingency tables; viii) comparison of model results and obtained susceptibility maps; and ix) analysis of temporal variation of landslide susceptibility related to input parameter changes. Models based on Logistic Regression and Random Forests have demonstrated excellent predictive capabilities. Land use and wildfire variables were found to have a strong control on the occurrence of very rapid shallow landslides. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000363827400011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="41">
<title>A hybrid feature selection algorithm integrating an extreme learning machine for landslide susceptibility modeling of Mt. Woomyeon, South Korea</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2016.03.023</url>
<snippet>An ever-increasing trend of extreme rainfall events in South Korea owing to climate change is causing shallow landslides and debris flows in mountains that cover 70&#37; of the total land area of the nation. These catastrophic, gravity-driven processes cost the government several billion KRW (South Korean Won) in losses in addition to fatalities every year. The most common type of landslide observed is the shallow landslide, which occurs at 1-3 m depth, and may mobilize into more catastrophic flow-type landslides. Hence, to predict potential landslide areas, susceptibility maps are developed in a geographical information system (GIS) environment utilizing available morphological, hydrological, geotechnical, and geological data. Landslide susceptibility models were developed using 163 landslide points and an equal number of nonlandslide points in Mt. Woomyeon, Seoul, and 23 landslide conditioning factors. However, because not all of the factors contribute to the determination of the spatial probability for landslide initiation, and a simple filter or wrapper-based approach is not efficient in identifying all of the relevant features, a feedback-loop-based hybrid algorithm was implemented in conjunction with a learning scheme called an extreme learning machine, which is based on a single-layer, feed-forward network Validation of the constructed susceptibility model was conducted using a testing set of landslide inventory data through a prediction rate curve. The model selected 13 relevant conditioning factors out of the initial 23; and the resulting susceptibility map shows a success rate of 85&#37; and a prediction rate of 89.45&#37;, indicating a good performance, in contrast to the low success and prediction rate of 69.19&#37; and 56.19&#37;, respectively, as obtained using a wrapper technique. (C) 2016 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000376712900004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="42">
<title>Landslide susceptibility evaluation based on BPNN and GIS: a case of Guojiaba in the Three Gorges Reservoir Area</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/13658816.2014.992436</url>
<snippet>A landslide susceptibility evaluation is vital for disaster management and development planning in the Yangtze River Three Gorges Reservoir Area. In this study, with the support of remote sensing and Geographic Information System, 4 factor groups comprising 10 separate subfactors of landslide-related data layers were selected to establish a susceptibility evaluation model based on the back-propagation neural network including slope, aspect, plan curvature, strata and lithology, distance to faults, land use/land cover, Normalized Difference Vegetation Index, Normalized Difference Water Index, distance from roads, and effect of rivers. During model development, a three-layered interconnected neural network structure of 10 (input layer) x 20 (hidden layer) x 1 (output layer) was used for evaluating the landslide susceptibility in Guojiaba. At the same time, a back-propagation algorithm was applied to calculate the weights between the input layer and the hidden layer and between the hidden layer and the output layer. The results showed that the effect of slope has the highest weight value (0.2051), which is more than two times that of the other factors, followed by strata and lithology (0.1213) and then the effect of rivers (0.1201). At the end of the susceptibility evaluation, the area was divided into four zones such as very high, high, moderate and low susceptibility. For verification, the receiver operating characteristic curve for the back-propagation neural network-derived landslide susceptibility evaluation model was drawn, and the results showed that the area under the receiver operating characteristic curve was 0.8790 and the prediction accuracy was 88&#37;. Furthermore, the results obtained from this article were then verified by comparing with the existing landslide historical data and multiple field-verified results. Lastly, the landslide susceptibility map will help decision makers in risk management, site selection, site planning, and the design of control engineering.
WOS:000359723200002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="43">
<title>GIS-based groundwater spring potential assessment and mapping in the Birjand Township, southern Khorasan Province, Iran</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10040-013-1089-6</url>
<snippet>Three statistical models-frequency ratio (FR), weights-of-evidence (WofE) and logistic regression (LR)-produced groundwater-spring potential maps for the Birjand Township, southern Khorasan Province, Iran. In total, 304 springs were identified in a field survey and mapped in a geographic information system (GIS), out of which 212 spring locations were randomly selected to be modeled and the remaining 92 were used for the model evaluation. The effective factors-slope angle, slope aspect, elevation, topographic wetness index (TWI), stream power index (SPI), slope length (LS), plan curvature, lithology, land use, and distance to river, road, fault-were derived from the spatial database. Using these effective factors, groundwater spring potential was calculated using the three models, and the results were plotted in ArcGIS. The receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves were drawn for spring potential maps and the area under the curve (AUC) was computed. The final results indicated that the FR model (AUC = 79.38 &#37;) performed better than the WofE (AUC = 75.69 &#37;) and LR (AUC = 63.71 &#37;) models. Sensitivity and factor analyses concluded that the bivariate statistical index model (i.e. FR) can be used as a simple tool in the assessment of groundwater spring potential when a sufficient number of data are obtained.
WOS:000334933000009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="44">
<title>Ensemble of ground subsidence hazard maps using fuzzy logic</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.2478/s13533-012-0175-y</url>
<snippet>Hazard maps of ground subsidence around abandoned underground coal mines (AUCMs) in Samcheok, Korea, were constructed using fuzzy ensemble techniques and a geographical information system (GIS). To evaluate the factors related to ground subsidence, a spatial database was constructed from topographic, geologic, mine tunnel, land use, groundwater, and ground subsidence maps. Spatial data, topography, geology, and various ground-engineering data for the subsidence area were collected and compiled in a database for mapping ground-subsidence hazard (GSH). The subsidence area was randomly split 70/30 for training and validation of the models. The relationships between the detected ground-subsidence area and the factors were identified and quantified by frequency ratio (FR), logistic regression (LR) and artificial neural network (ANN) models. The relationships were used as factor ratings in the overlay analysis to create ground-subsidence hazard indexes and maps. The three GSH maps were then used as new input factors and integrated using fuzzy-ensemble methods to make better hazard maps. All of the hazard maps were validated by comparison with known subsidence areas that were not used directly in the analysis. As the result, the ensemble model was found to be more effective in terms of prediction accuracy than the individual model.
WOS:000339803900007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="45">
<title>Application of data-driven evidential belief functions to landslide susceptibility mapping in Jinbu, Korea</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.catena.2012.07.014</url>
<snippet>Evidential belief function (EBF) model was applied and validated for analysis of landslide susceptibility in the Pyungchang area of Korea using geographic information system. Areas of landslide occurrence in the study area were determined from the interpretation of aerial photographs and subsequent field surveys. Landslide locations were randomly allocated for landslide susceptibility map generation (70&#37;) and validation (30&#37;) purposes. Maps relevant to landslide occurrence (topography, geology, soil, and forest cover) were assembled in a spatial database, from which 17 landslide-related factors were extracted. The relationships between the observed landslide locations and these factors were identified and quantified using the EBF model. Three relationships were calculated: disbelief (Dis), uncertainty (Unc), and belief (Bel). The quantified relationships between each factor and landslide locations of each factor with known landslides were then used as factor ratings in an overlay analysis to create landslide susceptibility indices and maps. The most representative of the resulting susceptibility maps (the Bel map) was validated using the landslide data reserved for validation. The landslide susceptibility map demonstrates 85.96&#37; accuracy. Thus, the EBF model was found to be effective in terms of prediction accuracy. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000310037300003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="46">
<title>Application of frequency ratio, weights of evidence and evidential belief function models in landslide susceptibility mapping</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10106049.2016.1165294</url>
<snippet>The landslide hazard occurred in Taibai County has the characteristics of the typical landslides in mountain hinterland. The slopes mainly consist of residual sediments and locate along the highway. Most of them are in the less stable state and in high risk during rainfall in flood season especially. The main purpose of this paper is to produce landslide susceptibility maps for Taibai County (China). In the first stage, a landslide inventory map and the input layers of the landslide conditioning factors were prepared in the geographic information system supported by field investigations and remote sensing data. The landslides conditioning factors considered for the study area were slope angle, altitude, slope aspect, plan curvature, profile curvature, distance to faults, distance to rivers, distance to roads, normalized difference vegetation index, lithological unit, rainfall and land use. Subsequently, the thematic data layers of conditioning factors were integrated by frequency ratio (FR), weights of evidence (WOE) and evidential belief function (EBF) models. As a result, landslide susceptibility maps were obtained. In order to compare the predictive ability of these three models, a validation procedure was conducted. The curves of cumulative area percentage of ordered index values vs. the cumulative percentage of landslide numbers were plotted and the values of area under the curve (AUC) were calculated. The predictive ability was characterized by the AUC values and it indicates that all these models considered have relatively similar and high accuracies. The success rate of FR, WOE and EBF models was 0.9161, 0.9132 and 0.9129, while the prediction rate of the three models was 0.9061, 0.9052 and 0.9007, respectively. Considering the accuracy and simplicity comprehensively, the FR model is the optimum method. These landslide susceptibility maps can be used for preliminary land use planning and hazard mitigation purpose.
WOS:000399646500003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="47">
<title>Applying artificial neural networks to estimate suspended sediment concentrations along the southern coast of the Caspian Sea using MODIS images</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-013-1171-3</url>
<snippet>In this day and age, most environmental researchers use satellite data for monitoring and assessing of water quality indicators since the traditional methods are both time- and money-consuming. One of the most important water quality parameters that can be assessed in coastal waters and river estuaries using remote sensing techniques is suspended sediment concentration (SSC). It regulates primary production and has substantial influence on the migration of pollutants, temperature, and marine life. In this study, Moderate-Resolution Imagine Spectrometry (MODIS) images were used to retrieve the SSC along the southern coast of the Caspian Sea. MODIS of 250 m resolution data were utilized because they have the highest spatial resolution of all the MODIS bands. In situ data were gathered with multiple campaigns with fast motor boats, while the MODIS sensor was passing over the study area. The goal of this article is to apply artificial neural networks (ANN) to retrieve SSC from satellite remote sensing imagery. ANN function as an intelligent structure to model a variety of nonlinear relationships because iteration-based inversion methods need long computation times for common usage. Using a validation data set and a testing data set, the network could be validated. The learning process was more efficient which resulted in a shorter learning time. The validation data set played a vital role as a stopping criterion during the training procedure to overcome the overtraining problem. A robust relationship between MODIS bands 1 and 2 and in situ data was established based on a three-layer ANN with six neurons in the hidden layer. Root mean squared error and R-2 values for this model were 0.853 and 0.969 mg/L, respectively, for all data. Results of this study reveal that the SSC in the Caspian Sea gradually decreases from west to east.
WOS:000350489900023
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="48">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping based on frequency ratio and logistic regression models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-012-0526-5</url>
<snippet>The aim of this study is to apply and compare a probability model, frequency ratio and statistical model, and a logistic regression to Sajaroud area, Northern Iran using geographic information system. Landslide locations of the study area were detected from interpretation of aerial photographs and field surveys. Landslide-related factors such as elevation, slope gradient, slope aspect, slope curvature, rainfall, distance to fault, distance to drainage, distance to road, land use, and geology were calculated from the topographic and geology map and LANDSAT ETM satellite imagery. The spatial relationships between the landslide location and each landslide-related factor were analyzed and then landslide susceptibility maps were produced using the frequency ratio and forward stepwise logistic regression methods. Finally, the maps were tested and compared using known landslide locations, and success rates were calculated. Predicted accuracy values for frequency ratio (79.48&#37;) and logistic regression models showed that the map obtained from frequency ratio model is more accurate than the logistic regression (77.4&#37;) model. The models used in this study have shown a great deal of importance for watershed management and land use planning.
WOS:000320662000028
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="49">
<title>Groundwater spring potential mapping using bivariate statistical model and GIS in the Taleghan Watershed, Iran</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-013-1161-5</url>
<snippet>The aim of the current study was to produce groundwater spring potential map using a bivariate statistical model (frequency ratio) and geographical information system (GIS) in the Taleghan Watershed, Alborz Province, Iran. Firstly, field surveys were done for identifying and springs inventory mapping. In total, 457 springs were identified and mapped in GIS; out of that, 320 (70 &#37;) locations were selected for training and the remaining 137 (30 &#37;) cases were used for the model validation. The effective factors on the groundwater spring such as: slope percent, slope aspect, altitude, topographic wetness index, stream power index, slope length, plan curvature, distance from rivers, distance from roads, distance from faults, lithology, land use, soil hydrology groups, and drainage density were derived from the spatial database. Using the above effective factors, groundwater spring potential mapping was calculated using FR model as a bivariate statistical model, and the results were plotted in Arc GIS. Eventually, the receiver operating characteristic curve was drawn for spring potential map and the area under the curve (AUC) was figured. Validation of results indicated that the frequency ratio model (AUC=75.99 &#37;) performed fairly good predication accuracy. The results of groundwater spring potential map may be helpful for planners and engineers in water resource management and land use planning.
WOS:000350489900025
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="50">
<title>Spatial prediction of flood susceptible areas using rule based decision tree (DT) and a novel ensemble bivariate and multivariate statistical models in GIS</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2013.09.034</url>
<snippet>Flood is one of the natural hazards which occur all over the world and it is critical to be controlled through proper management. Severe flood events in Kelantan, Malaysia cause damage to both life and property every year, and therefore the development of flood model to recognize the susceptible areas in watersheds is important for decision makers. Remote sensing (RS) and geographic information system (GIS) techniques could be useful in hydrological studies while they are able to fulfill all the requirements for comprehensive, rapid and accurate analysis. The aim of the current research is to compare the prediction performances of two different approaches such as rule-based decision tree (DT) and combination of frequency ratio (FR) and logistic regression (LR) statistical methods for flood susceptibility mapping at Kelantan, Malaysia. DT is based on the rules which are created precisely and strongly by considering all the characteristics of the variables which can enhance the performance of the flood susceptibility mapping. On the other hand, LR as multivariate statistical analysis (MSA) has some weak points. For that reason, FR was used to analyze the impact of classes of each variable on flood occurrence and overcome the weakness of LR. At first, flood inventory map with a total of 155 flood locations was extracted from various sources over the part of the Kelantan. Then the flood inventory data was randomly divided into a testing dataset 70&#37; (115 flood locations) for training the models and the remaining 30&#37; (40 flood locations) was used for validation purpose. The spatial database includes digital elevation model (DEM), curvature, geology, river, stream power index (SPI), rainfall, land use/cover (LULC), soil type, topographic wetness index (TWI) and slope. For validation both success and prediction rate curves were performed. The validation results showed that, area under the curve for the results of DT and integrated method of FR and LR was 87&#37; and 90&#37; for success rate and 82&#37; and 83&#37; for prediction rate respectively. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000328592300006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="51">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping &amp; prediction using Support Vector Machine for Mandakini River Basin, Garhwal Himalaya, India</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2017.06.013</url>
<snippet>In recent years, various machine learning techniques have been applied for landslide susceptibility mapping. In this study, three different variants of support vector machine viz., SVM, Proximal Support Vector Machine (PSVM) and L-2-Support Vector Machine - Modified Finite Newton (L-2-SVM-MFN) have been applied on the Mandakini River Basin in Uttarakhand, India to carry out the landslide susceptibility mapping. Eight thematic layers such as elevation, slope, aspect, drainages, geology/lithology, buffer of thrusts/faults, buffer of streams and soil along with the past landslide data were mapped in GIS environment and used for landslide susceptibility mapping in MATLAB. The study area covering 1625 km(2) has merely 0.11&#37; of area under landslides. There are 2009 pixels for past landslides out of which 50&#37; (1000) landslides were considered as training set while remaining 50&#37; as testing set. The performance of these techniques has been evaluated and the computational results show that L-2-SVM-MFN obtains higher prediction values (0.829) of receiver operating characteristic curve (AUC-area under the curve) as compared to 0.807 for PSVM model and 0.79 for SVM. The results obtained from L-2-SVM-MFN model are found to be superior than other SVM prediction models and suggest the usefulness of this technique to problem of landslide susceptibility mapping where training data is very less. However, these techniques can be used for satisfactory determination of susceptible zones with these inputs.
WOS:000413175000009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="52">
<title>Quantitative assessment of landslide susceptibility along the Xianshuihe fault zone, Tibetan Plateau, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2015.07.012</url>
<snippet>The Xianshuihe fault (XSF) zone is a sinistral-slip fault system on the eastern margin of the Tibetan Plateau, with high Quaternary activity and frequent historic earthquakes. Large landslides along the fault zone have caused substantial damage and are the second-most important regional hazard after earthquakes. A landslide inventory in a 7339-km(2) area along the XSF zone documented 415 landslides and evaluated landslide distribution characteristics using frequency ratio (FR) and weight-of-evidence (WOE) models to map landslide susceptibility. A total of 11 variables were analyzed as input variables: slope angle, slope aspect, altitude, planform curvature, topographic wetness index, distance from active faults, lithology, annual rainfall, distance from rivers, distance from roads, and the NDVI of the study area. Among these factors, the distance from active faults, altitude, slope angle, aspect, lithology, and rainfall were the dominant influencing factors. Assessment of six susceptibility mapping schemes with FR and WOE models using the ROC method showed that, while all six of the model schemes produced good results, on the whole, the FR model performed better than the WOE model. The landslide susceptibility map of the FR model with six variables performed as well as the WOE model with the full 11 variables. Inclusion of more variables did not necessarily translate into a better predictive capability. Several factors typically associated with susceptibility to rainfall-triggered landslides-topographic convergence, rainfall, and topographic wetness index-either did not follow expected patterns (rainfall) or were not good general predictors of landslide locations (topographic convergence and wetness index). In contrast distance to active faults, slope aspect, and topographic divergence were the best predictors as measured by the FR method. This combination points to earthquakes rather than rainfall as the dominant landslide-triggering mechanism in the study area. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000361867900008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="53">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping in Mizunami City, Japan: A comparison between logistic regression, bivariate statistical analysis and multivariate adaptive regression spline models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.catena.2015.08.007</url>
<snippet>Landslides are dangerous natural hazards. Because of their threat, a comprehensive landslide susceptibility map should be produced to reduce the possible damages to people and infrastructure. The quality of landslide susceptibility maps is influenced by many factors, such as the quality of input data and the selection of mathematical models. This study aimed to identify the optimal quantitative method for landslide susceptibility mapping in Mizunami City, Japan. Three mathematical methods, logistic regression (LR), bivariate statistical analysis (BS), and multivariate adaptive regression spline models (MARSplines), were used to create landslide-susceptibility maps by comparing the past landslide distribution and the conditioning factor thematic maps. A landslide inventory map with a total of 222 landslide locations was extracted from aerial photographs provided by NIED (National Research Institute for Earth Science and Disaster Prevention, Japan). Then, the landslide inventory was randomly divided into two datasets: 50&#37; was used for training the models and the remaining 50&#37; for validation purposes. The landslide inventory map provided by NIED and an area under the ROC curve were used to evaluate model performance. We found that the MARSpline method resulted in a better prediction rate (79&#37;) when compared to LR (75&#37;) and BS (77&#37;). In addition, a higher percentage of landslide polygons were found in the high to very high classes using the MARSpline method. Therefore, we concluded that the MARSpline method was the most efficient method for landslide susceptibility mapping in this study area. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000366225900028
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="54">
<title>Relative effect method of landslide susceptibility zonation in weathered granite soil: a case study in Deokjeok-ri Creek, South Korea</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-014-1065-z</url>
<snippet>The objective of this study was to produce and evaluate a landslide susceptibility map for weathered granite soils in Deokjeok-ri Creek, South Korea. The relative effect (RE) method was used to determine the relationship between landslide causative factors (CFs) and landslide occurrence. To determine the effect of CFs on landslides, data layers of aspect, elevation, slope, internal relief, curvature, distance to drainage, drainage density, stream power index, sediment transport index, topographic wetness index, soil drainage character, soil type, soil depth, forest type, timber age, and geology were analyzed in a geographical information system (GIS) environment. A GIS-based landslide inventory map of 748 landslide locations was prepared using data from previous reports, aerial photographic interpretation, and extensive field work. A RE model was generated from a training set consisting of 673 randomly selected landslides in the inventory map, with the remaining 75 landslides used for validation of the susceptibility map. The results of the analysis were verified using the landslide location data. According to the analysis, the RE model had a success rate of 86.3 &#37; and a predictive accuracy of 88.6 &#37;. The validation results showed satisfactory agreement between the susceptibility map and the existing data on landslide locations. The results of this study can therefore be used to mitigate landslide-induced hazards and to plan land use.
WOS:000335827100050
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="55">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping along PLUS expressways in Malaysia using probabilistic based model in GIS</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1088/1755-1315/20/1/012031</url>
<snippet>PLUS Berhad holds the concession for a total of 987 km of toll expressways in Malaysia, the longest of which is the North-South Expressway or NSE. Acting as the backbone of the west coast of the peninsula, the NSE stretches from the Malaysian-Thai border in the north to the border with neighbouring Singapore in the south, linking several major cities and towns along the way. North-South Expressway in Malaysia contributes to the country economic development through trade, social and tourism sector. Presently, the highway is good in terms of its condition and connection to every state but some locations need urgent attention. Stability of slopes at these locations is of most concern as any instability can cause danger to the motorist. In this paper, two study locations have been analysed; they are Gua Tempurung (soil slope) and Jelapang (rock slope) which are obviously having two different characteristics. These locations passed through undulating terrain with steep slopes where landslides are common and the probability of slope instability due to human activities in surrounding areas is high. A combination of twelve (12) landslide conditioning factors database on slope stability such as slope degree and slope aspect were extracted from IFSAR (interoferometric synthetic aperture radar) while landuse, lithology and structural geology were constructed from interpretation of high resolution satellite data from World View II, Quickbird and Ikonos. All this information was analysed in geographic information system (GIS) environment for landslide susceptibility mapping using probabilistic based frequency ratio model. Consequently, information on the slopes such as inventories, condition assessments and maintenance records were assessed through total expressway maintenance management system or better known as TEMAN. The above mentioned system is used by PLUS as an asset management and decision support tools for maintenance activities along the highways as well as for data quality checking and integrity. In this study, TEMAN data were further analysed and subsequently integrated with landslide susceptible map for Gua Tempurung and Jelapang area in Perak.
WOS:000346761600031
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="56">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping at Vaz Watershed (Iran) using an artificial neural network model: a comparison between multilayer perceptron (MLP) and radial basic function (RBF) algorithms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-012-0610-x</url>
<snippet>Landslide susceptibility and hazard assessments are the most important steps in landslide risk mapping. The main objective of this study was to investigate and compare the results of two artificial neural network (ANN) algorithms, i.e., multilayer perceptron (MLP) and radial basic function (RBF) for spatial prediction of landslide susceptibility in Vaz Watershed, Iran. At first, landslide locations were identified by aerial photographs and field surveys, and a total of 136 landside locations were constructed from various sources. Then the landslide inventory map was randomly split into a training dataset 70 &#37; (95 landslide locations) for training the ANN model and the remaining 30 &#37; (41 landslides locations) was used for validation purpose. Nine landslide conditioning factors such as slope, slope aspect, altitude, land use, lithology, distance from rivers, distance from roads, distance from faults, and rainfall were constructed in geographical information system. In this study, both MLP and RBF algorithms were used in artificial neural network model. The results showed that MLP with Broyden-Fletcher-Goldfarb-Shanno learning algorithm is more efficient than RBF in landslide susceptibility mapping for the study area. Finally the landslide susceptibility maps were validated using the validation data (i.e., 30 &#37; landslide location data that was not used during the model construction) using area under the curve (AUC) method. The success rate curve showed that the area under the curve for RBF and MLP was 0.9085 (90.85 &#37;) and 0.9193 (91.93 &#37;) accuracy, respectively. Similarly, the validation result showed that the area under the curve for MLP and RBF models were 0.881 (88.1 &#37;) and 0.8724 (87.24 &#37;), respectively. The results of this study showed that landslide susceptibility mapping in the Vaz Watershed of Iran using the ANN approach is viable and can be used for land use planning.
WOS:000322028400012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="57">
<title>Evaluation and comparison of landslide susceptibility mapping methods: a case study for the Ulus district, Bartin, northern Turkey</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/13658816.2014.953164</url>
<snippet>The purpose of this study was to investigate the capabilities of different landslide susceptibility methods by comparing their results statistically and spatially to select the best method that portrays the susceptibility zones for the Ulus district of the Bartin province (northern Turkey). Susceptibility maps based on spatial regression (SR), linear discriminant analysis (LDA), quadratic discriminant analysis (QDA), logistic regression (LR) method, and artificial neural network method (ANN) were generated, and the effect of each geomorphological parameter was determined. The landslide inventory map digitized from previous studies was used as a base map for landslide occurrence. All of the analyses were implemented with respect to landslides classified as rotational, active, and deeper than 5m. Three different sets of data were used to produce nine explanatory variables (layers). The study area was divided into grids of 90mx90m, and the seed cell technique was applied to obtain statistically balanced population distribution over landslide inventory area. The constructed dataset was divided into two datasets as training and test. The initial assessment consisted of multicollinearity of explanatory variables. Empirical information entropy analysis was implemented to quantify the spatial distribution of the outcomes of these methods. Results of the analyses were validated by using success rate curve (SRC) and prediction rate curve (PRC) methods. Additionally, statistical and spatial comparisons of the results were performed to determine the most suitable susceptibility zonation method in this large-scale study area. In accordance with all these comparisons, it is concluded that ANN was the best method to represent landslide susceptibility throughout the study area with an acceptable processing time.
WOS:000350367900007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="58">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping at Zonouz Plain, Iran using genetic programming and comparison with frequency ratio, logistic regression, and artificial neural network models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-013-0932-3</url>
<snippet>Without a doubt, landslide is one of the most disastrous natural hazards and landslide susceptibility maps (LSMs) in regional scale are the useful guide to future development planning. Therefore, the importance of generating LSMs through different methods is popular in the international literature. The goal of this study was to evaluate the susceptibility of the occurrence of landslides in Zonouz Plain, located in North-West of Iran. For this purpose, a landslide inventory map was constructed using field survey, air photo/satellite image interpretation, and literature search for historical landslide records. Then, seven landslide-conditioning factors such as lithology, slope, aspect, elevation, land cover, distance to stream, and distance to road were utilized for generation LSMs by various models: frequency ratio (FR), logistic regression (LR), artificial neural network (ANN), and genetic programming (GP) methods in geographic information system (GIS). Finally, total four LSMs were obtained by using these four methods. For verification, the results of LSM analyses were confirmed using the landslide inventory map containing 190 active landslide zones. The validation process showed that the prediction accuracy of LSMs, produced by the FR, LR, ANN, and GP, was 87.57, 89.42, 92.37, and 93.27 &#37;, respectively. The obtained results indicated that the use of GP for generating LSMs provides more accurate prediction in comparison with FR, LR, and ANN. Furthermore; GP model is superior to the ANN model because it can present an explicit formulation instead of weights and biases matrices.
WOS:000331395900024
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="59">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping at Gongliu county, China using artificial neural network and weight of evidence models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12303-016-0003-3</url>
<snippet>The aim of this study was to apply and to verify the use of artificial neural network (ANN) and weight of evidence (WoE) models to landslide susceptibility mapping in the Gongliu county, China, using a geographic information system (GIS). For this aim, in this study, a landslide inventory map was prepared using earlier reports and aerial photographs as well as by carrying out field surveys. A total of 163 landslides (70&#37; out of 233 detected landslides) were randomly selected for model training, and the remaining 70 landslides (30&#37;) were used for the model validation. Then, a total number of twelve landslide conditioning factors, such as slope angle, slope aspect, general curvature, plan curvature, profile curvature, altitude, distance to rivers, distance to roads, lithology, rainfall, normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI), and sediment transport index (STI), were used in the analysis. Landslide hazardous areas were analyzed and mapped using the landslide-occurrence factors by ANN and WoE models. Finally the output maps were validated using the area under the curve (AUC) method. The validation results showed that the ANN model with a success rate of 82.51&#37; and predictive accuracy of 77.31&#37; performs better than WoE (success rate, 79.82&#37;; predictive accuracy, 74.59&#37;) model. Overall, both models showed almost similar results. Therefore, the two landslide susceptibility maps obtained were successful and can be useful for preliminary general land use planning and hazard mitigation purpose.
WOS:000384518800010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="60">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping using GIS-based statistical models and Remote sensing data in tropical environment</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/srep09899</url>
<snippet>This research presents the results of the GIS-based statistical models for generation of landslide susceptibility mapping using geographic information system (GIS) and remote-sensing data for Cameron Highlands area in Malaysia. Ten factors including slope, aspect, soil, lithology, NDVI, land cover, distance to drainage, precipitation, distance to fault, and distance to road were extracted from SAR data, SPOT 5 and WorldView-1 images. The relationships between the detected landslide locations and these ten related factors were identified by using GIS-based statistical models including analytical hierarchy process (AHP), weighted linear combination (WLC) and spatial multi-criteria evaluation (SMCE) models. The landslide inventory map which has a total of 92 landslide locations was created based on numerous resources such as digital aerial photographs, AIRSAR data, WorldView-1 images, and field surveys. Then, 80&#37; of the landslide inventory was used for training the statistical models and the remaining 20&#37; was used for validation purpose. The validation results using the Relative landslide density index (R-index) and Receiver operating characteristic (ROC) demonstrated that the SMCE model (accuracy is 96&#37;) is better in prediction than AHP (accuracy is 91&#37;) and WLC (accuracy is 89&#37;) models. These landslide susceptibility maps would be useful for hazard mitigation purpose and regional planning.
WOS:000353284400001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="61">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping using LiDAR and DMC data: a case study in the Three Gorges area, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-012-2151-8</url>
<snippet>The objective of this study is to map landslide susceptibility in Zigui segment of the Yangtze Three Gorges area that is known as one of the most landslide-prone areas in China by using data from light detection and ranging (LiDAR) and digital mapping camera (DMC). The likelihood ratio (LR) and logistic regression model (LRM) were used in this study. The work is divided into three phases. The first phase consists of data processing and analysis. In this phase, LiDAR and DMC data and geological maps were processed, and the landslide-controlling factors were derived such as landslide density, digital elevation model (DEM), slope angle, aspect, lithology, land use and distance from drainage. Among these, the landslide inventories, land use and drainage were constructed with both LiDAR and DMC data; DEM, slope angle and aspect were constructed with LiDAR data; lithology was taken from the 1:250,000 scale geological maps. The second phase is the logistic regression analysis. In this phase, the LR was applied to find the correlation between the landslide locations and the landslide-controlling factors, whereas the LRM was used to predict the occurrence of landslides based on six factors. To calculate the coefficients of LRM, 13,290,553 pixels was used, 29.5 &#37; of the total pixels. The logical regression coefficients of landslide-controlling factors were obtained by logical regression analysis with SPSS 17.0 software. The accuracy of the LRM was 88.8 &#37; on the whole. The third phase is landslide susceptibility mapping and verification. The mapping result was verified using the landslide location data, and 64.4 &#37; landslide pixels distributed in "extremely high" zone and "high" zone; in addition, verification was performed using a success rate curve. The verification result show clearly that landslide susceptibility zones were in close agreement with actual landslide areas in the field. It is also shown that the factors that were applied in this study are appropriate; lithology, elevation and distance from drainage are primary factors for the landslide susceptibility mapping in the area, while slope angle, aspect and land use are secondary.
WOS:000323737300019
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="62">
<title>Data Mining Approaches for Landslide Susceptibility Mapping in Umyeonsan, Seoul, South Korea</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/app7070683</url>
<snippet>The application of data mining models has become increasingly popular in recent years in assessments of a variety of natural hazards such as landslides and floods. Data mining techniques are useful for understanding the relationships between events and their influencing variables. Because landslides are influenced by a combination of factors including geomorphological and meteorological factors, data mining techniques are helpful in elucidating the mechanisms by which these complex factors affect landslide events. In this study, spatial data mining approaches based on data on landslide locations in the geographic information system environment were investigated. The topographical factors of slope, aspect, curvature, topographic wetness index, stream power index, slope length factor, standardized height, valley depth, and downslope distance gradient were determined using topographical maps. Additional soil and forest variables using information obtained from national soil and forest maps were also investigated. A total of 17 variables affecting the frequency of landslide occurrence were selected to construct a spatial database, and support vector machine (SVM) and artificial neural network (ANN) models were applied to predict landslide susceptibility from the selected factors. In the SVM model, linear, polynomial, radial base function, and sigmoid kernels were applied in sequence; the model yielded 72.41&#37;, 72.83&#37;, 77.17&#37; and 72.79&#37; accuracy, respectively. The ANN model yielded a validity accuracy of 78.41&#37;. The results of this study are useful in guiding effective strategies for the prevention and management of landslides in urban areas.
WOS:000407700400040
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="63">
<title>Landslide Susceptibility Mapping in Changbai Mountain Area Using GIS and Artificial Neural Network(ANN)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>To analyze the landslide susceptibility in changbai mountain area, we used GIS(Geographic Information System) and ANN(Artificial Neural Network) method in this paper. To assess the landslide susceptibility, five factors which affect the landslide occurrence were selected as: slope, aspect, soil type, geological type, and land use. The weight values of each factor were calculated by the ANN method. Then, we obtained the susceptibility map using weighted overlay GIS method. Finally, the landslide susceptibility map shows that the very dangerous areas (0.9 or higher) were mainly distributed in the mountainous areas around JiAn Shi, LinJiang Shi, and HeLong Shi near the china-north Korea border and in the mountainous area between the WangQing Xian and AnTu Xian.
WOS:000337469200023
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="64">
<title>GIS-based landslide susceptibility evaluation using fuzzy-AHP multi-criteria decision-making techniques in the Abha Watershed, Saudi Arabia</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-018-7451-1</url>
<snippet>Landslides are natural geological disasters causing massive destructions and loss of lives, as well as severe damage to natural resources, so it is essential to delineate the area that probably will be affected by landslides. Landslide susceptibility mapping (LSM) is making increasing implications for GIS-based spatial analysis in combination with multi-criteria evaluation (MCE) methods. It is considered to be an effective tool to understand natural disasters related to mass movements and carry out an appropriate risk assessment. This study is based on an integrated approach of GIS and statistical modelling including fuzzy analytical hierarchy process (FAHP), weighted linear combination and MCE models. In the modelling process, eleven causative factors include slope aspect, slope, rainfall, geology, geomorphology, distance from lineament, distance from drainage networks, distance from the road, land use/land cover, soil erodibility and vegetation proportion were identified for landslide susceptibility mapping. These factors were identified based on the (1) literature review, (2) the expert knowledge, (3) field observation, (4) geophysical investigation, and (5) multivariate techniques. Initially, analytical hierarchy process linked with the fuzzy set theory is used in pairwise comparisons of LSM criteria for ranking purposes. Thereafter, fuzzy membership functions were carried out to determine the criteria weights used in the development of a landslide susceptibility map. These selected thematic maps were integrated using a weighted linear combination method to create the final landslide susceptibility map. Finally, a validation of the results was carried out using a sensitivity analysis based on receiver operator curves and an overlay method using the landslide inventory map. The study results show that the weighted overlay analysis method using the FAHP and eigenvector method is a reliable technique to map landslide susceptibility areas. The landslide susceptibility areas were classified into five categories, viz. very low susceptibility, low susceptibility, moderate susceptibility, high susceptibility, and very high susceptibility. The very high and high susceptibility zones account for 15.11&#37; area coverage. The results are useful to get an impression of the sustainability of the watershed in terms of landsliding and therefore may help decision makers in future planning and mitigation of landslide impacts.
WOS:000429985900013
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="65">
<title>Spatial data analysis and application of evidential belief functions to shallow landslide susceptibility mapping at Mt. Umyeon, Seoul, Korea</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10064-016-0919-x</url>
<snippet>Predictive mapping of landslide occurrence at the regional scale was performed at Mt. Umyeon, in the southern part of Seoul, Korea, using an evidential belief function (EBF) model. To generate the landslide susceptibility map, approximately 90 &#37; of 163 actual landslide locations were randomly selected as a training set, and about 10 &#37; of them were used as a validation set. Spatial data sets relevant to landslide occurrence (topographic factors, hydrologic factors, forest factors, soil factors, and geologic factors) were analyzed in a geographic information system environment. In this study, landslide susceptibility was assessed on the basis of mass function assignment (belief, disbelief, uncertainty, and plausibility) and integration within a data-driven approach. The most representative of the resulting integrated susceptibility maps (the belief map) was validated using the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) method. The verification result showed that the model had an accuracy of 74.3 &#37; and a predictive accuracy of 88.1 &#37;. The frequency ratio (FR) model was also used for comparison with the EBF model. Prediction and success rates of 72.1 and 85.9 &#37; were achieved using the FR model. The validation results showed satisfactory agreement between the susceptibility map and the existing landslide location data. The EBF model was more accurate than the FR model for landslide prediction in the study area. The results of this study can be used to mitigate landslide-induced hazards and for land-use planning.
WOS:000413673700004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="66">
<title>Application of analytical hierarchy process, frequency ratio, and certainty factor models for groundwater potential mapping using GIS</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12145-015-0220-8</url>
<snippet>The main goal of this study was to investigate the analytical hierarchy process (AHP), frequency ratio (FR), and certainty factor (CF) models for groundwater potential mapping using geographical information system (GIS) at Varamin Plain, Tehran province, Iran. In the first step, the groundwater conditioning factors such as altitude, slope angle, slope aspect, topographic witness index, rainfall, drainage density, water table level, aquifer thickness, lithology, and distance from rivers were prepared. The groundwater yield dataset was prepared using earlier reports, and extensive field surveys. In total, 71 groundwater data with high potential yield values of a parts per thousand yen40 m(3)/h were collected and mapped in GIS. Out these, 50 (70 &#37;) cases were randomly selected for models training, and the remaining 21 (30 &#37;) cases were used for the validation purposes. Subsequently, groundwater potential maps were produced using AHP, FR, and CF models in ArcGIS 10.2. Finally, the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves for all the groundwater potential models were constructed and the areas under the curves (AUC) were computed. From the analysis, it is seen that the FR model (AUC = 77.55 &#37;) performs better than AHP (AUC = 73.47 &#37;) and CF (AUC = 65.08 &#37;) models. The results of groundwater potential map can be helpful for future planning in groundwater resource management and land use planning.
WOS:000365266900012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="67">
<title>A GIS-based comparative evaluation of analytical hierarchy process and frequency ratio models for landslide susceptibility mapping</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/02723646.2017.1294522</url>
<snippet>The purpose of this study is to assess the susceptibility of landslides in Wen County, China, using both analytical hierarchy process (AHP) and frequency ratio (FR) models. For this, a total of 529 landslides were identified and randomly split into two groups. The modeling group, which represented approximately 70&#37; of the total landslides, was used as a training set to construct the susceptibility maps. The remaining 30&#37; were used for validation purpose. Eight layers of landslide-related factors were prepared, including slope angle, altitude, distance to rivers, distance to roads, distance to faults, rainfall, lithology, and normalized difference vegetation index. Subsequently, landslide susceptibility maps were produced using the models. For verification, an area under curvature (AUC) and the seed cell area index (SCAI) assessments were applied. The AUC plot estimation results showed that the success rates of the AHP and FR models were 83.55 and 88.42&#37; and the prediction rates were 83.43 and 86.62&#37;, respectively. According to the validation results of the AUC and SCAI evaluations, the map obtained from the FR model is more accurate than that from the AHP model. These landslide susceptibility maps can be used for optimum management by decision makers and land-use planners.
WOS:000402815500002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="68">
<title>GeoFIS: An integrated tool for the assessment of landslide susceptibility</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cageo.2013.12.016</url>
<snippet>In this study, requirements of landslide susceptibility mapping by a Mamdani fuzzy inference system (FIS) are identified, and a single standalone application (GeoFIS) is developed. GeoFIS includes two main open source libraries, one for GIS operations and the other for creating Mamdani FIS. As a result, it is possible to construct a landslide susceptibility map based on expert opinion, to visualize maps instantly and to measure model performance. GeoFIS supports all steps of the landslide susceptibility mapping process, starting from data deployment and ending with performance measurement. In GeoFIS, visual controls allow use of the inferred results and actual landslide occurrence information, and ROC-AUC values are calculated automatically. Moreover, a confusion matrix is produced, and alternative measurement schemes such as recall are suggested, to reveal those performance details not observable with ROC-AUC and to create trust in the inferred results. GeoFIS is applied to the Trabzon region of northern Turkey, and the recall and ROC-AUC values were .902 and .602, respectively. (C)2014 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000335293700003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="69">
<title>Landslide Susceptibility Mapping in Vertical Distribution Law of Precipitation Area: Case of the Xulong Hydropower Station Reservoir, Southwestern China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/w8070270</url>
<snippet>This study focused on landslide susceptibility analysis mapping of the Xulong hydropower station reservoir, which is located in the upstream of Jinsha River, a rapidly uplifting region of the Tibetan Plateau region. Nine factors were employed as landslide conditioning factors in landslide susceptibility mapping. These factors included the slope angle, slope aspect, curvature, geology, distance-to-fault, distance-to-river, vegetation, bedrock uplift and annual precipitation. The rapid bedrock uplift factor was represented by the slope angle. The eight factors were processed with the information content model. Since this area has a significant vertical distribution law of precipitation, the annual precipitation factor was analyzed separately. The analytic hierarchy process weighting method was used to calculate the weights of nine factors. Thus, this study proposed a component approach to combine the normalized eight-factor results with the normalized annual precipitation distribution results. Subsequently, the results were plotted in geographic information system (GIS) and a landslide susceptibility map was produced. The evaluation accuracy analysis method was used as a validation approach. The landslide susceptibility classes were divided into four classes, including low, moderate, high and very high. The results show that the four susceptibility class ratios are 12.9&#37;, 35.06&#37;, 34.11&#37; and 17.92&#37; of the study area, respectively. The red belt in the high elevation area represents the very high susceptibility zones, which followed the vertical distribution law of precipitation. The prediction accuracy was 85.74&#37;, which meant that the susceptibility map was confirmed to be reliable and reasonable. This susceptibility map may contribute to averting the landslide risk in the future construction of the Xulong hydropower station.
WOS:000380764800003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="70">
<title>Evaluation of prediction capability of the artificial neural networks for mapping landslide susceptibility in the Turbolo River catchment (northern Calabria, Italy)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.catena.2013.08.006</url>
<snippet>Landslides are one of the most widespread natural hazards that cause damage to both property and life every year, and therefore, the spatial distribution of the landslide susceptibility is necessary for planning future developmental activities. In this paper the artificial neural network (ANN) technique is tested for developing a landslide susceptibility map in Turbolo River catchment, North Calabria, South Italy. Landslides were mapped through air-photo interpretation and field surveys, by identifying both the landslide depletion zones (DZs) and accumulation zones (AZs); and relevant geo-environmental thematic layers pertaining to landslide predisposing factors were generated using air-photo interpretation, field surveys and Geographic Information System (GIS) tools. Ten predisposing factors were related to the occurrence of landslide: lithology, faults, land use, drainage network, and a series of topographic factors: elevation, slope, aspect, plan curvature, topographic wetness index (TWI) and stream power index (SPI). In order to evaluate and validate landslide susceptibility, the DZs were divided in two groups using a random partition strategy. The first group (training set) was used to prepare the susceptibility map, employing a back-propagation learning algorithm in the Idrisi Taiga software. The second group (testing set) was used to validate the landslide susceptibility model, using the confusion matrix and the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve. The susceptibility map was classified into five susceptibility classes: very low, low, moderate, high, and very high. About 46&#37; of the study area falls in high to very high susceptible classes and most of the DZs mapped (87.3&#37;) occur in the same classes. The validation results showed satisfactory agreement between the susceptibility map and the DZs locations; over 85&#37; of the DZs of the validation set are correctly classified falling in high and very high susceptibility areas. Also, the ROC curve had shown an area under curve (AUC) value of 0.90 which demonstrates the robustness and good reliability of the landslide susceptibility model. According to these results, we conclude that the map produced by the artificial neural network is reliable and the methodology applied in the study produced high performance, and satisfactory results, which may be useful for land planning policy. (C) 2013 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000328237500022
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="71">
<title>Application of spaceborne synthetic aperture radar data for extraction of soil moisture and its use in hydrological modelling at Gottleuba Catchment, Saxony, Germany</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/jfr3.12037</url>
<snippet>Hydrological modelling is a powerful tool for hydrologists and engineers involved in the planning and management of water resources. With the recent advent of computational power and the growing availability of spatial data, remote sensing and geographical information systems technologies can augment to a great extent the conventional methods used in rainfall run-off studies. That means it is possible to accurately describe the characteristics of watershed in particularly when determining the run-off response to rainfall inputs. The main objective of this study is to apply the potential application of spaceborne synthetic aperture radar (SAR) data (i.e. TerraSAR-X and Advanced Land Observing Satellite/Phased Array type L-band Synthetic Aperture Radar (ALOS PALSAR) for soil moisture retrieval) and to improve the spatial input parameters required for hydrological modelling. For the spatial database creation, a high-resolution 2-m aerial laser scanning digital terrain model, soil map, and land use map were used. Rainfall records were transformed into a run-off through hydrological parameterisation of the watershed using Hydrologic Engineering Centers Hydrologic Modelling System (HEC-HMS) software for rainfall run-off simulation. The Soil Conservation Services Curve Number and soil moisture accounting loss methods were selected to calculate the infiltration losses. In this research, soil moisture was derived from two different types of spaceborne SAR data: TerraSAR-X and ALOS PALSAR (L-band). The developed integrated hydrological model was applied to a flood prone area: Gottleuba Catchment in Pirna (Saxony, Germany). For model validation, 10 years historical precipitation data were used. The validated model was further optimised using the extracted soil moisture from SAR data. The simulation results showed a reasonable match between the simulated and the observed hydrographs. Hence, this paper confirms that TerraSAR-X and ALOS PALSAR (L-band) have a high potential for soil moisture mapping as a useful source of information and technique in hydrological modelling.
WOS:000335401600007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="72">
<title>Prediction of rainfall-induced shallow landslides in the Loess Plateau, Yan'an, China, using the TRIGRS model</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/esp.4050</url>
<snippet>In this work, a transient rainfall infiltration and grid-based regional slope-stability model (TRIGRS) was implemented in a case study of Yanan City, Northwest China. In this area, widespread shallow landslides were triggered by the 12 July 2013 exceptional rainstorm event. A high-resolution DEM, soil parameters from in-situ and laboratory measurements, water table depths, the maximum depth of precipitation infiltration and rain-gauge-corrected precipitation of the event, were used as inputs in the TRIGRS model. Shallow landslides triggered on the same day were used to evaluate the modeling results. The summarized results are as follows: (i) The characteristics and distribution of thirty-five shallow landslides triggered by the 12 July 2013 rainfall event were identified in the study area and all were classified as shallow landslides with the maximum depth, area and volume less than 3m, 200m(2) and 1000m(3), respectively, (ii) Four intermediate factor of safety (F-S) maps were generated using the TRIGRS model to represent the scenarios 6, 12, 18 and 24hours after the storm event. The area with F-S&lt;1 increased with the rainfall duration. The percentage of the area with F-S&lt;1 was 0.2&#37;, 3.3&#37;, 3.8&#37; and 5.1&#37; for the four stages, respectively. Twenty-four hours after the rainstorm, TRIGRS predicted that 1255 grid cells failed, which is consistent with the field data. (iii) TRIGRS generated more satisfactory results at a given precipitation threshold than SINMAP, which is ideal for landslide hazard zoning for land-use planning at the regional scale. Comparison results showed that TRIGRS is more useful for landslide prediction for a certain precipitation threshold, also in the regional scale. (iv) Analysis of the responses of loess slope prone to slope failure after different precipitation scenarios revealed that loess slopes are particularly sensitive to extended periods of heavy precipitation. Copyright 
WOS:000400646100006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="73">
<title>Landslide susceptibility, Peloponnese Peninsula in South Greece</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/17445647.2014.884022</url>
<snippet>The aim of this paper is to investigate landslide susceptibility mapping in regional scale, considering the spatial stationarity of the relationship between landslide susceptibility and its influencing factors. Landslides are among the most severe natural hazards and their management has a key role to human safety. During the last decades, a significant number of GIS-based methods for landslide susceptibility assessment and mapping have been proposed in the literature. In this paper, contemporary methods for landslide susceptibility analysis have been applied. The latter include global and local regression analysis aiming to study the relationship between landslide occurrence and its determinants. This paper also examines if this relationship is spatial non-stationary via the application of the Geographically Weighted Regression (GWR). The proposed methodology has been applied in the Peloponnese peninsula, in South Greece. To examine the factors responsible for the occurrence of a landslide event; topographic (slope angle, elevation), geological and other environmental variables (land cover, rainfalls) were considered. The results suggest that GWR provides a potential improvement in landslide susceptibility assessment compared to traditional global regression analysis methods.
WOS:000334117400005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="74">
<title>Spatial prediction of landslide susceptibility in parts of Garhwal Himalaya, India, using the weight of evidence modelling</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10661-015-4535-1</url>
<snippet>Garhwal Himalaya in northern India has emerged as one of the most prominent hot spots of landslide occurrences in the Himalaya mainly due to geological causes related to mountain building processes, steep topography and frequent occurrences of extreme precipitation events. As this region has many pilgrimage and tourist centres, it is visited by hundreds of thousands of people every year, and in the recent past, there has been rapid development to provide adequate roads and building infrastructure. Additionally, attempts are also made to harness hydropower by constructing tunnels, dams and reservoirs and thus altering vulnerable slopes at many places. As a result, the overall risk due to landslide hazards has increased many folds and, therefore, an attempt was made to assess landslide susceptibility using Weights of Evidence (WofE), a well-known bivariate statistical modelling technique implemented in a much improved way using remote sensing and Geographic Information System. This methodology has dual advantage as it demonstrates how to derive critical parameters related to geology, geomorphology, slope, land use and most importantly temporal landslide distribution in one of the data scarce region of the world. Secondly, it allows to experiment with various combination of parameters to assess their cumulative effect on landslides. In total, 15 parameters related to geology, geomorphology, terrain, hydrology and anthropogenic factors and 2 different landslide inventories (prior to 2007 and 2008-2011) were prepared from high-resolution Indian remote sensing satellite data (Cartosat-1 and Resourcesat-1) and were validated by field investigation. Several combinations of parameters were carried out using WofE modelling, and finally using best combination of eight parameters, 76.5 &#37; of overall landslides were predicted in 24 &#37; of the total area susceptible to landslide occurrences. The study has highlighted that using such methodology landslide susceptibility assessment can be carried out in vast stretches of Himalaya in short time in order to assess the impact of development as well as climate change/variability. The resultant map can play a critical role in selecting areas for remedial measures for slope stabilisation as well planning for future development of the region.
WOS:000355917300011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="75">
<title>Environmental modelling of visceral leishmaniasis by susceptibility-mapping using neural networks: a case study in north-western Iran</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.4081/gh.2014.15</url>
<snippet>Visceral leishmaniasis (VL) is a potentially fatal vector-borne zoonotic disease, which has become an increasing public health problem in the north-western part of Iran. This work presents an environmental health modelling approach to map the potential of VL outbreaks in this part of the country. Radial basis functional link networks is used as a data-driven method for predictive mapping of VL in the study area. The high susceptibility areas for VL outbreaks account for 36.3&#37; of the study area and occur mainly in the north (which may affect the neighbouring countries) and South (which is a warning for other provinces in Iran). These parts of the study area have many nomadic, riverside villages. The overall accuracy of the resultant map was 92&#37; in endemic villages. Such susceptibility maps can be used as reconnaissance guides for planning of effective control strategies and identification of possible new VL endemic areas.
WOS:000346512600015
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="76">
<title>A case study for the integration of predictive mineral potential maps</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.2478/s13533-012-0183-y</url>
<snippet>This study aims to elaborate on the mineral potential maps using various models and verify the accuracy for the epithermal gold (Au) - silver (Ag) deposits in a Geographic Information System (GIS) environment assuming that all deposits shared a common genesis. The maps of potential Au and Ag deposits were produced by geological data in Taebaeksan mineralized area, Korea. The methodological framework consists of three main steps: 1) identification of spatial relationships 2) quantification of such relationships and 3) combination of multiple quantified relationships. A spatial database containing 46 Au-Ag deposits was constructed using GIS. The spatial association between training deposits and 26 related factors were identified and quantified by probabilistic and statistical modelling. The mineral potential maps were generated by integrating all factors using the overlay method and recombined afterwards using the likelihood ratio model. They were verified by comparison with test mineral deposit locations. The verification revealed that the combined mineral potential map had the greatest accuracy (83.97&#37;), whereas it was 72.24&#37;, 65.85&#37;, 72.23&#37; and 71.02&#37; for the likelihood ratio, weight of evidence, logistic regression and artificial neural network models, respectively. The mineral potential map can provide useful information for the mineral resource development.
WOS:000340387900009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="77">
<title>Landslide susceptibility assessment using frequency ratio, statistical index and certainty factor models for the Gangu County, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-015-2112-0</url>
<snippet>The purpose of this paper is to produce a reliable susceptibility mapping using frequency ratio (FR), statistical index (SI), and certainty factor (CF) models with the aid of geographic information system (GIS) for the Gangu County, Gansu Province, China. First, a total of 328 landslide locations were detected by literatures, aerial photographs and field surveys; meanwhile, a landslide inventory map was constructed mainly based on landslide locations. Then, 230 (70 &#37;) landslides were randomly selected for modeling, and the remaining 98 (30 &#37;) landslides were used for the model validation. In order to produce a susceptibility map, 12 landslide influencing factors were selected from the database: slope angle, slope aspect, plan curvature, profile curvature, altitude, distance to faults, distance to rivers, distance to roads, NDVI, land use, rainfall, and lithology. Whereafter, the landslide susceptibility maps were mapped using landslide influencing factors based on the FR, SI, and CF models. Finally, the accuracy of the landslide susceptibility maps developed from the three models was validated using area under the curve (AUC) analysis. Through the analysis, it is seen that the prediction accuracy of the three models was 75.62&#37; for FR model, 75.71&#37; for SI model, and 75.56 &#37; for CF model, respectively. According to the results, three models show almost similar results, while SI model performs slightly better than other models and the map produced by SI model represents the most appropriate properties. In addition, the study area was classified into five classes, such as very low, low, moderate, high, and very high. The landslide susceptibility maps can be helpful to select site and mitigate landslide hazards in the study area.
WOS:000371380500002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="78">
<title>GIS techniques for regional-scale landslide susceptibility assessment: the Sicily (Italy) case study</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/13658816.2012.693614</url>
<snippet>This study describes the assessment of landslide susceptibility in Sicily (Italy) at a 1:100,000 scale using a multivariate logistic regression model. The model was implemented in a GIS environment by using the ArcSDM (Arc Spatial Data Modeller) module, modified to develop spatial prediction through regional data sets. A newly developed algorithm was used to automatically extract the detachment area from mapped landslide polygons. The following factors were selected as independent variables of the logistic regression model: slope gradient, lithology, land cover, a curve number derived index and a pluviometric anomaly index. The above-described configuration has been verified to be the best one among others employing from three to eight factors. All the regression coefficients and parameters were calculated using selected landslide training data sets. The results of the analysis were validated using an independent landslide data set. On an average, 82&#37; of the area affected by instability and 79&#37; of the not affected area were correctly classified by the model, which proved to be a useful tool for planners and decision-makers.
WOS:000322213600012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="79">
<title>Groundwater potential mapping at northeastern Wasit and Missan governorates, Iraq using a data-driven weights of evidence technique in framework of GIS</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-015-4097-0</url>
<snippet>In this study, a data-driven weights of evidence (WOE) technique was used to demarcate groundwater potential zones at northeastern Missan and Wasit governorates, Iraq using geographic information system (GIS) platform. In the first step, borehole location inventory map consisting of 143 with relatively high yield (&gt; 8 L/s) was prepared. Then, eight influencing groundwater factors, namely altitude, slope, geology, land use/land cover, distance to roads, distance to faults, aquifer type, and depth of wells were prepared and integrated into spatial database. The spatial association between borehole locations and each influencing groundwater factors were analyzed and discussed. For the analysis of groundwater productivity, the studentised contrast C/S(C) of each groundwater factors were spatially overlaid and weighted summed to produce groundwater potential index (GWPI) map. The resulting map was classified into four categories: low, moderate, high, and very high according to natural break classification scheme. The low GWPI zone covers 30 &#37; (2,215 km(2)). The moderate, high, and very high cover 32 &#37; (2,349 km(2)), 23 &#37; (1,649 km(2)), and 15 &#37; (1,075 km(2)) of the total study area, respectively. The high and very high zones cover approximately 40 &#37; of the study area indicating moderate productivity of the aquifer system in the study area. The results of the analysis were validated using receiver operating characteristic (ROC) technique. The areas under the ROC curve (AUC) for success and prediction rates were 0.81 and 0.80, respectively, indicating the high capability of WOE for modeling groundwater potentiality in the study area. Result of this study could be used as guide to manage aquifers in these areas and serve as indicator for sustainable management of aquifer systems.
WOS:000356871500021
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="80">
<title>Landslide hazard assessment along a mountain highway in the Indian Himalayan Region (IHR) using remote sensing and computational models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1117/12.2029080</url>
<snippet>Landslide hazard assessments using computational models, such as artificial neural network (ANN) and frequency ratio (FR), were carried out covering one of the important mountain highways in the Central Himalaya of Indian Himalayan Region (IHR). Landslide influencing factors were either calculated or extracted from spatial databases including recent remote sensing data of LANDSAT TM, CARTOSAT digital elevation model (DEM) and Tropical Rainfall Measuring Mission (TRMM) satellite for rainfall data. ANN was implemented using the multi-layered feed forward architecture with different input, output and hidden layers. This model based on back propagation algorithm derived weights for all possible parameters of landslides and causative factors considered. The training sites for landslide prone and non-prone areas were identified and verified through details gathered from remote sensing and other sources. Frequency Ratio (FR) models are based on observed relationships between the distribution of landslides and each landslide related factor. FR model implementation proved useful for assessing the spatial relationships between landslide locations and factors contributing to its occurrence. Above computational models generated respective susceptibility maps of landslide hazard for the study area. This further allowed the simulation of landslide hazard maps on a medium scale using GIS platform and remote sensing data. Upon validation and accuracy checks, it was observed that both models produced good results with FR having some edge over ANN based mapping. Such statistical and functional models led to better understanding of relationships between the landslides and preparatory factors as well as ensuring lesser levels of subjectivity compared to qualitative approaches.
WOS:000327619300019
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="81">
<title>A small-scale landslide susceptibility assessment for the territory of Western Carpathians</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-013-0751-6</url>
<snippet>This study presented herein compares the bivariate and multivariate landslide susceptibility mapping methods and presents the landslide susceptibility map of the territory of Western Carpathians in small scale. This study also describes pioneer work for the territory of Western Carpathians, overreaching state borders, using verified sophisticated statistical methods. In the susceptibility mapping, digital elevation model was first constructed using a GIS software, and parameter maps affecting the slope stability such as geology, seismicity, precipitation, topographical elevation, slope angle, slope aspect and land cover were considered. In the last stage of the analyses, landslide susceptibility maps were produced using bivariate and multivariate analyses, and they were then compared by means of their validations. The validation of the bivariate analysis data was performed using the results of bivariate analysis for landslide areas of Slovakia containing five classes of susceptibility in scale 1:500,000. The validation area is the area of Western Carpathians within Slovakia. Eighty-two per cent of area does not differ in more than one class. The validation of the multivariate analysis data was performed using the results from the Kysuce region in the northern part of Slovakia in scale 1:10,000. The raster calculator was used to express the difference between each pair of pixels within these two layers. Seventy-seven per cent of the pixels do not differ in more than 25 &#37;, 94 &#37; of the pixels do not differ in more than 50 &#37;. The maximal possible difference is 100 &#37; (one pixel with value 0 and other with value 1, or vice versa). Receiver operating characteristic analysis was also performed, the area under curve value for bivariate model was calculated to be 0.735, while it was 0.823 for multivariate. The results of the validation can be considered as satisfactory.
WOS:000325101100056
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="82">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping using certainty factor, index of entropy and logistic regression models in GIS and their comparison at Mugling-Narayanghat road section in Nepal Himalaya</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-012-0347-6</url>
<snippet>Landslide susceptibility maps are vital for disaster management and for planning development activities in the mountainous country like Nepal. In the present study, landslide susceptibility assessment of Mugling-Narayanghat road and its surrounding area is made using bivariate (certainty factor and index of entropy) and multivariate (logistic regression) models. At first, a landslide inventory map was prepared using earlier reports and aerial photographs as well as by carrying out field survey. As a result, 321 landslides were mapped and out of which 241 (75 &#37;) were randomly selected for building landslide susceptibility models, while the remaining 80 (25 &#37;) were used for validating the models. The effectiveness of landslide susceptibility assessment using GIS and statistics is based on appropriate selection of the factors which play a dominant role in slope stability. In this case study, the following landslide conditioning factors were evaluated: slope gradient; slope aspect; altitude; plan curvature; lithology; land use; distance from faults, rivers and roads; topographic wetness index; stream power index; and sediment transport index. These factors were prepared from topographic map, drainage map, road map, and the geological map. Finally, the validation of landslide susceptibility map was carried out using receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves. The ROC plot estimation results showed that the susceptibility map using index of entropy model with AUC value of 0.9016 has highest prediction accuracy of 90.16 &#37;. Similarly, the susceptibility maps produced using logistic regression model and certainty factor model showed 86.29 and 83.57 &#37; of prediction accuracy, respectively. Furthermore, the ROC plot showed that the success rate of all the three models performed more than 80 &#37; accuracy (i.e. 89.15 &#37; for IOE model, 89.10 &#37; for LR model and 87.21 &#37; for CF model). Hence, it is concluded that all the models employed in this study showed reasonably good accuracy in predicting the landslide susceptibility of Mugling-Narayanghat road section. These landslide susceptibility maps can be used for preliminary land use planning and hazard mitigation purpose.
WOS:000312087100009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="83">
<title>Landslide susceptibility zonation in Greece</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-012-0381-4</url>
<snippet>The objective of this study is to perform a preliminary national-scale assessment of the landslide susceptibility in Greece using a landslide inventory derived from historical archives. The effects of controlling factors on landslide susceptibility combined with multivariate statistics have been evaluated using GIS aided mapping techniques. Thousand six hundred thirty-five landslide occurrences, mainly earth slides obtained from Public Authorities archives, covering a long time period were recorded and digitally stored using a spatial relational database management system. Ten landslide predisposing factors (predictors) were identified, while digital thematic maps on the spatial distribution of those factors were generated. The correlation between the landslide locations and predictor classes was analyzed by using the Landslide Relative Frequency. R-mode factor analysis was applied to study the interrelations between predictors (independent variables) while weighting coefficients were determined. Landslide susceptibility was derived from an algorithm which modeled the influence of predictors, and a susceptibility map was compiled. The landslide susceptibility map was verified using a data set of 375 new landslide locations. It is the first comprehensive attempt to illustrate the landslide susceptibility in the total country based on the interpretation of historical data only.
WOS:000312087100030
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="84">
<title>A comparative study on the landslide susceptibility mapping using evidential belief function and weights of evidence models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>The purpose of this study is to produce landslide susceptibility map of a landslide-prone area (Daguan County, China) by evidential belief function (EBF) model and weights of evidence (WoE) model to compare the results obtained. For this purpose, a landslide inventory map was constructed mainly based on earlier reports and aerial photographs, as well as, by carrying out field surveys. A total of 194 landslides were mapped. Then, the landslide inventory was randomly split into a training dataset; 70&#37; (136 landslides) for training the models and the remaining 30&#37; (58 landslides) was used for validation purpose. Then, a total number of 14 conditioning factors, such as slope angle, slope aspect, general curvature, plan curvature, profile curvature, altitude, distance from rivers, distance from roads, distance from faults, lithology, normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI), sediment transport index (STI), stream power index (SPI), and topographic wetness index (TWI) were used in the analysis. Subsequently, landslide susceptibility maps were produced using the EBF and WoE models. Finally, the validation of landslide susceptibility map was accomplished with the area under the curve (AUC) method. The success rate curve showed that the area under the curve for EBF and WoE models were of 80.19&#37; and 80.75&#37; accuracy, respectively. Similarly, the validation result showed that the susceptibility map using EBF model has the prediction accuracy of 80.09&#37;, while for WoE model, it was 79.79&#37;. The results of this study showed that both landslide susceptibility maps obtained were successful and would be useful for regional spatial planning as well as for land cover planning.
WOS:000375930100013
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="85">
<title>Landfire hazard assessment in the Caspian Hyrcanian forest ecoregion with the long-term MODIS active fire data</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-017-2850-2</url>
<snippet>Relatively little is known about the causes of landfire assembly in Golestan Province that are subject to environmental and anthropogenic factors. The present study investigated how the landfire hazard is influenced by the environmental and anthropogenic parameters in the fire-prone Hyrcanian forest. The MODIS hotspot data of the past 15 years were collected and analyzed in Golestan Province. The frequencies and distributions of landfires were investigated with 13 environmental and anthropogenic factors selected to construct landfire hazard maps by BLR and ANN methods. The comparison between MODIS active fire detections collected between 2000 and 2015 of the Golestan Province and landfire hazard areas, as predicted by the BLR and ANN, showed satisfactory results for ANN. The results of this study confirmed that anthropogenic variables were important predictors of landfire hazard and showed nonlinear relationships. Vegetation moisture, climate, and topography were also significant variables in the study area.
WOS:000403040000030
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="86">
<title>GIS-based landslide susceptibility mapping with probabilistic likelihood ratio and spatial multi-criteria evaluation models (North of Tehran, Iran)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-012-0825-x</url>
<snippet>The aim of this study is to produce landslide susceptibility mapping by probabilistic likelihood ratio (PLR) and spatial multi-criteria evaluation (SMCE) models based on geographic information system (GIS) in the north of Tehran metropolitan, Iran. The landslide locations in the study area were identified by interpretation of aerial photographs, satellite images, and field surveys. In order to generate the necessary factors for the SMCE approach, remote sensing and GIS integrated techniques were applied in the study area. Conditioning factors such as slope degree, slope aspect, altitude, plan curvature, profile curvature, surface area ratio, topographic position index, topographic wetness index, stream power index, slope length, lithology, land use, normalized difference vegetation index, distance from faults, distance from rivers, distance from roads, and drainage density are used for landslide susceptibility mapping. Of 528 landslide locations, 70 &#37; were used in landslide susceptibility mapping, and the remaining 30 &#37; were used for validation of the maps. Using the above conditioning factors, landslide susceptibility was calculated using SMCE and PLR models, and the results were plotted in ILWIS-GIS. Finally, the two landslide susceptibility maps were validated using receiver operating characteristic curves and seed cell area index methods. The validation results showed that area under the curve for SMCE and PLR models is 76.16 and 80.98 &#37;, respectively. The results obtained in this study also showed that the probabilistic likelihood ratio model performed slightly better than the spatial multi-criteria evaluation. These landslide susceptibility maps can be used for preliminary land use planning and hazard mitigation purpose.
WOS:000334686100015
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="87">
<title>An integrated artificial neural network model for the landslide susceptibility assessment of Osado Island, Japan</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-015-1799-2</url>
<snippet>The objective of this study was to select the maximum number of correlated factors with landslide occurrence for slope-instability mapping and assess landslide susceptibility on Osado Island, Niigata Prefecture, Central Japan, integrating two techniques, namely certainty factor (CF) and artificial neural network (ANN), in a geographic information system (GIS) environment. The landslide inventory data of the National Research Institute for Earth Science and Disaster Prevention (NIED) and a 10-m digital elevation model (DEM) from the Geographical Survey of Institute, Japan, were analyzed. Our study identified fourteen possible landslide-conditioning factors. Considering the spatial autocorrelation and factor redundancy, we applied the CF approach to optimize these set of variables. We hypothesize that if the thematic factor layers of the CF values are positive, it implies that these conditioning factors have a correlation with the landslide occurrence. Therefore, based on this assumption and because of their positive CF values, six conditioning factors including slope angle (0.04), slope aspect (0.02), drainage density network (0.34), distance to the geologic boundaries (0.37), distance to fault (0.35), and lithology (0.31) have been selected as landslide-conditioning factors for further analysis. We partitioned the data into two groups: 70 &#37; (520 landslide locations) for model training and the remaining 30 &#37; (220 landslide locations) for validation. Then, a common ANN model, namely the back-propagation neural network (BPNN), was employed to produce the landslide susceptibility maps. The receiver operating characteristics including the area under the curve (AUC) were used to assess the model accuracy. The validation results indicate that the values of the AUC at optimized and non-optimized BPNN were 0.82 and 0.73, respectively. Hence, it is concluded that the optimized factor model can provide superior accuracy in the prediction of landslide susceptibility in the study area. In this context, we propose a method to select the factors with landslide occurrence. This work is fundamental for further study of the landslide susceptibility evaluation and prediction.
WOS:000358410300015
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="88">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping using support vector machine and GIS at the Golestan Province, Iran</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12040-013-0282-2</url>
<snippet>The main goal of this study is to produce landslide susceptibility map using GIS-based support vector machine (SVM) at Kalaleh Township area of the Golestan province, Iran. In this paper, six different types of kernel classifiers such as linear, polynomial degree of 2, polynomial degree of 3, polynomial degree of 4, radial basis function (RBF) and sigmoid were used for landslide susceptibility mapping. At the first stage of the study, landslide locations were identified by aerial photographs and field surveys, and a total of 82 landslide locations were extracted from various sources. Of this, 75&#37; of the landslides (61 landslide locations) are used as training dataset and the rest was used as (21 landslide locations) the validation dataset. Fourteen input data layers were employed as landslide conditioning factors in the landslide susceptibility modelling. These factors are slope degree, slope aspect, altitude, plan curvature, profile curvature, tangential curvature, surface area ratio (SAR), lithology, land use, distance from faults, distance from rivers, distance from roads, topographic wetness index (TWI) and stream power index (SPI). Using these conditioning factors, landslide susceptibility indices were calculated using support vector machine by employing six types of kernel function classifiers. Subsequently, the results were plotted in ArcGIS and six landslide susceptibility maps were produced. Then, using the success rate and the prediction rate methods, the validation process was performed by comparing the existing landslide data with the six landslide susceptibility maps. The validation results showed that success rates for six types of kernel models varied from 79&#37; to 87&#37;. Similarly, results of prediction rates showed that RBF (85&#37;) and polynomial degree of 3 (83&#37;) models performed slightly better than other types of kernel (polynomial degree of 2 = 78&#37;, sigmoid = 78&#37;, polynomial degree of 4 = 78&#37;, and linear = 77&#37;) models. Based on our results, the differences in the rates (success and prediction) of the six models are not really significant. So, the produced susceptibility maps will be useful for general land-use planning.
WOS:000317606500007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="89">
<title>Flood susceptibility analysis and its verification using a novel ensemble support vector machine and frequency ratio method</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00477-015-1021-9</url>
<snippet>Flood is one of the most commonly occurred natural hazards worldwide. Severe flood occurrences in Kelantan, Malaysia cause damage to both life and property every year. Due to the huge losses in this area, development of appropriate flood modeling is required for the government. Remote sensing and geographic information system techniques can support overall flood management as they can produce rapid data collection and analysis for hydrological studies. The existing models for flood mapping have some weak points that may improve through more sophisticated and ensemble methods. The current research aimed to propose a novel ensemble method by integrating support vector machine (SVM) and frequency ratio (FR) to produce spatial modeling in flood susceptibility assessment. In the literature, mostly statistical and machine learning methods are used individually; however, their integration can enhance the final output. The FR model can perform bivariate statistical analysis and evaluate the correlation between the flooding and classes of each conditioning factors. The weights achieved by FR can be assigned to each conditioning factor and the resulted factors can be used in SVM analysis. In order to examine the efficiency of the proposed ensemble method and to show the proficiency of SVM, another machine learning algorithm such as decision tree (DT) was applied and the results were compared. To perform the methods, the upper catchment of the Kelantan basin in Malaysia was chosen. First, a flood inventory map with a total of 155 flood locations were extracted from various sources over the study area. The flood inventory map was randomly divided into two dataset; 70 &#37; (115 flood locations) for the purpose of training and the remaining 30 &#37; (40 flood locations) was used for validation. The spatial database included digital elevation model, curvature, geology, river, stream power index, rainfall, land use/cover, soil type, topographic wetness index and slope. For model validation, area under curve method was used and both success and prediction rate curves were calculated. The validation results for ensemble method showed 88.71 and 85.21 &#37; for success rate and prediction rate respectively. The DT model showed 87.00 and 82.00 &#37; for the success rate and prediction rate respectively. It is evident that the accuracies were increased using the ensemble method. The acquired results proved the efficiency of the proposed ensemble method as rapid, accurate and reasonable in flood susceptibility assessment.
WOS:000353516400006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="90">
<title>A Combination of Geographically Weighted Regression, Particle Swarm Optimization and Support Vector Machine for Landslide Susceptibility Mapping: A Case Study at Wanzhou in the Three Gorges Area, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijerph13050487</url>
<snippet>In this study, a novel coupling model for landslide susceptibility mapping is presented. In practice, environmental factors may have different impacts at a local scale in study areas. To provide better predictions, a geographically weighted regression (GWR) technique is firstly used in our method to segment study areas into a series of prediction regions with appropriate sizes. Meanwhile, a support vector machine (SVM) classifier is exploited in each prediction region for landslide susceptibility mapping. To further improve the prediction performance, the particle swarm optimization (PSO) algorithm is used in the prediction regions to obtain optimal parameters for the SVM classifier. To evaluate the prediction performance of our model, several SVM-based prediction models are utilized for comparison on a study area of the Wanzhou district in the Three Gorges Reservoir. Experimental results, based on three objective quantitative measures and visual qualitative evaluation, indicate that our model can achieve better prediction accuracies and is more effective for landslide susceptibility mapping. For instance, our model can achieve an overall prediction accuracy of 91.10&#37;, which is 7.8&#37;-19.1&#37; higher than the traditional SVM-based models. In addition, the obtained landslide susceptibility map by our model can demonstrate an intensive correlation between the classified very high-susceptibility zone and the previously investigated landslides.
WOS:000377256900044
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="91">
<title>Landslide zoning over large areas from a sample inventory by means of scale-dependent terrain units</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2012.10.026</url>
<snippet>A procedure is proposed to produce landslide distribution zoning maps to be considered preparatory to susceptibility, hazard and risk zoning maps, based on 1) the results from a statistical multivariate analysis of a landslide inventory, which must be available for only a portion of the territory to be zoned, and 2) the use of appropriately defined terrain mapping units. The units are divided into terrain computational units (TCUs) and terrain zoning units (TZUs), whose size is related to the scale of zoning. The procedure comprises three phases: calibration, validation and prediction. The purpose of the prediction phase is the application of a calibrated and validated statistical model in a territory, previously recognized as viable on the basis of a-priori applicability maps, for which no information is available regarding the distribution of landslides or where the information provided by the landslides inventory is unreliable or heterogeneous. The proposed procedure is applied to two case studies in southern Italy for the analysis and zoning of slow-moving landslides at 1:25,000 and 1:100,000 scales, respectively. The first case study illustrates the applicability of the procedure. The aim of the second case study is to address the part of the procedure related to the evaluation of the computational maps at the end of the calibration and validation phases. (C) 2012 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000314328800003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="92">
<title>Integration of genetic algorithm and multiple kernel support vector regression for modeling urban growth</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compenvurbsys.2017.04.011</url>
<snippet>There are two main issues of concern for land change scientists to consider. First, selecting appropriate and independent land cover change (LCC) drivers is a substantial challenge because these drivers usually correlate with each other. For this reason, we used a well-known machine learning tool called genetic algorithm (GA) to select the optimum LCC drivers. In addition, using the best or most appropriate LCC model is critical since some of them are limited to a specific function, to discover non-linear patterns within land use data. In this study, a support vector regression (SVR) was implemented to model LCC as SVRs use Various linear and non-linear kernels to better identify non-linear patterns within land use data. With such an approach, choosing the appropriate kernels to model LCC is critical because SVR kernels have a direct impact on the accuracy of the model. Therefore, various linear and non-linear kernels, including radial basis function (RBF), sigmoid (SIG), polynomial (PL) and linear (LN) kernels, were used across two phases: 1) in combination with GA, and 2) without GA present. The simulated maps resulting from each combination were evaluated using a recently modified version of the receiver operating characteristics (ROC) tool called the total operating characteristic (TOC) tool. The proposed approach was applied to simulate urban growth in Rasht County, which is located in the north of Iran. As a result, an SVR-GA-RBF model achieved the highest area under curve (AUC) value at 94&#37; while the lowest AUC was achieved when using the SVR-LN model at 71&#37;. The results show that the synergy between GA and SVR can effectively optimize the variables selection process used when developing an LCC model, and can enhance the predictive accuracy of SVR. (C) 2017 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000408300700003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="93">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping using analytic hierarchy process and information value methods along a highway road section in Constantine, Algeria</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-017-2980-6</url>
<snippet>This research work deals with the landslide susceptibility assessment using Analytic hierarchy process (AHP) and information value (IV) methods along a highway road section in Constantine region, NE Algeria. The landslide inventory map which has a total of 29 single landslide locations was created based on historical information, aerial photo interpretation, remote sensing images, and extensive field surveys. The different landslide influencing geoenvironmental factors considered for this study are lithology, slope gradient, slope aspect, distance from faults, land use, distance from streams, and geotechnical parameters. A thematic layer map is generated for every geoenvironmental factor using Geographic Information System (GIS); the lithological units and the distance from faults maps were extracted from the geological database of the region. The slope gradient, slope aspect, and distance from streams were calculated from the Digital Elevation Model (DEM). Contemporary land use map was derived from satellite images and field study. Concerning the geotechnical parameters maps, they were determined making use of the geotechnical data from laboratory tests. The analysis of the relationships between the landslide-related factors and the landslide events was then carried out in GIS environment. The AUC plot showed that the susceptibility maps had a success rate of 77 and 66&#37; for IV and AHP models, respectively. For that purpose, the IV model is better in predicting the occurrence of landslides than AHP one. Therefore, the information value method could be used as a landslide susceptibility mapping zonation method along other sections of the A1 highway.
WOS:000400266200010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="94">
<title>Evaluation of different machine learning models for predicting and mapping the susceptibility of gully erosion</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2017.09.006</url>
<snippet>Gully erosion constitutes a serious problem for land degradation in a wide range of environments. The main objective of this research was to compare the performance of seven state-of-the-art machine learning models (SVM with four kernel types, BP-ANN, RF, and BRT) to model the occurrence of gully erosion in the Kashkan-Poldokhtar Watershed, Iran. In the first step, a gully inventory map consisting of 65 gully polygons was prepared through field surveys. Three different sample data sets (S1, S2, and S3), including both positive and negative cells (70&#37; for training and 30&#37; for validation), were randomly prepared to evaluate the robustness of the models. To model the gully erosion susceptibility, 12 geo-environmental factors were selected as predictors. Finally, the goodness-of-fit and prediction skill of the models were evaluated by different criteria, including efficiency percent, kappa coefficient, and the area under the ROC curves (AUC). In terms of accuracy, the RF, RBF-SVM, BRT, and P-SVM models performed excellently both in the degree of fitting and in predictive performance (AUC values well above 0.9), which resulted in accurate predictions. Therefore, these models can be used in other gully erosion studies, as they are capable of rapidly producing accurate and robust gully erosion susceptibility maps (GESMs) for decision-making and soil and water management practices. Furthermore, it was found that performance of RF and RBF-SVM for modelling gully erosion occurrence is quite stable when the learning and validation samples are changed. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000415771900009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="95">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping using rough sets and back-propagation neural networks in the Three Gorges, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-013-2217-2</url>
<snippet>In the Three Gorges of China, there are frequent landslides, and the potential risk of landslides is tremendous. An efficient and accurate method of generating landslide susceptibility maps is very important to mitigate the loss of lives and properties caused by these landslides. This paper presents landslide susceptibility mapping on the Zigui-Badong of the Three Gorges, using rough sets and back-propagation neural networks (BPNNs). Landslide locations were obtained from a landslide inventory map, supported by field surveys. Twenty-two landslide-related factors were extracted from the 1:10,000-scale topographic maps, 1:50,000-scale geological maps, Landsat ETM + satellite images with a spatial resolution of 28.5 m, and HJ-A satellite images with a spatial resolution of 30 m. Twelve key environmental factors were selected as independent variables using the rough set and correlation coefficient analysis, including elevation, slope, profile curvature, catchment aspect, catchment height, distance from drainage, engineering rock group, distance from faults, slope structure, land cover, topographic wetness index, and normalized difference vegetation index. The initial, three-layered, and four-layered BPNN were trained and then used to map landslide susceptibility, respectively. To evaluate the models, the susceptibility maps were validated by comparing with the existing landslide locations according to the area under the curve. The four-layered BPNN outperforms the other two models with the best accuracy of 91.53 &#37;. Approximately 91.37 &#37; of landslides were classified as high and very high landslide-prone areas. The validation results show sufficient agreement between the obtained susceptibility maps and the existing landslide locations.
WOS:000324252900026
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="96">
<title>Spatial prediction of rainfall-induced landslides for the Lao Cai area (Vietnam) using a hybrid intelligent approach of least squares support vector machines inference model and artificial bee colony optimization</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10346-016-0711-9</url>
<snippet>The main objective of this study is to produce a landslide susceptibility map for the Lao Cai area (Vietnam) using a new hybrid intelligent method based on least squares support vector machines (LSSVM) and artificial bee colony (ABC) optimization, namely LSSVM-BC. LSSVM and ABC are state-of-the-art soft computing techniques that have been rarely utilized in landslide susceptibility assessment. LSSVM is adopted to develop landslide prediction model whereas ABC was used to optimize the prediction model by identifying an appropriate set of the LSSVM hyper-parameters. To establish the hybrid intelligent method, a GIS database with ten landslide-influencing factors and 340 landslide locations that occurred mainly during the last 20-years was constructed. These historical landslide locations were collected from the existing inventories that sourced from (i) five landslide projects carried out in this study areas before and (ii) interpretations of SPOT satellite images with resolution of 2.5 m. The study area was geographically split into two different parts, with landslides located in the first part was used for building models whereas the other landslides in the second part was used for the model validation. Performance of the LSSVM-BC model was assessed using the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve and area under the curve (AUC). Result shows that the prediction power of the model is good with the area under the curve (AUC) = 0.900. Experiments have pointed out the prediction power of the LSSVM-BC is better than that obtained from the popular support vector machines. Therefore, the proposed model is a promising tool for spatial prediction of landslides at the study area. The landslide susceptibility map is useful for landuse planning for the Lao Cai area.
WOS:000398889900001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="97">
<title>Strategies investigation in using artificial neural network for landslide susceptibility mapping: application to a Sicilian catchment</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.2166/hydro.2013.191</url>
<snippet>Susceptibility assessment of areas prone to landsliding remains one of the most useful approaches in landslide hazard analysis. The key point of such analysis is the correlation between the physical phenomenon and its triggering factors based on past observations. Many methods have been developed in the scientific literature to capture and model this correlation, usually within a geographic information system (GIS) framework. Among these, the use of neural networks, in particular the multi-layer perceptron (MLP) networks, has provided successful results. A successful application of the MLP method to a basin area requires the definition of different model strategies, such as the sample selection for the training phase or the design of the network structure. The present study investigates the effects of these strategies on the development of landslide susceptibility maps by applying different model configurations to a small basin located in northeastern Sicily (Italy), where a number of historical slope failure events have been documented over the years. Model performances and their comparison are evaluated using specific metrics.
WOS:000333684400018
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="98">
<title>Spatial Prediction of Landslide Hazard at the Yihuang Area (China): A Comparative Study on the Predictive Ability of Backpropagation Multi-layer Perceptron Neural Networks and Radial Basic Function Neural Networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-17738-0_13</url>
<snippet>The aim of this study is to investigate potential applications of multi-layer perceptron neural networks (MLP Neural Nets) and radial basis function neural networks (RBF Neural Nets) for landslide susceptibility mapping in the Yihuang area (China). First, a landslide inventory map with 187 landslide locations was generated, and then the map was randomly partitioned into a ratio of 70/30 for training and validating models. Second, 14 landslide conditioning factors (slope, altitude, aspect, topographic wetness, sediment transport index (STI), stream power index (SPI), plan curvature, distance to rivers, distance to faults, distance to roads, land use, normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI), lithology, rainfall) were prepared. Using MLP Neural Nets and RBF Neural Nets, two landslide susceptibility models were constructed and two landslide susceptibility maps were generated. Finally, the two resulting landslide susceptibility maps were validated using the landslide locations and the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) method. The validation results showed that the areas under the ROC curve (AUC) for the two landslide models produced by MLP Neural Nets and RBF Neural Nets are 0.932 and 0.765 for success rate curve and 0.757 and 0.725 for prediction rate curve, respectively. The results showed that the MLP Neural Nets model is better than the RBF Neural Nets model in this study. The results may be useful for general land use planning and hazard mitigation purposes.
WOS:000390822000013
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="99">
<title>Mapping landslide susceptibility with frequency ratio, statistical index, and weights of evidence models: a case study in northern Iran</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-017-6839-7</url>
<snippet>The main objective of this study is to investigate potential application of frequency ratio (FR), weights of evidence (WoE), and statistical index (SI) models for landslide susceptibility mapping in a part of Mazandaran Province, Iran. First, a landslide inventory map was constructed from various sources. The landslide inventory map was then randomly divided in a ratio of 70/30 for training and validation of the models, respectively. Second, 13 landslide conditioning factors including slope degree, slope aspect, altitude, plan curvature, stream power index, topographic wetness index, sediment transport index, topographic roughness index, lithology, distance from streams, faults, roads, and land use type were prepared, and the relationships between these factors and the landslide inventory map were extracted by using the mentioned models. Subsequently, the multi-class weighted factors were used to generate landslide susceptibility maps. Finally, the susceptibility maps were verified and compared using several methods including receiver operating characteristic curve with the areas under the curve (AUC), landslide density, and spatially agreed area analyses. The success rate curve showed that the AUC for FR, WoE, and SI models was 81.51, 79.43, and 81.27, respectively. The prediction rate curve demonstrated that the AUC achieved by the three models was 80.44, 77.94, and 79.55, respectively. Although the sensitivity analysis using the FR model revealed that the modeling process was sensitive to input factors, the accuracy results suggest that the three models used in this study can be effective approaches for landslide susceptibility mapping in Mazandaran Province, and the resultant susceptibility maps are trustworthy for hazard mitigation strategies.
WOS:000406241000032
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="100">
<title>Spatial model integration for shallow landslide susceptibility and its runout using a GIS-based approach in Yongin, Korea</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10106049.2016.1155658</url>
<snippet>Rainfall-triggered shallow landslide is very common in Korean mountains and the socioeconomic impact is much higher than in the past due to population pressure in hazardous zones. Present study is an attempt toward the development of a methodology for the integration of shallow landslide susceptibility zones and runout zones that could be reached by mobilized mass. Landslide occurrence areas in Yongin were determined based on the interpretation of aerial photographs and extensive field surveys. Nineteen landslide-related factors maps were collected and analysed in geographic information system environment. Among 109 identified landslides, about 85&#37; randomly selected training landslide data from inventory map was used to generate an evidential belief function model and remaining 15&#37; landslides were used to validate the shallow landslide susceptibility map. The resulting susceptibility map had a success rate of 89.2&#37; and a predictive accuracy of 92.1&#37;. A runout propagation from high susceptible area was obtained from the modified multiple-flow direction algorithm. A matrix was used to integrate the shallow landslide susceptibility classes and the runout probable zone. Thus, each pixel had a susceptibility class in relation to its failure probability and runout susceptibility class. The study of landslide potential and its propagation can be used to obtain a spatial prediction for landslides, which could contribute to landslide risk mitigation.
WOS:000395143900005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="101">
<title>Flood susceptibility assessment using GIS-based support vector machine model with different kernel types</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.catena.2014.10.017</url>
<snippet>Statistical learning theory is the basis of support vector machine (SVM) technique. This technique in natural hazard assessment is getting extremely popular these days. It contains a training stage related to the input and desire output values. The main goal of this paper is to assess and evaluate the prediction capability of SVM technique with different kernel functions for spatial prediction of flood occurrence. Kuala Terengganu basin, Malaysia was selected as study area. To begin, a flood inventory map was produced by mapping the flood locations in the Terengganu using documentary sources and field survey. The flood inventory was partitioned into training and testing datasets through random selection. The spatial database was constructed using various flood conditioning factors: altitude, slope, curvature, stream power index (SPI), topographic wetness index (TWI), distance from the river, geology, land use/cover (LULC), soil, and surface runoff. Four SVM kernel types such as linear (LN), polynomial (PL), radial basis function (RBF), and sigmoid (SIG) were utilized to check the robustness of the SVM model. Consequently, four flood susceptibility maps were created. In order to examine the efficiency of the SVM model, a probabilistic based frequency ratio (FR) model was applied and compared with the SVM outcomes. An area under the curve (AUC) method was used to validate the resultant flood susceptibility maps. The validation results demonstrated that the prediction rate curves for flood susceptibility maps generated by the SVM-LN, SVM-PL, SVM-RBF, and SVM-SIG were 84.63&#37;, 83.92&#37;, 84.97&#37;, and 81.88&#37; respectively. On the other hand, the prediction rate achieved by FR showed the lowest accuracy of 61.43&#37;. To evaluate the impacts of conditioning factors on the flood susceptibility mapping, Cohens kappa index was measured. The result demonstrated that all conditioning factors have reasonably positive influence on the flood analysis in current case study except surface runoff which decreased the accuracy of the final results. The most influential factors were altitude and slope for all kernel types. It can be concluded that SVM technique is an efficient and reliable tool in flood susceptibility assessment. The resultant flood susceptibility maps can be beneficial in flood mitigation strategies. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000346398600009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="102">
<title>A comparative study of landslide susceptibility mapping using landslide susceptibility index and artificial neural networks in the Krios River and Krathis River catchments (northern Peloponnesus, Greece)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10064-014-0607-7</url>
<snippet>The main scope of this study is to compare the performance of a conventional statistical method like the landslide susceptibility index (LSI) and a soft computing method like artificial neural networks (ANNs). These models were applied in order to realistically map landslide susceptibility (LS) in the Krathis and Krios drainage basins in northern Peloponnesus. The relationship between landslides and various conditioning factors contributing to their occurrence was investigated through geographic information system-based analysis. A landslide inventory was realised using aerial-photos, satellite images and field surveys. Eight conditioning factors, including land cover, geology, elevation, slope, aspect, distance to road network, distance to drainage network, distance to structural elements, were considered. Subsequently, LS maps were produced using LSI and ANNs, and they were then compared and validated accordingly. Model performance was checked by an independent validation set of landslide events. For the validation process, the receiver operating curve was drawn and the area-under-the-curve (AUC) values were calculated. The calculated AUC values were 0.852 for the LSI model, and 0.842 for the ANNs; thus, both methods seem to lead to quite similar results. Based on these results, with an average percentage of correctly predicting landslides of about 84 &#37;, model validation confirms that extrapolation results are very good, and that both models can be used to mitigate hazards related to landslides, and to aid in generalised land-use planning assessment purposes.
WOS:000348300600003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="103">
<title>Determination of importance for comprehensive topographic factors on landslide hazard mapping using artificial neural network</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-013-3003-x</url>
<snippet>A landslide is one of the natural disasters that occur in Malaysia. In addition to the geological factor and the rain as triggering factor, topographic factors such as elevation, slope angle, slope aspect, and curvature are considered as the main causes of landslides. The study in this paper was conducted in three stages. The first stage involved the extraction of extra topographic factors. Previous landslide studies had identified only four of the topographic factors. However, eight new additional factors have also been identified in this study. They are general curvature, longitudinal curvature, tangential curvature, cross-section curvature, surface area, diagonal line length, surface roughness, and rugosity. At this stage, 13 factors were extracted from the digital elevation model. The second stage involved specifying the importance of each factor. The multilayer perceptron network and backpropagation algorithm were used to specify the weight of each factor. Results were verified using the receiver operating characteristics based on the area under the curve method in the third stage. The results indicated 76.07 &#37; accuracy in predicting of landslides, with slope angle as the most important factor while the tangential curvature has the least importance.
WOS:000339376300013
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="104">
<title>Assessment of Landslide-Prone Areas and Their Zonation Using Logistic Regression, LogitBoost, and NaiveBayes Machine-Learning Algorithms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/su10103697</url>
<snippet>The occurrence of landslide in the hilly region of South Korea is a matter of serious concern. This study tries to produce landslide susceptibility maps for Jumunjin Country in South Korea. Three machine learning algorithms, namely Logistic Regression (LR), LogitBoost (LB), and NaiveBayes (NB) are used, and their final model outcomes are compared to each other. Firstly, a landslide inventory map and the associated input data layers of the landslide conditioning factors were developed based on field verification, historical records, and high-resolution remote-sensing data in the geographic information system (GIS) environment. Seventeen landslide conditioning factors were prepared, including aspect, slope, altitude, maximum curvature, profile curvature, topographic wetness index (TWI), topographic positioning index (TPI), distance from fault, convexity, forest type, forest diameter, forest density, land use/land cover, lithology, soil, flow accumulation, and mid slope position. The result showed that the area under the curve (AUC) values of LR, LB, and NB models were 84.2&#37;, 70.7&#37;, and 85.2&#37;, respectively. The results revealed that the LR and LB models produced reasonable accuracy than respect to NB model in landslide susceptibility assessment. The final susceptibility maps would be useful for preliminary land-use planning and hazard mitigation purpose.
WOS:000448559400339
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="105">
<title>Comparative Assessment of Three Nonlinear Approaches for Landslide Susceptibility Mapping in a Coal Mine Area</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijgi6070228</url>
<snippet>Landslide susceptibility mapping is the first and most important step involved in landslide hazard assessment. The purpose of the present study is to compare three nonlinear approaches for landslide susceptibility mapping and test whether coal mining has a significant impact on landslide occurrence in coal mine areas. Landslide data collected by the Bureau of Land and Resources are represented by the X, Y coordinates of its central point; causative factors were calculated from topographic and geologic maps, as well as satellite imagery. The five-fold cross-validation method was adopted and the landslide/non-landslide datasets were randomly split into a ratio of 80:20. From this, five subsets for 20 times were acquired for training and validating models by GIS Geostatistical analysis methods, and all of the subsets were employed in a spatially balanced sample design. Three landslide models were built using support vector machine (SVM), logistic regression (LR), and artificial neural network (ANN) models by selecting the median of the performance measures. Then, the three fitted models were compared using the area under the receiver operating characteristics (ROC) curves (AUC) and the performance measures. The results show that the prediction accuracies are between 73.43&#37; and 87.45&#37; in the training stage, and 67.16&#37; to 73.13&#37; in the validating stage for the three models. AUCs vary from 0.807 to 0.906 and 0.753 to 0.944 in the two stages, respectively. Additionally, three landslide susceptibility maps were obtained by classifying the range of landslide probabilities into four classes representing low (0-0.02), medium (0.02-0.1), high (0.1-0.85), and very high (0.85-1) probabilities of landslides. For the distributions of landslide and area percentages under different susceptibility standards, the SVM model has more relative balance in the four classes compared to the LR and the ANN models. The result reveals that the SVM model possesses better prediction efficiency than the other two models. Furthermore, the five factors, including lithology, distance from the road, slope angle, elevation, and land-use types, are the most suitable conditioning factors for landslide susceptibility mapping in the study area. The mining disturbance factor has little contribution to all models, because the mining method in this area is underground mining, so the mining depth is too deep to affect the stability of the slopes.
WOS:000407506900045
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="106">
<title>Developing a Dynamic Web-GIS Based Landslide Early Warning System for the Chittagong Metropolitan Area, Bangladesh</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijgi7120485</url>
<snippet>This article aims to develop a Web-GIS based landslide early warning system (EWS) for the Chittagong Metropolitan Area (CMA), Bangladesh, where, in recent years, rainfall-induced landslides have caused great losses of lives and property. A method for combining static landslide susceptibility maps and rainfall thresholds is proposed by introducing a purposely-build hazard matrix. To begin with, eleven factor maps: soil permeability; surface geology; landcover; altitude; slope; aspect; distance to stream; fault line; hill cut; road cut; and drainage network along with a detailed landslide inventory map were produced. These maps were used, and four methods were applied: artificial neural network (ANN); multiple regressions; principal component analysis; and support vector machine to produce landslide susceptibility maps. After model validation, the ANN map was found best fitting and was classified into never warning, low, medium, and high susceptibility zones. Rainfall threshold analysis (1960-2017) revealed consecutive 5-day periods of rainfall of 71-282 mm could initiate landslides in CMA. Later, the threshold was classified into three rainfall rates: low rainfall (70-160 mm), medium rainfall (161-250 mm), and high rainfall (&gt;250 mm). Each landslide was associated with a hazard class (no warning vs. warning state) based on the assumption that the higher the susceptibility, the lower the rainfall. Finally, the EWS was developed using various libraries and frameworks that is connected with a reliable online-based weather application programming interface. The system is publicly available, dynamic, and replicable to similar contexts and is able to disseminate alerts five days in advance via email notifications. The proposed EWS is novel and the first of its kind in Bangladesh, and can be applied to mitigate landslide disaster risks.
WOS:000455392100033
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="107">
<title>Land subsidence susceptibility mapping at Kinta Valley (Malaysia) using the evidential belief function model in GIS</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-014-1128-1</url>
<snippet>Land subsidence is one of the frequent geological hazards worldwide. Urban areas and agricultural industries are the entities most affected by the consequences of land subsidence. The main objective of this study was to estimate the land subsidence (sinkhole) hazards at the Kinta Valley of Perak, Malaysia, using geographic information system and remote sensing techniques. To start, land subsidence locations were observed by surveying measurements using GPS and using the tabular data, which were produced as coordinates of each sinkhole incident. Various land subsidence conditioning factors were used such as altitude, slope, aspect, lithology, distance from the fault, distance from the river, normalized difference vegetation index, soil type, stream power index, topographic wetness index, and land use/cover. In this article, a data-driven technique of an evidential belief function (EBF), which is in the category of multivariate statistical analysis, was used to map the land subsidence-prone areas. The frequency ratio (FR) was performed as an efficient bivariate statistical analysis method in order compare it with the acquired results from the EBF analysis. The probability maps were acquired and the results of the analysis validated by the area under the (ROC) curve using the testing land subsidence locations. The results indicated that the FR model could produce a 71.16 &#37; prediction rate, while the EBF showed better prediction accuracy with a rate of 73.63 &#37;. Furthermore, the success rate was measured and accuracies of 75.30 and 79.45 &#37; achieved for FR and EBF, respectively. These results can produce an understanding of the nature of land subsidence as well as promulgate public awareness of such geo-hazards to decrease human and economic losses.
WOS:000340490100048
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="108">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping using GIS-based multi-criteria decision analysis, support vector machines, and logistic regression</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10346-013-0391-7</url>
<snippet>Identification of landslides and production of landslide susceptibility maps are crucial steps that can help planners, local administrations, and decision makers in disaster planning. Accuracy of the landslide susceptibility maps is important for reducing the losses of life and property. Models used for landslide susceptibility mapping require a combination of various factors describing features of the terrain and meteorological conditions. Many algorithms have been developed and applied in the literature to increase the accuracy of landslide susceptibility maps. In recent years, geographic information system-based multi-criteria decision analyses (MCDA) and support vector regression (SVR) have been successfully applied in the production of landslide susceptibility maps. In this study, the MCDA and SVR methods were employed to assess the shallow landslide susceptibility of Trabzon province (NE Turkey) using lithology, slope, land cover, aspect, topographic wetness index, drainage density, slope length, elevation, and distance to road as input data. Performances of the methods were compared with that of widely used logistic regression model using ROC and success rate curves. Results showed that the MCDA and SVR outperformed the conventional logistic regression method in the mapping of shallow landslides. Therefore, multi-criteria decision method and support vector regression were employed to determine potential landslide zones in the study area.
WOS:000337061000008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="109">
<title>Comparison of Landslides Susceptibility Analysis using AHP, SMCE and GIS for Nilgiris district, India</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>In this study first locations of past occurrence were identified and an inventory form were created and integrated to GIS to derive landslide inventory map predictors. Secondly predictors causing landslides were identified from report of past landslides. Thirdly thematic maps of the identified predictors namely geomorphology, geology, drainage, rainfall, lineament, road, railway, soil, land use/land cover, slope and aspect were derived using Geographical Information System (GIS). Finally based on relative importance of factors and their categories influencing landslide susceptibility weights and ratings of predictors were calculated using two multi criteria approaches namely Analytical Hierarchy processes (AHP) and Spatial Multi Criteria Evaluation (SMCE). Weights and rating obtained for factors and predictors were overlayed using weighted overlay tool of GIS software to generate LS map with classified five zones namely very low, low, moderate, high and very high. Using field check and Receiver Operating Curve (ROC) the LS map were validated, using validate location set Area Under the Curve (AUC) AHP of 95.98&#37; and SMCE of 98.86&#37; were determined.
WOS:000406894400023
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="110">
<title>Remote sensing and GIS-based landslide susceptibility mapping using frequency ratio, logistic regression, and fuzzy logic methods at the central Zab basin, Iran</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-015-4028-0</url>
<snippet>A remote sensing and geographic information system-based study has been carried out to map areas susceptible to landslides using three statistical models, frequency ratio (FR), logistic regression (LR), and fuzzy logic at the central Zab basin in the mountainsides in the southwest West Azerbaijan province in Iran. Ten factors such as slope, aspect, elevation, lithology, normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI), land cover, precipitation, distance to fault, distance to drainage, and distance to road were considered. Landsat ETM+ images were used for NDVI and land cover maps. A landslide inventory map of the study area was identified by a SPOT 5 satellite after which fuzzy algebraic operators were applied to the fuzzy membership values of landslide susceptibility mapping. In addition, FR and LR models were applied to determine the landslide susceptibility. The three models are validated using the receiver operating characteristic and the area under which curve values were calculated. The validation results showed that the LR model (accuracy is 96 &#37;) has better prediction than fuzzy logic (accuracy is 95 &#37;) and FR (accuracy is 94 &#37;) models. Also, among the fuzzy operators, the gamma operator (lambda = 0.975) showed the best accuracy (94.64 &#37;) while the fuzzy OR operator when applied showed the worst accuracy (85.11 &#37;).
WOS:000355142800079
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="111">
<title>Spatial prediction of landslide hazard at the Luxi area (China) using support vector machines</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-015-4866-9</url>
<snippet>The main objective of this study is to investigate the potential application of GIS-based Support Vector Machines (SVM) with four kernel functions, i.e., radial basis function (RBF), polynomial (PL), sigmoid (SIG), and linear (LN) for landslide susceptibility mapping at Luxi city in Jiangxi province, China. At the first stage of the study, a landslide inventory map with 282 landslide locations was identified using aerial photographs, satellite images, and field surveys. Of this, 70 &#37; of the landslides (196 landslide locations) are used as a training dataset and the rest (86 landslide locations) were used as the validation dataset. Then, 15 landslide conditioning factors were prepared, i.e., altitude, aspect, slope, stream power index (SPI), topographic wetness index (TWI), sediment transport index (STI), plan curvature, profile curvature, distance from river, distance from road, distance from fault, lithology, land use, NDVI, and rainfall. Using these conditioning factors, landslide susceptibility indexes were calculated using SVM with the four kernel functions. Subsequently, the results were exported and plotted in ArcGIS and four landslide susceptibility maps were produced. The four susceptibility maps were validated and compared using the landslide locations and the success rate and prediction rate methods. The validation results showed that success rates for the four SVM models are 82.0 &#37; (RBF), 83.0 &#37; (PL), 45.0 &#37; (SIG), and 70.0 &#37; (LN). The prediction rates for the four SVM models are 81.0 &#37; (RBF), 71.0 &#37; (PL), 40.0 &#37; (SIG), and LN 63.0 &#37; (SIG). The result shows that the RBF-SVM model has the highest overall performance. The produced susceptibility maps may be useful for general land-use planning in landslides.
WOS:000370239800040
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="112">
<title>A Remote Sensing-Based Approach for Debris-Flow Susceptibility Assessment Using Artificial Neural Networks and Logistic Regression Modeling</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2014.2337273</url>
<snippet>Efforts to map the distribution of debris flows, to assess the factors controlling their development, and to identify the areas susceptible to their occurrences are often hampered by the paucity of monitoring systems and historical databases in many parts of the world. In this paper, we develop and successfully apply methodologies that rely heavily on readily available remote-sensing datasets over the Jazan province in the Red Sea hills of Saudi Arabia. A fivefold exercise was conducted: 1) a geographical information system (GIS) with a Web interface was generated to host and analyze relevant coregistered remote-sensing data and derived products; 2) an inventory was compiled for debris flows identified from satellite datasets (e.g., GeoEye, Orbview), a subset of which was field verified; 3) spatial analyses were conducted in a GIS environment and 10 predisposing factors were identified; 4) an artificial neural network (ANN) model and a logistic regression (LR) model were constructed, optimized, and validated; and 5) the generated models were used to produce debris-flow susceptibility maps. Findings include: 1) excellent prediction performance for both models (ANN: 96.1&#37;; LR: 96.3&#37;); 2) the high correspondence between model outputs (91.5&#37; of the predictions were common) reinforces the validity of the debris-flow susceptibility results; 3) the variables with the highest predictive power were topographic position index (TPI), slope, distance to drainage line (DTDL), and normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI); and 4) the adopted methodologies are reliable, cost-effective, and could potentially be applied over many of the worlds data-scarce mountainous lands, particularly along the Red Sea Hills.
WOS:000348372000019
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="113">
<title>Landslide hazard zonation using analytical hierarchy process along National Highway-3 in mid Himalayas of Himachal Pradesh, India</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-018-7896-2</url>
<snippet>Landslide zonation studies emphasize on preparation of landslide hazard zonation maps considering major instability factors contributing to occurrence of landslides. This paper deals with geographic information system-based landslide hazard zonation in mid Himalayas of Himachal Pradesh from Mandi to Kullu by considering nine relevant instability factors to develop the hazard zonation map. Analytical hierarchy process was applied to assign relative weightages over all ranges of instability factors of the slopes in study area. To generate landslide hazard zonation map, layers in geographic information system were created corresponding to each instability factor. An inventory of existing major landslides in the study area was prepared and combined with the landslide hazard zonation map for validation purpose. The validation of the model was made using area under curve technique and reveals good agreement between the produced hazard map and previous landslide inventory with prediction accuracy of 79.08&#37;. Thelandslide hazard zonation map was classified by natural break classifier into very low hazard, low hazard, moderate hazard, high hazard and very high landslide hazard classes in geographic information system depending upon the frequency of occurrence of landslides in each class. The resultant hazard zonation map shows that 14.30&#37; of the area lies in very high hazard zone followed by 15.97&#37; in high hazard zone. The proposed model provides the best-fit classification using hierarchical approach for the causative factors of landslides having complex structure. The developed hazard zonation map is useful for landslide preparedness, land-use planning, and social-economic and sustainable development of the region.
WOS:000447506500002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="114">
<title>SPATIAL RESOLUTION EFFECTS OF DIGITAL TERRAIN MODELS ON LANDSLIDE SUSCEPTIBILITY ANALYSIS</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.5194/isprsarchives-XLI-B8-33-2016</url>
<snippet>The purposes of this study are to identify the maximum number of correlated factors for landslide susceptibility mapping and to evaluate landslide susceptibility at Sihjhong river catchment in the southern Taiwan, integrating two techniques, namely certainty factor (CF) and artificial neural network (ANN). The landslide inventory data of the Central Geological Survey (CGS, MOEA) in 2004-2014 and two digital elevation model (DEM) datasets including a 5-meter LiDAR DEM and a 30-meter Aster DEM were prepared. We collected thirteen possible landslide-conditioning factors. Considering the multi-collinearity and factor redundancy, we applied the CF approach to optimize these thirteen conditioning factors. We hypothesize that if the CF values of the thematic factor layers are positive, it implies that these conditioning factors have a positive relationship with the landslide occurrence. Therefore, based on this assumption and positive CF values, seven conditioning factors including slope angle, slope aspect, elevation, terrain roughness index (TRI), terrain position index (TPI), total curvature, and lithology have been selected for further analysis. The results showed that the optimized-factors model provides a better accuracy for predicting landslide susceptibility in the study area. In conclusion, the optimized-factors model is suggested for selecting relative factors of landslide occurrence.
WOS:000393156000005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="115">
<title>Assessment and mapping of slope stability based on slope units: A case study in Yan'an, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12040-016-0741-7</url>
<snippet>Precipitation frequently triggers shallow landslides in the Loess Plateau of Shaanxi, China, resulting in loss of life, damage to gas and oil routes, and destruction of transport infrastructure and farmland. To assess the possibility of shallow landslides at different precipitation levels, a method to draw slope units and steepest slope profiles based on ARCtools and a new method for calculating slope stability are proposed. The methods were implemented in a case study conducted in Yanan, north-west China. High resolution DEM (Digital Elevation Model) images, soil parameters from in-situ laboratory measurements and maximum depths of precipitation infiltration were used as input parameters in the method. Next, DEM and reverse DEM were employed to map 2146 slope units in the study area, based on which the steepest profiles of the slope units were constructed. Combining analysis of the water content of loess, strength of the sliding surface, its response to precipitation and the infinite slope stability equation, a new equation to calculate infinite slope stability is proposed to assess shallow landslide stability. The slope unit stability was calculated using the equation at 10-, 20-, 50-and 100-year return periods of antecedent effective precipitation. The number of slope units experiencing failure increased in response to increasing effective antecedent rainfall. These results were validated based on the occurrence of landslides in recent decades. Finally, the applicability and limitations of the model are discussed.
WOS:000386922300010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="116">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping based on GIS and support vector machine models for the Qianyang County, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-015-5093-0</url>
<snippet>The main purpose of this study is to produce reliable susceptibility maps using GIS-based support vector machine (SVM) models and compare their performances for the Qianyang County of Baoji City, Shaanxi Province, China. In this paper, with kernel classifiers of linear, polynomial, radial basis function and sigmoid, the four various types were applied in landslide susceptibility mapping. The important input parameters for the landslide susceptibility assessment were acquired from different sources. Firstly, 81 landslide sites were obtained by aerial photographs, earlier reports and field surveys. Then, the landslide inventory was randomly classified into two datasets: 70 &#37; (56 landslides) for training the models and 30 &#37; (25 landslides) for validation purpose. Secondly, 15 landslide conditioning factors were selected (i.e., slope angle, slope aspect, altitude, plan curvature, profile curvature, distance to faults, distance to rivers, distance to roads, NDVI, STI, SPI, TWI, geomorphology, rainfall, and lithology). Subsequently, with four types of kernel function classifiers based on landslide conditioning factors, landslide susceptibility parameters were obtained using SVM models. Finally, the rationality of landslide susceptibility maps was verified using the receiver operating characteristics with both success rate curve and prediction rate curve. The validation results showed that success rates for the four SVM models were 83.15 &#37; (RBF-SVM), 82.72 &#37; (PL-SVM), 81.77 &#37; (LN-SVM), and 79.99 &#37; (SIG-SVM). The prediction rates for the four SVM models were 77.98 &#37; (RBF-SVM), 77.50 &#37; (PL-SVM), 77.07 &#37; (LN-SVM), and 76.08 &#37; (SIG-SVM), respectively. The results showed that the RBF-SVM model had the highest overall performance.
WOS:000372251000025
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="117">
<title>Integration of Information Theory, K-Means Cluster Analysis and the Logistic Regression Model for Landslide Susceptibility Mapping in the Three Gorges Area, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/rs9090938</url>
<snippet>In this work, an effective framework for landslide susceptibility mapping (LSM) is presented by integrating information theory, K-means cluster analysis and statistical models. In general, landslides are triggered by many causative factors at a local scale, and the impact of these factors is closely related to geographic locations and spatial neighborhoods. Based on these facts, the main idea of this research is to group a study area into several clusters to ensure that landslides in each cluster are affected by the same set of selected causative factors. Based on this idea, the proposed predictive method is constructed for accurate LSM at a regional scale by applying a statistical model to each cluster of the study area. Specifically, each causative factor is first classified by the natural breaks method with the optimal number of classes, which is determined by adopting Shannons entropy index. Then, a certainty factor (CF) for each class of factors is estimated. The selection of the causative factors for each cluster is determined based on the CF values of each factor. Furthermore, the logistic regression model is used as an example of statistical models in each cluster using the selected causative factors for landslide prediction. Finally, a global landslide susceptibility map is obtained by combining the regional maps. Experimental results based on both qualitative and quantitative analysis indicated that the proposed framework can achieve more accurate landslide susceptibility maps when compared to some existing methods, e.g., the proposed framework can achieve an overall prediction accuracy of 91.76&#37;, which is 7.63-11.5&#37; higher than those existing methods. Therefore, the local scale LSM technique is very promising for further improvement of landslide prediction.
WOS:000414138700068
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="118">
<title>A novel geographical information system-based Ant Miner algorithm model for delineating groundwater flowing artesian well boundary: a case study from Iraqi southern and western deserts</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-017-6876-2</url>
<snippet>The Ant Miner algorithm was compared with the bivariate frequency ratio (FR) and boosted regression trees (BRT) algorithms in terms of its capacity to assess groundwater potential. A geospatial dataset was prepared that contains two components: a flowing well inventory map and eleven factors relevant to groundwater conditions. Average nearest neighbor technique was used to investigate the spatial pattern of flowing wells and to find the appropriate distance between flowing and nonflowing points in the study area. A wrapper approach known as random forest classifier and a filtering approach known as information gain ratio were used to identify the most relevant groundwater factors. The developed models were validated via the area under the operating characteristic curve. Results revealed that the Ant Miner model performed better in terms of both success (0.944) and prediction (0.92) rates compared to FR and BRT. Furthermore, the Ant Miner algorithm derived five simple, easily interpreted rules for predicting groundwater potential that can be used by hydrogeologists for identifying potential groundwater well locations with minimal effort and cost.
WOS:000407545200027
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="119">
<title>Investigation of sinkholes spatial distribution using the weights of evidence method and GIS in the vicinity of Karapinar (Konya, Turkey)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2015.04.034</url>
<snippet>There are many sinkholes (182) in the vicinity of Karapinar. Approximately 20 large sinkholes (&gt;10 m in diameter) were formed within the Obruk Plateau between 1970 and 2012. The formation of sinkholes is the most important geological hazard in the study area because they can damage engineering structures, settlements, agricultural areas, and eventually be a source of casualties. To date, no study has been conducted on the distribution of sinkholes in this region. In this study, the spatial distribution of the sinkholes and the factors controlling sinkhole development were studied through the use of geographical information systems using a sinkhole inventory and a spatial database containing information on the topography, geology, hydrogeology, and land use. Initially, 182 sinkholes were identified in the area by examining the digital elevation model produced for this study. The sinkholes were verified in the field. Thirty-two factor maps were produced to investigate their relationship with sinkholes using the weights of evidence method. The sinkholes are mainly related to dissolution of the Neogene-age lacustrine Insuyu Formation, consisting of limestone and clayey limestone. Sinkhole frequency increases in the vicinity of drainages (2000-3000 m) and faults (&lt;1000 m) and in areas with lower cover thickness (&lt;50 m). Injuries and property losses caused by sinkhole formation may be prevented or reduced by producing sinkhole susceptibility and risk maps considered the identified controlling factors. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000360511200004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="120">
<title>Susceptibility Assessment of Landslides Triggered by the Lushan Earthquake, April 20, 2013, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2014.2308553</url>
<snippet>The Lushan earthquake (Ms = 7.0; epicenter located at 30 degrees 17N, 102 degrees 57E) occurred on April 20, 2013 and had a focal depth of 12.3 km. The earthquake was triggered by the reactivation of the Longmenshan Fault in Lushan County, Sichuan Province, China. This earthquake caused massive landslides that resulted in tragic loss of life and economic devastation. Strong earthquakes are among the prime triggering factors of landslides. The zone of highest seismic intensity for this earthquake was selected as a case study to assess the susceptibility to earthquake-induced landslides. Visual interpretation of color aerial photographs with 0.4- and 0.6-m spatial resolution and extensive field surveys provided a detailed landslide inventory map that included 226 landslides. Nine primary landslide-related factors were selected as predictor variables, including elevation, slope, aspect, curvature classification, distance from drainages, slope structure, lithology, distance from faults, and peak ground acceleration. The support vector machine (SVM) is a popular learning procedure that is based on statistical learning theory and utilizes a kernel function to map data from the original feature space to a high-dimensional space. Using an SVM, a nonlinear landslide system can be converted into a linear landslide system. Two parameters C and sigma must be carefully predetermined to establish an efficient SVM. Therefore, a genetic algorithm (GA) was adopted to optimize the parameters of the SVM. The proposed GA-SVM model with the highest predictive accuracy and generalization ability was trained and then used to predict landslide susceptibility. The analytical results were validated by comparing them with known landslides using a success rate curve and classification accuracy. The GA-SVM model has an area ratio of 0.9586 and a kappa coefficient of 0.9575 and outperforms the SVM. Approximately, 94.97&#37; of the landslides lie in the very-high-susceptibility region, 2.17&#37; of the landslides lie in the high-susceptibility region, 1.13&#37; of the landslides lie in the moderate-susceptibility region, and 1.73&#37; of the landslides lie in the low- and very-low-susceptibility regions. The experimental results demonstrate that the GA-SVM model provides the best predictive accuracy. The model can effectively assess landslide susceptibility and provides a novel method for landslide prediction.
WOS:000344992200028
</snippet>
</document>

</searchresult>
