<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<searchresult>
<query>Global</query>
<document id="1">
<title>Optical remotely sensed time series data for land cover classification: A review</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2016.03.008</url>
<snippet>Accurate land cover information is required for science, monitoring, and reporting. Land cover changes naturally over time, as well as a result of anthropogenic activities. Monitoring and mapping of land cover and land cover change in a consistent and robust manner over large areas is made possible with Earth Observation (EO) data. Land cover products satisfying a range of science and policy information needs are currently produced periodically at different spatial and temporal scales. The increased availability of EO data-particularly from the Landsat archive (and soon to be augmented with Sentinel-2 data)-coupled with improved computing and storage capacity with novel image compositing approaches, have resulted in the availability of annual, large-area, gap-free, surface reflectance data products. In turn, these data products support the development of annual land cover products that can be both informed and constrained by change detection outputs. The inclusion of time series change in the land cover mapping process provides information on class stability and informs on logical class transitions (both temporally and categorically). In this review, we present the issues and opportunities associated with generating and validating time-series informed annual, large-area, land cover products, and identify methods suited to incorporating time series information and other novel inputs for land cover characterization. Crown Copyright (C) 2016 Published by Elsevier B.V.
WOS:000374624600005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="2">
<title>A generalized computer vision approach to mapping crop fields in heterogeneous agricultural landscapes</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.rse.2016.03.010</url>
<snippet>Smallholder farms dominate in many parts of the world, particularly Sub-Saharan Africa. These systems are characterized by small, heterogeneous, and often indistinct field patterns, requiring a specialized methodology to map agricultural land cover. Using a variety of sites in South Africa, we present a new approach to mapping agricultural fields, based on efficient extraction of a vast set of simple, highly correlated, and interdependent features, followed by a random forest classifier. We achieved similar high performance across agricultural types, including the spectrally indistinct smallholder fields as well as the more easily distinguishable commercial fields, and demonstrated the ability to generalize performance across large geographic areas. In sensitivity analyses, we determined multi-temporal information provided greater gains in performance than the addition of multi-spectral bands available in DigitalGlobe Worldview-2 imagery. (C) 2016 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.
WOS:000375506100017
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="3">
<title>Optimizing selection of training and auxiliary data for operational land cover classification for the LCMAP initiative</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2016.11.004</url>
<snippet>The U.S. Geological Surveys Land Change Monitoring, Assessment, and Projection (LCMAP) initiative is a new end-to-end capability to continuously track and characterize changes in land cover, use, and condition to better support research and applications relevant to resource management and environmental change. Among the LCMAP product suite are annual land cover maps that will be available to the public. This paper describes an approach to optimize the selection of training and auxiliary data for deriving the thematic land cover maps based on all available clear observations from Landsats 4-8. Training data were selected from map products of the U.S. Geological Surveys Land Cover Trends project. The Random Forest classifier was applied for different classification scenarios based on the Continuous Change Detection and Classification (CCDC) algorithm. We found that extracting training data proportionally to the occurrence of land cover classes was superior to an equal distribution of training data per class, and suggest using a total of 20,000 training pixels to classify an area about the size of a Landsat scene. The problem of unbalanced training data was alleviated by extracting a minimum of 600 training pixels and a maximum of 8000 training pixels per class. We additionally explored removing outliers contained within the training data based on their spectral and spatial criteria, but observed no significant improvement in classification results. We also tested the importance of different types of auxiliary data that were available for the conterminous United States, including: (a) five variables used by the National Land Cover Database, (b) three variables from the cloud screening "Function of mask" (Fmask) statistics, and 
WOS:000390719600015
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="4">
<title>Efficiency Assessment of Multitemporal C-Band Radarsat-2 Intensity and Landsat-8 Surface Reflectance Satellite Imagery for Crop Classification in Ukraine</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2015.2454297</url>
<snippet>Ukraine is one of the most developed agricultural countries in the world. For many applications, it is extremely important to provide reliable crop maps taking into account diversity of cropping systems used in Ukraine. The use of optical imagery only is limited due to cloud cover, and previous studies showed particular difficulties in discriminating summer crops in Ukraine such as maize, soybeans, sunflower, and sugar beet. This paper focuses on exploring feasibility and assessing efficiency of using multitemporal satellite synthetic-aperture radar (SAR) acquired in C-band and optical images for crop classification in Ukraine. Both optical (Landsat-8/OLI) and SAR (Radarsat-2) images are used to assess the impact of adding backscattering intensity from SAR images for classification purposes. SAR intensity information is very important due to availability of Sentinel-1 imagery over Ukraine starting March 2015. Different combinations of optical and SAR images, as well as SAR modes and polarizations, are assessed for better discrimination of crops. A committee of neural networks, in particular multilayer perceptrons (MLPs), is used to improve classification accuracy compared to several standard classifiers. It is found that using backscatter coefficients from SAR images alone provides the same performance for winter crops (wheat and rapeseed) as surface reflectance from optical images. Considering the summer crops, the major impact of adding backscatter intensity information from SAR images is in better separation of sunflower, soybeans, and maize.
WOS:000384907200034
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="5">
<title>The Sensitivity of Mapping Methods to Reference Data Quality: Training Supervised Image Classifications with Imperfect Reference Data</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijgi5110199</url>
<snippet>The accuracy of a map is dependent on the reference dataset used in its construction. Classification analyses used in thematic mapping can, for example, be sensitive to a range of sampling and data quality concerns. With particular focus on the latter, the effects of reference data quality on land cover classifications from airborne thematic mapper data are explored. Variations in sampling intensity and effort are highlighted in a dataset that is widely used in mapping and modelling studies; these may need accounting for in analyses. The quality of the labelling in the reference dataset was also a key variable influencing mapping accuracy. Accuracy varied with the amount and nature of mislabelled training cases with the nature of the effects varying between classifiers. The largest impacts on accuracy occurred when mislabelling involved confusion between similar classes. Accuracy was also typically negatively related to the magnitude of mislabelled cases and the support vector machine (SVM), which has been claimed to be relatively insensitive to training data error, was the most sensitive of the set of classifiers investigated, with overall classification accuracy declining by 8&#37; (significant at 95&#37; level of confidence) with the use of a training set containing 20&#37; mislabelled cases.
WOS:000390104200006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="6">
<title>Parcel-Based Crop Classification in Ukraine Using Landsat-8 Data and Sentinel-1A Data</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2016.2560141</url>
<snippet>For many applied problems in agricultural monitoring and food security, it is important to provide reliable crop classification maps. Satellite imagery is extremely valuable source of data to provide crop maps in a timely way at moderate and high spatial resolution. Information on parcel boundaries that takes into account the spatial context may improve the quality of maps compared to pixel-based classification approaches. In general, parcels may contain several plots with different crops and such situations should be taken into account when using parcel boundaries. In this paper, we aim to compare pixel-based and parcel-based approaches to crop classification from multitemporal optical (Landsat-8) and synthetic-aperture radar (SAR) Sentinel-1 imagery. For this, we propose a parcel-based approach that involves a pixel-based classification map and specifically designed rules to account for several plots within parcel. The study is carried out for the Joint Experiment of Crop Assessment and Monitoring test site in Ukraine covering the Kyiv oblast (North of Ukraine) in 2013-2015, and the Odessa oblast (South of Ukraine) in 2014-2015. We found that pixel-based overall classification accuracy can be increased from 85.32&#37; to 89.40&#37; when using parcel boundaries. Among tested parcel-based approaches, the one that relied on pixel-based classification map and a procedure to select multiple plots within the parcel yielded the best performance.
WOS:000379935100034
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="7">
<title>Change detection based on deep feature representation and mapping transformation for multi-spatial-resolution remote sensing images</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.isprsjprs.2016.02.013</url>
<snippet>Multi-spatial-resolution change detection is a newly proposed issue and it is of great significance in remote sensing, environmental and land use monitoring, etc. Though multi-spatial-resolution image pair are two kinds of representations of the same reality, they are often incommensurable superficially due to their different modalities and properties. In this paper, we present a novel multi-spatial resolution change detection framework, which incorporates deep-architecture-based unsupervised feature learning and mapping-based feature change analysis. Firstly, we transform multi-resolution image-pair into the same pixel-resolution through co-registration, followed by details recovery, which is designed to remedy the spatial details lost in the registration. Secondly, the denoising autoencoder is stacked to learn local and high-level representation/feature from the local neighborhood of the given pixel, in an unsupervised fashion. Thirdly, motivated by the fact that multi-resolution image-pair share the same reality in the unchanged regions, we try to explore the inner relationships between them by building a mapping neural network. And it can be used to learn a mapping function based on the most-unlikely-changed feature-pairs, which are selected from all the feature-pairs via a coarse initial change map generated in advance. The learned mapping function can bridge the different representations and highlight changes. Finally, we can build a robust and contractive change map through feature similarity analysis, and the change detection result is obtained through the segmentation of the final change map. Experiments are carried out on four real datasets, and the results confirmed the effectiveness and superiority of the proposed method. (C) 2016 International Society for Photogrammetry and Remote Sensing, Inc. (ISPRS). Published by Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000374624600003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="8">
<title>Estimating Soil Moisture with Landsat Data and Its Application in Extracting the Spatial Distribution of Winter Flooded Paddies</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/rs8010038</url>
<snippet>Dynamic monitoring of the spatial pattern of winter continuously flooded paddies (WFP) at regional scales is a challenging but highly necessary process in analyzing trace greenhouse gas emissions, water resource management, and food security. The present study was carried out to demonstrate the feasibility of extracting the spatial distribution of WFP through time series imagery of volumetric surface soil moisture content ((v)) at the field scale (30 m). A trade-off approach based on the synergistic use of tasseled cap transformation wetness and temperature vegetation dryness index was utilized to obtain paddy (v). The results showed that the modeled (v) was in good agreement with in situ measurements. The overall correlation coefficient (R) was 0.78, with root-mean-square ranging from 1.96&#37; to 9.96&#37; in terms of different vegetation cover and surface water status. The lowest error of (v) estimates was found to be restricted at the flooded paddy surface with moderate or high fractional vegetation cover. The flooded paddy was then successfully identified using the (v) image with saturated moisture content thresholding, with an overall accuracy of 83.33&#37;. This indicated that the derived geospatial dataset of WFP could be reliably applied to fill gaps in census statistics.
WOS:000369494500020
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="9">
<title>COMBINING SPECTRAL AND TEXTURE FEATURES USING RANDOM FOREST ALGORITHM: EXTRACTING IMPERVIOUS SURFACE AREA IN WUHAN</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.5194/isprsarchives-XLI-B7-351-2016</url>
<snippet>Impervious surface area (ISA) is one of the most important indicators of urban environments. At present, based on multi-resolution remote sensing images, numerous approaches have been proposed to extract impervious surface, using statistical estimation, sub pixel classification and spectral mixture analysis method of sub-pixel analysis. Through these methods, impervious surfaces can be effectively applied to regional-scale planning and management. However, for the large scale region, high resolution remote sensing images can provide more details, and therefore they will be more conducive to analysis environmental monitoring and urban management. Since the purpose of this study is to map impervious surfaces more effectively, three classification algorithms (random forests, decision trees, and artificial neural networks) were tested for their ability to map impervious surface. Random forests outperformed the decision trees, and artificial neural networks in precision. Combining the spectral indices and texture, random forests is applied to impervious surface extraction with a producers accuracy of 0.98, a users accuracy of 0.97, and an overall accuracy of 0.98 and a kappa coefficient of 0.97.
WOS:000393155900055
</snippet>
</document>

</searchresult>
