<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<searchresult>
<query>Global</query>
<document id="1">
<title>Sensitivity analysis and accuracy assessment of the land transformation model using cellular automata</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/15481603.2017.1309125</url>
<snippet>This study evaluates the effects of cellular automata (CA) with different neighborhood sizes on the predictive performance of the Land Transformation Model (LTM). Landsat images were used to extract urban footprints and the driving forces behind urban growth seen for the metropolitan areas of Tehran and Isfahan in Iran. LTM, which uses a back-propagation neural network, was applied to investigate the relationships between urban growth and the associated drivers, and to create the transition probability map. To simulate urban growth, the following two approaches were implemented: (a) the LTM using a top-down approach for cell allocation grounding on the highest values in the transition probability map and (b) a CA with varying spatial neighborhood sizes. The results show that using the LTM-CA approach increases the accuracy of the simulated land use maps when compared with the use of the LTM top-down approach. In particular, the LTM-CA with a 7 x 7 neighborhood size performed well and improved the accuracy. The level of agreement between simulated and actual urban growth increased from 58&#37; to 61&#37; for Tehran and from 39&#37; to 43&#37; for Isfahan. In conclusion, even though the LTM-CA outperforms the LTM with a top-down approach, more studies have to be carried out within other geographical settings to better evaluate the effect of CA on the allocation phase of the urban growth simulation.
WOS:000406530000002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="2">
<title>A spatial zoning approach to calibrate and validate urban growth models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/13658816.2016.1236927</url>
<snippet>Calibration and validation of models predicting urban growth have been largely developed using internal variables. Further investigation is required to improve models calibration and validation mixing internal and external variables. To reach this objective, a spatial zoning approach simulating long-term expansion of Mashhad, the second largest city of Iran, was presented in this study. Spatial zoning approaches distinguish local-scale urban dynamics in districts with different socioeconomic characteristics. Thiessen polygons were used to identify districts with different morphology and functional attributes. Urban growth was subsequently simulated for each district using a Multi-Layer Perceptron (MLP) neural network and Markov chains (MC) analysis. MLP and MC algorithms were respectively used to derive transition maps from non-urban to urban use of land and to determine spatial evolution of built-up areas at the metropolitan scale. Results of simulations based on spatial zoning were compared with outcomes of traditional urban growth models. Spatial zoning improved significantly models accuracy in respect to more traditional simulation modes. The approach proposed here is appropriate when simulating land-use changes under discontinuous urban expansion.
WOS:000392597300007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="3">
<title>Urbanization dynamics of Tehran city (1975-2015) using artificial neural networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/17445647.2017.1305300</url>
<snippet>Land-use dynamic is a major challenge for town and country planners especially in developing countries such as Iran. Iran has been under rapid urban expansion and population growth for past three decades which led to lack of resources, environmental deterioration and haphazard landscape development. In this paper, an attempt has been made to map the urbanization dynamics of Tehran in 40 years based on remote sensing imagery and by means of artificial neural networks. The presented scheme could be taken into consideration when planning initiatives aimed at surveying, monitoring, managing and sustainable development of the territory. Moreover, it can serve the experts in the fields of geography, urban studies and planning as a background for number of geographical analyses.
WOS:000419705700002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="4">
<title>Integration of genetic algorithm and multiple kernel support vector regression for modeling urban growth</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compenvurbsys.2017.04.011</url>
<snippet>There are two main issues of concern for land change scientists to consider. First, selecting appropriate and independent land cover change (LCC) drivers is a substantial challenge because these drivers usually correlate with each other. For this reason, we used a well-known machine learning tool called genetic algorithm (GA) to select the optimum LCC drivers. In addition, using the best or most appropriate LCC model is critical since some of them are limited to a specific function, to discover non-linear patterns within land use data. In this study, a support vector regression (SVR) was implemented to model LCC as SVRs use Various linear and non-linear kernels to better identify non-linear patterns within land use data. With such an approach, choosing the appropriate kernels to model LCC is critical because SVR kernels have a direct impact on the accuracy of the model. Therefore, various linear and non-linear kernels, including radial basis function (RBF), sigmoid (SIG), polynomial (PL) and linear (LN) kernels, were used across two phases: 1) in combination with GA, and 2) without GA present. The simulated maps resulting from each combination were evaluated using a recently modified version of the receiver operating characteristics (ROC) tool called the total operating characteristic (TOC) tool. The proposed approach was applied to simulate urban growth in Rasht County, which is located in the north of Iran. As a result, an SVR-GA-RBF model achieved the highest area under curve (AUC) value at 94&#37; while the lowest AUC was achieved when using the SVR-LN model at 71&#37;. The results show that the synergy between GA and SVR can effectively optimize the variables selection process used when developing an LCC model, and can enhance the predictive accuracy of SVR. (C) 2017 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000408300700003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="5">
<title>Coupling machine learning, tree-based and statistical models with cellular automata to simulate urban growth</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.compenvurbsys.2017.04.002</url>
<snippet>This paper compares six land use change (LUC) models, including artificial neural networks (ANNs), support vector regression (SVR), random forest (RF), classification and regression trees (CART), logistic regression (LR), and multivariate adaptive regression splines (MARS). These models were used to simulate urban growth in the mega city of Tehran Metropolitan Area (TMA). These LUC models were integrated with cellular automata (CA) and validated using a variety of goodness-of-fit metrics. The results showed that the percent correct metrics (PCMs) varied between 54.6&#37; for LR and 59.6&#37; for MARS, while the area under curve (AUC) ranged from 67.6&#37; for LR to 74.7&#37; for ANNs. The results also showed a considerable difference between the spatial patterns within the error maps. The results of this comparative study will enable decision makers and scholars to better understand the performance of the models when reducing the number of misses and false alarms is a priority. (C) 2017 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000403623600025
</snippet>
</document>

</searchresult>
