<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<searchresult>
<query>Global</query>
<document id="1">
<title>Towards improving the efficiency of the fuzzy cognitive map classifier</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.neucom.2016.11.059</url>
<snippet>Fuzzy Cognitive Map (FCM) is a model that combines selected features of fuzzy sets and neural networks. FCM is usually applied as a decision support tool or as a predictive model for time series forecasting. It is less well known as a classifier. To perform the classification, numeric data produced by the FCM must be assigned to class labels. To accomplish this task, we propose a new algorithm for generating thresholds for the discrimination of FCM outcomes. The thresholds resulting from the proposed algorithm are determined after the learning of the FCM, and, then they are applied when classifying new data. The results of the experiments conducted with publicly available data provide evidence that the application of the proposed algorithm leads to improved efficiency of the FCM classifier. Comparative experiments showed that the proposed approach makes the FCM a very competitive alternative to other state-of-the-art classifiers.
WOS:000393532800008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="2">
<title>A new conception on the Fuzzy Cognitive Maps method</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ifacol.2016.11.083</url>
<snippet>Fuzzy Cognitive Maps, being a combination of Fuzzy Logic and Neural Networks, have been gaining researchers interest on an international level. In recent years there has been an effort to evolve the method of Fuzzy Cognitive Maps and improve its response and effectiveness. Towards this direction various approaches and different learning algorithms have been used with very good results. This proves that Fuzzy Cognitive Maps method is very promising and worth of further investigation and development. Classical Fuzzy Cognitive Maps theory will be presented and a new conception will be put forward and implemented. The results will be analytically presented and the conclusions will leave space for more creative and evolving research. (C) 2016, IFAC (International Federation of Automatic Control) Hosting by Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000401259100055
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="3">
<title>Hybrid Model for Water Demand Prediction based on Fuzzy Cognitive Maps and Artificial Neural Networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>In this study, we propose a new hybrid approach for time series prediction based on the efficient capabilities of fuzzy cognitive maps (FCMs) with structure optimization algorithms and artificial neural networks (ANNs). The proposed structure optimization genetic algorithm (SOGA) for automatic construction of FCM is used for modeling complexity based on historical time series, and artificial neural networks (ANNs) which are used at the final process for making time series prediction. The suggested SOGA-FCM method is used for selecting the most important nodes (attributes) and interconnections among them which in the next stage are used as the input data to ANN used for time series prediction after training. The FCM with efficient learning algorithms and ANN have been already proved as sufficient methods for making time series forecasting. The performance of the proposed approach is presented through the analysis of real data of daily water demand and the corresponding prediction. The multivariate analysis of historical data is held for nine variables, season, month, day or week, holiday, mean and high temperature, rain average, touristic activity and water demand. The whole approach was implemented in an intelligent software tool initially deployed for FCM prediction. Through the experimental analysis, the usefulness of the new hybrid approach in water demand prediction is demonstrated, by calculating the mean absolute error (as one of the well known prediction measures). The results are promising for future work to this direction.
WOS:000392150700212
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="4">
<title>Accurate Prediction of Differential GPS Corrections using Fuzzy Cognitive Map</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>Fuzzy Cognitive Maps (FCMs) are fuzzy neural networks that are used for modeling and simulation of dynamic systems in a spread spectrum of different areas. In this paper, we apply this method for modeling the time variant errors of Global Positioning System (GPS) receivers, which are utilized for many surveying and navigation applications in various locations. These errors in receivers are ordinarily caused by atmosphere, imprecise orbit, satellite distribution geometry, multi-path, satellite, receiver clock, and selective availability. For increasing the accuracy of positioning, we predict the components' errors of location that are used as Differential GPS (DGPS) corrections in real-time positioning by FCM. To validate the performance, this approach is verified with experimental data from an actual data collection. The simulation studies show the effectiveness of the proposed approach compared with the results of multi-layer perceptron neural network.
WOS:000428435300013
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="5">
<title>Dynamic Fuzzy Cognitive Maps Embedded and Classical Fuzzy Controllers Applied in Industrial Process</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>This research presents the application of intelligent techniques to control an industrial mixer. The controller design is based on Hebbian learning for evolution of Fuzzy Cognitive Maps. A Fuzzy Classic Controller and Artificial Neural Network was used to validate the simulation results. Experimental simulations and analysis in this control problem was made. In addition, the results were embedded using algorithms into the Arduino platform.
WOS:000428763400011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="6">
<title>On the comparison of random and Hebbian weights for the training of single-hidden layer feedforward neural networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.eswa.2017.04.025</url>
<snippet>4 In this paper, we provide an experimental study for two unsupervised processes, namely, the random initialization and the Hebbian learning, which can be used to determine the input weights in Single-hidden Layer Feedforward Neural Networks (SLFNs). In addition, a fusion technique that combines the two feature spaces is proposed. Experiments are conducted on six publicly available facial image datasets. Experimental results show that the proposed fusion technique can improve the performance of Hebbian and random feature spaces when they achieve similar performance. In the cases where the difference in performance of the two feature spaces is high, the proposed fusion scheme preserves the power of the most discriminating one and outperforms the average fused feature space. The experimental results show that there is a trade-off between the generalization of the Hebbian feature space and the low computational cost of the random one. (C) 2017 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.
WOS:000403030000015
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="7">
<title>A two-stage model for time series prediction based on fuzzy cognitive maps and neural networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.neucom.2016.10.072</url>
<snippet>This paper proposes a two-stage prediction model, for multivariate time series prediction based on the efficient capabilities of evolutionary fuzzy cognitive maps (FCMs) enhanced by structure optimization algorithms and artificial neural networks (ANNs). In the first-stage, an evolutionary FCM is constructed automatically from historical time series data using the previously proposed structure optimization genetic algorithm, while in the second stage, the produced FCM defines the inputs in an ANN which next is trained by the back propagation method with momentum and Levenberg-Marquardt algorithm on the basis of available data. The structure optimization genetic algorithm for automatic construction of FCM is implemented for modeling complexity based on historical time series data, selecting the most important nodes (attributes) and interconnections among them thus providing a less complex and efficient FCM-based model. This model is used next as input in an ANN. ANNs are used at the final process for making time series prediction considering as inputs the concepts defined by the produced FCM. The previously proposed structure optimization genetic algorithm for FCM construction by historical data as well as the ANN have been already proved their efficacy on time series forecasting. The performance of the proposed approach is presented through the analysis of multivariate historical data of benchmark datasets for making predictions. The multivariate analysis of historical data is held for a large number of input variables, like season, month, day or week, holiday, mean and high temperature, etc. The whole approach was implemented in an intelligent software tool initially deployed for FCM prediction. Through the experimental analysis, the usefulness of the new two-stage approach in time series prediction is demonstrated, by calculating seven prediction performance indicators which are well known from the literature.
WOS:000393532800011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="8">
<title>Learning of Fuzzy Cognitive Maps With Varying Densities Using A Multiobjective Evolutionary Algorithm</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TFUZZ.2015.2426314</url>
<snippet>Fuzzy cognitive maps (FCMs) are cognition fuzzy influence graphs, which are based on fuzzy logic and neural networks. Many automated learning algorithms have been proposed to reconstruct FCMs from data, but most learnedmaps using such methods are much denser than those constructed by human experts. To this end, we first model the FCM learning problem as a multiobjective optimization problem, and then propose a multiobjective evolutionary algorithm, labeled as MOEA-FCM, to learn FCM models. MOEA-FCM is able to learn FCMs with varying densities at the same time from input historical data, which can provide candidate solutions with different properties for decision makers. In the experiments, the performance of MOEA-FCM is validated on both synthetic and real data with varying sizes and densities. The experimental results demonstrate the efficiency of MOEA-FCM and show that MOEA-FCM can not only reconstruct FCMs with high accuracy without expert knowledge, but also create a diverse Pareto optimal front which consists of FCMs with varying densities. The significance of this study is that decision makers can choose different FCM models provided by MOEA-FCM based on their practical requirements.
WOS:000370764100006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="9">
<title>Content Analysis using Fuzzy Cognitive Map (FCM) A Guide to Capturing Causal Relationships from Secondary Sources of Data</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>Cognitive mapping was introduced as a method to model complex systems that reflects how experts or stakeholders understand cause-and-effect relationships. Later, fuzzy cognitive mapping (FCM) combined cognitive mapping with artificial neural networks (ANN), resulting in the unique capacity to capture and use qualitative data to perform quantitative analysis and study system behavior in response to changes of system elements. However, when it comes to building FCM models from qualitative data, particularly from secondary data sources, guidance for modelers is scarce. This article introduces a step by step guideline for building FCM that not only deals with causal relationships but also offers techniques to adjust the inconsistencies, and tune the granularities through parent-child relationships. It also proposes two techniques, isolated graph analysis, and receiver-only-concept analysis to investigate the completeness of the final FCM and hypothesize new connections to fill the gaps.
WOS:000419843900063
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="10">
<title>Wavelet fuzzy cognitive maps</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.neucom.2016.10.071</url>
<snippet>Fuzzy cognitive maps (FCMs) are fuzzy influence graphs which consist of concepts and weighted edges. Various transfer functions have been applied in modelling and simulating the dynamic system of FCMs. In FCMs, transfer function is used to bound the expression level of nodes to a certain range. Therefore, in this paper, we first use wavelet transfer function, and then combine it with FCMs to form wavelet FCMs (WFCM). The wavelet function is a kind of local functions that has limited duration and an average value of zero. Then, we conduct comprehensive analyses over existing transfer functions using synthetic data, real data and pattern classification problems. Finally, according to analysis, a new method involving the selection of transfer functions in the optimization process for pattern classification problems is proposed. The experimental results demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed method. Still, findings show how the existing functions offer different capacities to deal with both problems.
WOS:000393532800009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="11">
<title>On the convergence of sigmoid Fuzzy Cognitive Maps</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ins.2016.02.040</url>
<snippet>Fuzzy Cognitive Maps (FCM) are Recurrent Neural Networks that are used for modeling complex dynamical systems using causal relations. Similarly to other recurrent models, a FCM-based system repeatedly propagates an initial activation vector over the causal network until either the map converges to a fixed-point or a maximal number of cycles is reached. The former scenario leads to a hidden pattern, whereas the latter implies that cyclic or chaotic configurations may be produced. It should be highlighted that FCM equipped with discrete transfer functions never exhibit chaotic states, but this premise cannot be ensured for systems having continuous neurons. Recently, a few studies dealing with convergence on continuous FCM have been introduced. However, such methods are not suitable for FCM-based systems used in pattern classification environments. In this paper, we first review a new heuristic procedure called Stability based on sigmoid Functions, which allows to improve the convergence on sigmoid FCM, without modifying the weights configuration. Afterwards, we examine some drawbacks that affect the algorithm performance and introduce solutions to enhance its performance in pattern classification environments. Additionally, we formalize several definitions which were omitted in the original research. These solutions lead to accurate classifiers and prevent specific scenarios where the method may fail. Towards the end, we conduct numerical simulations across six FCM-based classifiers with unstable features in order to evaluate the proposed improvements in pattern classification environments. (C) 2016 Elsevier Inc. All rights reserved.
WOS:000374081300010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="12">
<title>A review of fuzzy cognitive maps in medicine: Taxonomy, methods, and applications</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.cmpb.2017.02.021</url>
<snippet>Background and Objective: A high percentage of medical errors, committed because of physicians lack of experience, huge volume of data to be analyzed, and inaccessibility to medical records of previous patients, can be reduced using computer-aided techniques. Therefore, designing more efficient medical decision-support systems (MDSSs) to assist physicians in decision-making is crucially important. Through combining the properties of fuzzy logic and neural networks, fuzzy cognitive maps (FCMs) are among the latest, most efficient, and strongest artificial intelligence techniques for modeling complex systems. This review study is conducted to identify different FCM structures used in MDSS designs. The best structure for each medical application can be introduced by studying the properties of FCM structures. Methods: This paper surveys the most important decision-making methods and applications of FCMs in the medical field in recent years. To investigate the efficiency and capability of different FCM models in designing MDSSs, medical applications are categorized into four key areas: decision-making, diagnosis, prediction, and classification. Also, various diagnosis and decision support problems addressed by FCMs in recent years are reviewed with the goal of introducing different types of FCMs and determining their contribution to the improvements made in the fields of medical diagnosis and treatment. Results: In this survey, a general trend for future studies in this field is provided by analyzing various FCM structures used for medical purposes, and the results from each category. Conclusions: Due to the unique specifications of FCMs in integrating human knowledge and experience with computer-aided techniques, they are among practical instruments for MDSS design. In the not too distant future, they will have a significant role in medical sciences. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000399509800014
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="13">
<title>Fuzzy transforms prediction in spatial analysis and its application to demographic balance data</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s00500-017-2621-8</url>
<snippet>We present a new prediction algorithm based on fuzzy transforms for forecasting problems in spatial analysis. Our algorithm allows to predict the spatial distribution of assigned parameters of the problem under exam. Here, we test our method by exploring the demographical balance data measured every month in the period 01/01/2003-31/10/2014 in the municipalities of "Cilento and Vallo di Diano" National Park located in the district of Salerno (Italy). We use this method for predicting the value of the parameters "birthrate" and "deathrate" in November 2014. We apply this process in all the municipalities in the area of study; moreover, we present a fuzzification process for establishing the thematic map of the errors calculated between the real data and the predicted data. The thematic maps are constructed in a GIS environment.
WOS:000403472700007
</snippet>
</document>

</searchresult>
