<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<searchresult>
<query>Global</query>
<document id="1">
<title>Debris Flow Susceptibility Mapping Using Machine-Learning Techniques in Shigatse Area, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/rs11232801</url>
<snippet>Debris flows have been always a serious problem in the mountain areas. Research on the assessment of debris flows susceptibility (DFS) is useful for preventing and mitigating debris flow risks. The main purpose of this work is to study the DFS in the Shigatse area of Tibet, by using machine learning methods, after assessing the main triggering factors of debris flows. Remote sensing and geographic information system (GIS) are used to obtain datasets of topography, vegetation, human activities and soil factors for local debris flows. The problem of debris flow susceptibility level imbalances in datasets is addressed by the Borderline-SMOTE method. Five machine learning methods, i.e., back propagation neural network (BPNN), one-dimensional convolutional neural network (1D-CNN), decision tree (DT), random forest (RF), and extreme gradient boosting (XGBoost) have been used to analyze and fit the relationship between debris flow triggering factors and occurrence, and to evaluate the weight of each triggering factor. The ANOVA and Tukey HSD tests have revealed that the XGBoost model exhibited the best mean accuracy (0.924) on ten-fold cross-validation and the performance was significantly better than that of the BPNN (0.871), DT (0.816), and RF (0.901). However, the performance of the XGBoost did not significantly differ from that of the 1D-CNN (0.914). This is also the first comparison experiment between XGBoost and 1D-CNN methods in the DFS study. The DFS maps have been verified by five evaluation methods: Precision, Recall, F1 score, Accuracy and area under the curve (AUC). Experiments show that the XGBoost has the best score, and the factors that have a greater impact on debris flows are aspect, annual average rainfall, profile curvature, and elevation.
WOS:000508382100082
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="2">
<title>Remote sensing GIS-based landslide susceptibility &amp; risk modeling in Darjeeling-Sikkim Himalaya together with FEM-based slope stability analysis of the terrain</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-021-04823-5</url>
<snippet>Landslide susceptibility (LSI) modeling of Darjeeling-Sikkim Himalaya is performed by integrating 28 causative factors on C-28(28) combinations on Geographical Information System (GIS) following analytic hierarchy process (AHP)-based multicriteria decision protocol, logistic regression (LR)-based multivariate technique, machine learning data-driven random forest (RF) and artificial neural network (ANN) methods wherein the terrain is classified into None (with: 0.0 &lt; LSI &lt;= 0.17), Low (with: 0.17 &lt; LSI &lt;= 0.34), Moderate (with: 0.34 &lt; LSI &lt;= 0.51), High (with: 0.51 &lt; LSI &lt;= 0.68),Very High (with: 0.68 &lt; LSI &lt;= 0.85) and Severe (with: 0.85 &lt; LSI &lt;= 1.00) susceptible zones as validated through standard statistical accuracy tests and direct cross-correlation analysis of all the susceptible zonation maps generated by drawing comparison with the 30&#37; landslide inventory test data. The best integrated thematic RF-based LSI vector layer with an accuracy level of 0.871, in turn, on integration with the vulnerability components like population density, number of households, building types, building height and building density has demarketed approximately 21&#37; of the region under Very High to Severe socioeconomic risk zone while about 36&#37; area are classified under Very High to Severe structural risk zone as implicated by devastating landslide hazards in the region. Ground Penetrating Radar Survey has been conducted on all the slopes in the Very High to Severe landslide susceptible zones wherein near-surface lithologic setting, presence of paleo-slopes and microstructural features like fractures/faults and poorly stratified debris flow have been imaged that provided favorable subsurface conditions for slope failure. Finite element method-based slope failure analysis for Newmark displacement estimates factor of safety (FoS) value that acts as the proxy in defining the degree of slope instability is seen to vary between 1.905 and 2.357 in the Low to Moderate landslide susceptible zone while it ranges between 1.051 and 1.652 in the High landslide susceptible zone and between 0.649 and 1.349 in the Very High to Severe landslide inventory subset along the slopes under both gravity loading and seismic shaking in the terrain. The slope stability analysis puts the yield acceleration between 0.0012 and 0.11984 m/s(2) and the total deformation between 0.0027 and 1.4484 m. All these parameters in the classified landslide susceptible zones in unison demonstrate how unstable are the terrain slopes in the High to Severe landslide susceptible zones.
WOS:000660800200001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="3">
<title>A comparative study of heterogeneous ensemble-learning techniques for landslide susceptibility mapping</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/13658816.2020.1808897</url>
<snippet>This study introduces four heterogeneous ensemble-learning techniques, that is, stacking, blending, simple averaging, and weighted averaging, to predict landslide susceptibility in Yanshan County, China. These techniques combine several state-of-the-art classifiers of convolutional neural network, recurrent neural network, support vector machine, and logistic regression in specific ways to produce reliable results and avoid problems with the model selection. The study consists of three main steps. The first step establishes a spatial database consisting of 16 landslide conditioning factors and 380 historical landslide locations. The second step randomly selects training (70&#37; of the total) and test (30&#37;) datasets out of grid cells corresponding to landslide and non-slide locations in the study area. The final step constructs the proposed heterogeneous ensemble-learning methods for landslide susceptibility mapping. The proposed ensemble-learning methods show higher prediction accuracy than the individual classifiers mentioned above based on statistical measures. The blending ensemble-learning method achieves the highest overall accuracy of 80.70&#37; compared to the other ensemble-learning methods.
WOS:000569836500001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="4">
<title>Assessment of the uncertainty and interpretability of deep learning models for mapping soil salinity using DeepQuantreg and game theory</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41598-022-19357-4</url>
<snippet>This research introduces a new combined modelling approach for mapping soil salinity in the Minab plain in southern Iran. This study assessed the uncertainty (with 95&#37; confidence limits) and interpretability of two deep learning (DL) models (deep boltzmann machine-DBM) and a one dimensional convolutional neural networks (1DCNN)-long short-term memory (LSTM) hybrid model (1DCNN-LSTM) for mapping soil salinity by applying DeepQuantreg and game theory (Shapely Additive exPlanations (SHAP) and permutation feature importance measure (PFIM)), respectively. Based on stepwise forward regression (SFR)-a technique for controlling factor selection, 18 of 47 potential controls were selected as effective factors. Inventory maps of soil salinity were generated based on 476 surface soil samples collected for measuring electrical conductivity (ECe). Based on Taylor diagrams, both DL models performed well (RMSE &lt; 20&#37;), but the 1DCNN-LSTM hybrid model performed slightly better than the DBM model. The uncertainty range associated with the ECe values predicted by both models estimated using DeepQuantilreg were similar (0-25 dS/m for the 1DCNN-LSTM hybrid model and 2-27 dS/m for DBM model). Based on the SFR and PFIM (permutation feature importance measure)-a measure in game theory, four controls (evaporation, sand content, precipitation and vertical distance to channel) were selected as the most important factors for soil salinity in the study area. The results of SHAP (Shapely Additive exPlanations)-the second measure used in game theory-suggested that five factors (evaporation, vertical distance to channel, sand content, cation exchange capacity (CEC) and digital elevation model (DEM)) have the strongest impact on model outputs. Overall, the methodology used in this study is recommend for applications in other regions for mapping environmental problems.
WOS:000852630800050
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="5">
<title>Deep Fusion of DOM and DSM Features for Benggang Discovery</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijgi10080556</url>
<snippet>Benggang is a typical erosional landform in southern and southeastern China. Since benggang poses significant risks to local ecological environments and economic infrastructure, it is vital to accurately detect benggang-eroded areas. Relying only on remote sensing imagery for benggang detection cannot produce satisfactory results. In this study, we propose integrating high-resolution Digital Orthophoto Map (DOM) and Digital Surface Model (DSM) data for efficient and automatic benggang discovery. The fusion of complementary rich information hidden in both DOM and DSM data is realized by a two-stream convolutional neural network (CNN), which integrates aggregated terrain and activation image features that are both extracted by supervised deep learning. We aggregate local low-level geomorphic features via a supervised diffusion-convolutional embedding branch for expressive representations of benggang terrain variations. Activation image features are obtained from an image-oriented convolutional neural network branch. The two sources of information (DOM and DSM) are fused via a gated neural network, which learns the most discriminative features for the detection of benggang. The evaluation of a challenging benggang dataset demonstrates that our method exceeds several baselines, even with limited training examples. The results show that the fusion of DOM and DSM data is beneficial for benggang detection via supervised convolutional and deep fusion networks.
WOS:000689272900001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="6">
<title>Medium scale earthflow susceptibility modelling by remote sensing and geographical information systems based multivariate statistics approach: an example from Northeastern Turkey</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-020-09217-7</url>
<snippet>The aim of the present study was to produce an earthflow susceptibility map for the city center and environs of the province of Rize located at the Northeastern part of Turkey. The study area is the rainiest region of Turkey, and due to the triggering effect of precipitation earthflows are frequently observed in and around the study area. Besides this point, weathered rock units and steep topography accompany with precipitation for the occurrence of earthflow cases. Considering this point, an earthflow susceptibility mapping was inferred to be a necessity for the area. Parameters, such as lithology, slope gradient, slope aspect, topographical wetness index (TWI), stream power index (SPI), slope curvature, and sediment capacity index (LS) were considered to be earthflow conditioning parameters. A multi-temporal earthflow inventory map for a period of 4 years (2011-2015) was initially generated by way of remote sensing approach and field surveys. Earthflow susceptibility map was produced using the logistic regression method after which the produced susceptibility map was validated. The mapped earthflows were separated into two groups prior to modelling and validation. The first group was for training and the second group was for validation steps. The accuracy of the model was measured by fitting them to a validation set of mapped earthflows. Area under curvature (AUC) approach was applied for validation purposes. The prediction capability of the earthflow susceptibility map produced can be regarded as acceptable in accordance with the AUC values of 0.62 for the logistic regression model. Based on these results, the obtained earthflow susceptibility map can be used to mitigate hazards related to landslides and to aid in land-use planning for the Rize city center.
WOS:000576915800002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="7">
<title>Landslide susceptibility maps of Italy: Lesson learnt from dealing with multiple landslide types and the uneven spatial distribution of the national inventory</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.earscirev.2022.104125</url>
<snippet>Landslide susceptibility corresponds to the probability of landslide occurrence across a given geographic space. This probability is usually estimated by using a binary classifier which is informed of landslide presence/absence data and associated landscape characteristics. Here, we consider the Italian national landslide inventory to prepare slope-unit based landslide susceptibility maps. These maps are prepared for the eight types of mass movements existing in the inventory, (Complex, Deep Seated Gravitational Slope Deformation, Diffused Fall, Fall, Rapid Flow, Shallow, Slow Flow, Translational) and we build one susceptibility map for each type. The analysis - carried out by using a Bayesian version of a Generalized Additive Model with a multiple intercept for each Italian region - revealed that the inventory may have been compiled with different levels of detail. This would be consistent with the dataset being assembled from twenty sub-inventories, each prepared by different administrations of the Italian regions. As a result, this spatial heterogeneity may lead to biased national-scale susceptibility maps. On the basis of these considerations, we further analyzed the national database to confirm or reject the varying quality hypothesis on the basis of the model equipped with multiple regional intercepts. For each landslide type, we then tried to build unbiased susceptibility models by removing regions with a poor landslide inventory from the calibration stage, and used them only as a prediction target of a simulation routine. We analyzed the resulting eight maps finding out a congruent dominant pattern in the Alpine and Apennine sectors.The whole procedure is implemented in R-INLA. This allowed to examine fixed (linear) and random (nonlinear) effects from an interpretative standpoint and produced a full prediction equipped with an estimated uncertainty.We propose this overall modeling pipeline for any landslide datasets where a significant mapping bias may influence the susceptibility pattern over space.
WOS:000842980100002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="8">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping using maximum entropy (MaxEnt) and geographically weighted logistic regression (GWLR) models in the Rio Aguas catchment (Almeria, SE Spain)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-023-05857-7</url>
<snippet>A landslide susceptibility analysis has been made in the Rio Aguas catchment (Almeria, Southeast Spain), using two statistical models, Maximum Entropy (MaxEnt) and Geographically Weighted Logistic Regression (GWLR). For this purpose, a previous landslide inventory has been used and re-elaborated, reaching a total incidence of 2.58&#37; of the whole area. Different types of movements have been distinguished, being rock falls, slides and complex movements the predominant. From the inventory, the centroid of the rupture zone has been extracted to represent the landslides introduced in the models. A previous factor analysis has been made, using 12 predictors related to morphometry, hydrography, geology and land cover, with 5 m grid spacing, allowing the selection of factors to be used in the analysis and discarding those showing correlation between them. Then, MaxEnt and GWLR models are applied using different distributions of training and testing samples from the landslide inventory. For the validation, the Area Under the Curve of the Receiver Operating Characteristic (AUC-ROC) has been used but additionally, the degree of fit (DF) has allowed to validate the rupture zones themselves, not only the centroids. Results show an excellent prediction with both metrics in all the methods and samples, but the better results are obtained in the GWLR method for AUC and in the MaxEnt for the degree of fit. Therefore, a consensus model of both methods has been obtained, that improves even more the results reaching an AUC value of 0.99 and a degree of fit of 90&#37;.
WOS:000936437100001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="9">
<title>Prediction of wetland area and depth using linear regression model and artificial neural network based cellular automata</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoinf.2021.101272</url>
<snippet>Wetlands are an integral part of the socio-ecological setup of the earth, but their fast transformation beg careful consideration. In this regard, the flood plain wetlands of the Atreyee river basin of India and Bangladesh are not exceptional. The main goal of this study is the mapping of the floodplain wetlands, along with arriving at predictions of their area up to 2039 using the advanced technique of artificial neural network based cellular automata (ANN-CA). Apart from this, prediction of wetland depth using linear regression model is another aim of the present research work. The analysis is executed using 27 Landsat images and Digital Elevation Model (DEM). Results reveal that the present wetland area is 52.92 km2 in pre-monsoon and 518.68 km2 in post-monsoon season, respectively. The composite wetland map from 1987 to 2019 of post-monsoon clearly indicates that 10.48km2 wetlands are identified as hydro-ecologically consistent wetlands. Simulated models reveal that the wetland area from 2009 to 2019 has declined by 66.16km2 and is expected to decrease by 164.62km2 in the next 20 years. Normalized Difference Water Index (NDWI) depth indicates that water availability also may decline significantly in the next 20 years as per regression model-based simulation. All the simulated models were validated with observed wetland area by kappa coefficient, receiver operating curve. The present study will definitely be useful for decision-makers by aiding them in initiatives that take a significant step toward maintaining the wetland landscape, as well as the environment.
WOS:000639851100007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="10">
<title>Machine learning-based mapping of micro-topographic earthquake-induced paleo-Pulju moraines and liquefaction spreads from a digital elevation model acquired through laser scanning</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2020.107099</url>
<snippet>The advent of public open source airborne laser scanning-produced digital elevationmodels (ALS DEM) has provided new perspectives on glacial geomorphology in the Nordic countries. Seismically-induced microtopographic paleo-landforms can now be identified and mapped throughout the former Fennoscandian Ice Sheet, allowing spatial safety assessment for nuclear waste disposal. Automated machine learning techniques enable recognition of these fine-scale geomorphological features efficiently and in a consistent way nationwide. The current study focuses on automated recognition of paleo-liquefaction spreads and Pulju moraines in northern Finland. Geomorphometric variables in different cell sizes were first derived from the 2 m ALS DEM by Gabor and principal curvature filtering to emphasize the elevational multi-scale texture of these paleo-seismic landforms. The Gabor textural variables were considered as a baseline method and the principal curvature features, including maximum and minimum curvature, were used because they have previously been proven critical in recognition of concave and convex elongated features. Both sets of raster variables were then turned into histogram-based features and input into a non-linear supervised multilayer perceptron early-stop committee which is a neural network classifier. The leave-one-out cross-validation performance results indicated principal curvature features to be highly successful with 94&#37; accuracy. Principal curvatures provided a clear improvement to Gabor based features which provided significantly lower accuracies between 83 and 85&#37;. The study demonstrates the high success of supervised neural network-based classification of ALS DEM data and derived textural features capturing the multi-scale nature of the micro-topographic liquefaction spreads and Pulju moraines. The approach could be utilized for time-efficient mapping of these paleo-seismic geomorphologies to complete paleo-seismic databases in formerly glaciated regions. (C) 2020 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000527307400011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="11">
<title>A novel hybrid based on nature-inspired and Stochastic Fractal Search algorithms for optimizing of artificial neural network model in landslide susceptibility</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.engappai.2022.105457</url>
<snippet>Today, meta-heuristic algorithms are becoming the techniques commonly used to discover adequately ap-propriate solutions for optimization problems. This investigation has suggested and compared three new hybrid techniques, i.e., Stochastic Fractal Search (SFS), Multi-verse optimizer (MVO), and combined with the traditional Artificial Neural Network in order to model susceptibility landslides in Kurdistan province, Iran. The factors related to landslides, i.e., slope aspect, elevation, NDVI, slope angle, plan curvature, distance to fault, rainfall, profile curvature, distance to road, distance from the river, STI, SPI, TWI, TRI, geology, and land use were included in the geographic information system (GIS). After obtaining the optimum structure of the multilayer perceptron neural network, stochastic fractal search and multi-verse optimizer algorithms were applied in order to enhance its efficiency. The maps of landslide susceptibility were created within a GIS environment, and the criterion of the area under the curve (AUC) was utilized to estimate the integrity of the predictive models employed. According to the results, after applying the above algorithms, the area under the curve significantly increased from 0.789 to 0.816 for SFS-MLP and in MVO-MLP from 0.755 to 0.808 in the training process. The AUC criterion was utilized to evaluate the accuracy of the probabilistic models that were put into use. Incidentally, the calculated comparable AUCs for the SFS-MLP testing databases and the obtained AUCs were 0.824, 0.817, 0.816, 0.814, 0.814, 0.807, 0.791, 0.789, 0.781, and 0.777, respectively and 0.811, 0.808, 0.800, 0.799, 0.798, 0.793, 0.784, 0.780, and 0.755 for the MVO-MLP. As a consequence, the findings demonstrated that these two models had incredibly effective capabilities for ANN-MLP optimization. Taking into consideration this evaluation, the hybrid models that were provided are trustworthy for the modeling of landslides.
WOS:000886931000005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="12">
<title>Landslide Segmentation with Deep Learning: Evaluating Model Generalization in Rainfall-Induced Landslides in Brazil</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/rs14092237</url>
<snippet>Automatic landslide mapping is crucial for a fast response in a disaster scenario and improving landslide susceptibility models. Recent studies highlighted the potential of deep learning methods for automatic landslide segmentation. However, only a few works discuss the generalization capacity of these models to segment landslides in areas that differ from the ones used to train the models. In this study, we evaluated three different locations to assess the generalization capacity of these models in areas with similar and different environmental aspects. The model training consisted of three distinct datasets created with RapidEye satellite images, Normalized Vegetation Index (NDVI), and a digital elevation model (DEM). Here, we show that larger patch sizes (128 x 128 and 256 x 256 pixels) favor the detection of landslides in areas similar to the training area, while models trained with smaller patch sizes (32 x 32 and 64 x 64 pixels) are better for landslide detection in areas with different environmental aspects. In addition, we found that the NDVI layer helped to balance the models results and that morphological post-processing operations are efficient for improving the segmentation precision results. Our research highlights the potential of deep learning models for segmenting landslides in different areas and is a starting point for more sophisticated investigations that evaluate model generalization in images from various sensors and resolutions.
WOS:000794859900001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="13">
<title>Sub-Pixel Mapping of Spectral Imagery Based on Deviation Information Measurement</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TIM.2023.3236318</url>
<snippet>Sub-pixel mapping (SPM) technology can analyze mixed pixels in spectral image and realize the transformation from abundance images to a fine sub-pixel classification image. Since the SPM belongs to an ill-posed issue, deviation information (DI) inevitably is in optimal abundance images. Due to simple structure and good robustness, most SPM approaches are according to the spatial dependence assumption; namely, the closer the spatial distance is, the more likely the subpixels belong to the same class. However, the existing SPM methods based on spatial dependence assumption cannot accurately measure the DI, which affects the accuracy of the final mapping result. To address this problem, the SPM based on DI measurement (DIM) is proposed in this work. The DIM uses a dual-scale spatial attraction model (DSAM) to process the coarse abundance images to obtain predicted abundance images. The fine prior images captured at different times from the same field of view are used to measure the deviation abundance images with the DI using a geographically weighted regression (GWR) model. The predicted abundance images and deviation abundance images are fused to derive optimal abundance images. Based on the proportion information on sub-pixels being classes in the optimal abundance images, the class labels are assigned to sub-pixels by label allocation method, yielding the final mapping result. The proposed DIM method is tested on National Land-cover Dataset, Rome Dataset, and Bastrop Fires dataset. The experimental results verify that the proposed DIM achieves the best performance with the overall accuracy of 97.26&#37;, 88.15&#37;, and 99.80&#37; in the three experimental results.
WOS:000922884900009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="14">
<title>High-Resolution Lidar-Derived DEM for Landslide Susceptibility Assessment Using AHP and Fuzzy Logic in Serdang, Malaysia</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/geosciences13020034</url>
<snippet>Landslide impact is potentially hazardous to an urban environment. Landslides occur at certain slope levels over time and require practical slope analysis to assess the nature of the slope where a landslide is likely to occur. Thus, acquiring very high-resolution remote sensing data plays a significant role in determining the slope surface. For this study, 12 landslide conditioning parameters with 10 x 10 cell sizes that have never been previously collectively applied were created. These factors were created directly from the LiDAR (Light Detection and Ranging) DEM (digital elevation model)using their layer toolboxes, which include slope, aspect, elevation, curvature, and hill shade. Stream power index (SPI), topographic wetness index (TWI), and terrain roughness index (TRI) were created from spatial layers such as slope, flow direction, and flow accumulation. Shapefiles of distances to roads, lakes, trees, and build-up were digitized as land use/cover from the LiDAR image and produced using the Euclidean distance method in ArcGIS. The parameters were selected based on expert knowledge, previous landslide literature, and the study area characteristics. Moreover, multicriteria decision-making analysis, which includes the analytic hierarchy process (AHP) and fuzzy logic approaches not previously utilized with a LiDAR DEM, was used in this study to predict the possibility of a landslide. The receiver operating characteristics (ROC) were used for the validation of results. The area under the curve (AUC) values obtained from the ROC method for the AHP and fuzzy were 0.859 and 0.802, respectively. The final susceptibility results will be helpful to urban developers in Malaysia and for sustainable landslide hazard mitigation.
WOS:000944959700001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="15">
<title>Flood susceptibility assessment using hybrid machine learning and remote sensing in Quang Tri province, Vietnam</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/tgis.12980</url>
<snippet>Flooding is the most dangerous of all environmental hazards and leads to significant impacts both on the environment and on human life. Environmental protection and water management can be achieved by modeling flood susceptibility, to inform strategy that will reduce flood damage. The aim of this study is to develop novel hybrid models based on a radial basis functions neural network (RBFNN), arithmetic optimization algorithm (AOA), artificial bee colony (ABC), and ant lion optimizer (ALO), to build flood susceptibility maps in the Quang Tri province of Vietnam. The obtained models were trained and validated using 1511 flood points and 14 conditioning factors. Various statistical indices were used to assess the performance of the models, namely root mean square error, receiver operation characteristics (ROC), area under the receiver operating characteristic curve (AUC), and the coefficient of determination (R-2). The comparison analysis highlights that the RBFNN-ABC model was better than other models with an AUC of 0.98, followed by RBFNN-AOA, support vector machine, and random forest, all with an AUC value of 0.96, and finally RBFNN-ALO, with an AUC of 0.95. From the flood susceptibility map, it can be seen that the eastern areas of the study area have high and very high flood susceptibility, that requires local government attention. The approach and results of this study can support national and local authorities, decision-makers, and other planners in the construction of appropriate strategies to reduce potential damage in the future.
WOS:000850502100001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="16">
<title>GIS-based landslide susceptibility assessment using optimized hybrid machine learning methods</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.catena.2020.104833</url>
<snippet>Globally, but especially in China, landslides are considered to be one of the most severe and significant natural hazards. In this study, bivariate statistical-based kernel logistic regression (KLR) models with different kernel functions (Polynomial, PUK, and Radial Basis Function), named the PLKLR, PUKLR, and RBFKLR models, were proposed for landslide susceptibility evaluation in Zichang City, China. Meanwhile, the present study aims to build landslide susceptibility maps based on bivariate statistical correlation analysis, optimization of different kernel functions, comparison of three landslide susceptibility maps and systematic analysis of spatial patterns. The steps of this article are organized as follows: Firstly, a landslide inventory containing 263 historical landslide locations was constructed. For the purpose of training and validation of models, 263 landslide locations were randomly divided into two parts with a ratio of 70/30. Secondly, 14 landslide conditioning factors were extracted from the spatial database. Subsequently, correlation analysis between the conditioning factors and the occurrence of landslides was conducted using frequency ratios. Then, the conditioning factors with normalized frequency ratios values were used as inputs to build the landslide susceptibility maps using the three models. A multicollinearity analysis was performed using collinearity statistics. Finally, the area under the receiver operating characteristic curve (AUC) was used for comparison and validation of models for recognizing the prediction capability. By further quantitative comparing mapped susceptibility values on a pixel-by-pixel basis, which can acquire underestimations and overestimations of factors (distance to river and slope) and susceptibility area. The results indicated that the PUKLR model had superior performance in landslide susceptibility assessment, with the highest AUC values of 0.884 and 0.766 for training and validation datasets, respectively. This model was followed by the RBFKLR model and the PLKLR model for the training datasets (AUC values of 0.879 and 0.797, respectively), and the PLKLR model and the RBFKLR model for the validation datasets (AUC values of 0.758 and 0.752, respectively). The landslide susceptibility map could help government agencies and decision-makers make wise decisions for future natural hazards prevention in Zichang region.
WOS:000583955200021
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="17">
<title>Susceptibility-Guided Landslide Detection Using Fully Convolutional Neural Network</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2022.3233043</url>
<snippet>Automatic landslide detection based on very high spatial resolution remote sensing images is crucial for disaster prevention and mitigation applications. With the rapid development of deep-learning techniques, state-of-the-art semantic segmentation methods based on fully convolutional network (FCNN) have achieved outstanding performance in the landslide detection task. However, most of the existing articles only utilize visual features. Even if the advanced FCNN models are applied, there is still a certain amount of falsely detected and miss detected landslides. In this article, we innovatively introduce landslide susceptibility as prior knowledge and propose an innovative susceptibility-guided landslide detection method based on FCNN (SG-FCNN) to detect landslides from single temporal images. In addition, an unsupervised change detection method based on the mean changing magnitude of objects (MCMO) is further proposed and integrated with the SG-FCNN to detect newly occurred landslides from bitemporal images. The effectiveness of the proposed SG-FCNN and MCMO has been tested in Lantau Island, Hong Kong. The experimental results show that the SG-FCNN can significantly reduce the amount of falsely detected and miss detected landslides compared with the FCNN. It can conclude that applying landslide susceptibility as prior knowledge is much more effective than using visual features only, which introduces a new methodology of landslide detection and lifts the detection performance to a new level.
WOS:000912413700004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="18">
<title>Swarm-based optimizer for convolutional neural network: An application for flood susceptibility mapping</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1111/tgis.12715</url>
<snippet>This article investigates the use of the galactic swarm optimization algorithm in searching for parameters of a convolutional neural network for flood susceptibility mapping. Ha Giang province, the mountainous area of Vietnam, was chosen as a case study because of the frequent occurrence of floods. From this study area, 11 predictor variables and historical flood locations were selected to build up the training datasets, in which each sample is prepared in the 3D form of (height x width x channels or variables) = (5 x 5 x 11), (7 x 7 x 11), and (9 x 9 x 11), respectively for three experiments. The model performance was assessed by root mean square error, area under the receiver operating characteristic (AUC), and overall accuracy (OA). The results showed that the examined model significantly improved the classification accuracies: OA = 83.093, AUC = 0.917; OA = 83.726, AUC = 0.923; and OA = 82.791, AUC = 0.908 for the three training datasets in comparison to benchmarked classifiers, and this model can be considered as an alternative solution for flood susceptibility mapping.
WOS:000594737600001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="19">
<title>Deep Learning of High-Resolution Aerial Imagery for Coastal Marsh Change Detection: A Comparative Study</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijgi11020100</url>
<snippet>Deep learning techniques are increasingly being recognized as effective image classifiers. Aside from their successful performance in past studies, the accuracies have varied in complex environments, in comparison with the popularly of applied machine learning classifiers. This study seeks to explore the feasibility of using a U-Net deep learning architecture to classify bi-temporal, high-resolution, county-scale aerial images to determine the spatial extent and changes of land cover classes that directly or indirectly impact tidal marsh. The image set used in the analysis is a collection of a 1-m resolution collection of National Agriculture Imagery Program (NAIP) tiles from 2009 and 2019, covering Beaufort County, South Carolina. The U-Net CNN classification results were compared with two machine learning classifiers, the random trees (RT) and support vector machine (SVM). The results revealed a significant accuracy advantage in using the U-Net classifier (92.4&#37;), as opposed to the SVM (81.6&#37;) and RT (75.7&#37;) classifiers, for overall accuracy. From the perspective of a GIS analyst or coastal manager, the U-Net classifier is now an easily accessible and powerful tool for mapping large areas. Change detection analysis indicated little areal change on marsh extent, though increased land development throughout the county has the potential to negatively impact the health of the marshes. Future work should explore applying the constructed U-Net classifier to coastal environments in large geographic areas, while also implementing other data sources (e.g., LIDAR and multispectral data) to enhance classification accuracy.
WOS:000767289900001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="20">
<title>A Research on Susceptibility Mapping of Multiple Geological Hazards in Yanzi River Basin, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijgi10040218</url>
<snippet>Collapses, landslides, and debris flows are the main geological hazards faced by mankind, which bring heavy losses of life and property to people every year. The purpose of this paper is to establish a method for determining the optimal weighting scheme for multiple geological hazard susceptibility mapping. The information gain ratio (IGR) method was used to analyze the predictive ability of the conditioning factors. The support vector machine (SVM) algorithm was used to evaluate the susceptibility to collapse, landslide, and debris flow of the study area. The receiver operating characteristic curves (ROC) and classification statistics of geological hazard samples were applied to evaluate the performance of the models. The analytic hierarchy process (AHP) and frequency ratio (FR) method were combined to determine the optimal weighting scheme for collapse, landslide, and debris flow. All the conditioning factors have shown a certain predictive ability, making the models of collapse, landslide, and debris flow achieve very good performance. The multiple geological hazard susceptibility maps with the weights of 0.297, 0.539, and 0.164 for collapse, landslide, and debris flow was optimal for this study area with high-precision classification of all the geological hazard samples. The conclusions of this paper could provide meaningful references for risk migration and land use in the study area.
WOS:000643074500001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="21">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping along the China Pakistan Economic Corridor (CPEC) route using multi-criteria decision-making method</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s40808-021-01226-0</url>
<snippet>This study maps the landslide susceptibility along the China-Pakistan Economic Corridor (CPEC) route using multiple landslide causative factors. A decisive statistical approach and the Geographic Information System (GIS) were used to map the routes susceptibility. The study area comprises a 236 km section of the Karakoram Highway, located in a region subjected to repeated landslides. The maps of different causative factors, including topographical, geological, and hydrological factors, were generated through GIS using data obtained from various sources. The causative factors were weighted according to their potential for developing a landslide event in a pairwise matrix of a multi-criteria decision-making approach. The analytical hierarchy process was applied to get the Consistency Index that governed the whole rating process. The weights of the landslide causative factors were used for generating the study areas final landslide susceptibility map. The results indicated that about 38&#37; of the study area falls under the category of high and very high susceptibility. The outcomes of this study could be valuable in the identification of the parameters at a given area or region that are more prominently influencing the happening of landslides, in this way permitting the more viable preventive measures to be taken.
WOS:000668423600001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="22">
<title>Spatial landslide susceptibility assessment using machine learning techniques assisted by additional data created with generative adversarial networks</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.gsf.2020.09.002</url>
<snippet>In recent years, landslide susceptibility mapping has substantially improved with advances in machine learning. However, there are still challenges remain in landslide mapping due to the availability of limited inventory data. In this paper, a novel method that improves the performance of machine learning techniques is presented. The proposed method creates synthetic inventory data using Generative Adversarial Networks (GANs) for improving the prediction of landslides. In this research, landslide inventory data of 156 landslide locations were identified in Cameron Highlands, Malaysia, taken from previous projects the authors worked on. Elevation, slope, aspect, plan curvature, profile curvature, total curvature, lithology, land use and land cover (LULC), distance to the road, distance to the river, stream power index (SPI), sediment transport index (STI), terrain roughness index (TRI), topographic wetness index (TWI) and vegetation density are geo-environmental factors considered in this study based on suggestions from previous works on Cameron Highlands. To show the capability of GANs in improving landslide prediction models, this study tests the proposed GAN model with benchmark models namely Artificial Neural Network (ANN), Support Vector Machine (SVM), Decision Trees (DT), Random Forest (RF) and Bagging ensemble models with ANN and SVM models. These models were validated using the area under the receiver operating characteristic curve (AUROC). The DT, RF, SVM, ANN and Bagging ensemble could achieve the AUROC values of (0.90, 0.94, 0.86, 0.69 and 0.82) for the training; and the AUROC of (0.76, 0.81, 0.85, 0.72 and 0.75) for the test, subsequently. When using additional samples, the same models achieved the AUROC values of (0.92, 0.94, 0.88, 0.75 and 0.84) for the training and (0.78, 0.82, 0.82, 0.78 and 0.80) for the test, respectively. Using the additional samples improved the test accuracy of all the models except SVM. As a result, in data-scarce environments, this research showed that utilizing GANs to generate supplementary samples is promising because it can improve the predictive capability of common landslide prediction models.
WOS:000611950300009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="23">
<title>Application of genetic algorithm in optimization parallel ensemble-based machine learning algorithms to flood susceptibility mapping using radar satellite imagery</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2023.162285</url>
<snippet>Floods are the natural disaster that occurs most frequently due to the weather and causes the most widespread destruc-tion. The purpose of the proposed research is to analyze flood susceptibility mapping (FSM) in the Sulaymaniyah prov-ince of Iraq. This study employed a genetic algorithm (GA) to fine-tune parallel ensemble-based machine learning algorithms (random forest (RF) and bootstrap aggregation (Bagging)). Four machine learning algorithms (RF, Bagging, RF-GA, and Bagging-GA) were used to build FSM in the study area. To provide inputs into parallel ensemble-based ma-chine learning algorithms, we gathered and processed data from meteorological (Rainfall), satellite image (flood in-ventory, normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI), aspect, land cover, altitude, stream power index (SPI), plan curvature, topographic wetness index (TWI), slope) and geographic sources (geology). For this research, Sentinel-1 synthetic aperture radar (SAR) satellite images were utilized to locate flooded areas and create an inventory map of floods. To train and validate the model, we employed 70 &#37; and 30 &#37; of 160 selected flood locations, respectively. Mul-ticollinearity, frequency ratio (FR), and Geodetector methods were used for data preprocessing. Four metrics were uti-lized to assess the FSM performance: the root mean square error (RMSE), the area under the receiver-operator characteristic curve (AUC-ROC), the Taylor diagram, and the seed cell area index (SCAI). The results exhibited that all the suggested models have high accuracy of prediction, but the performance of Bagging-GA (RMSE (Train = 0.1793, Test = 0.4543)) was slightly better than RF-GA (RMSE (Train = 0.1803, Test = 0.4563)), Bagging (RMSE (Train = 0.2191, Test = 0.4566)), and RF (RMSE (Train = 0.2529, Test = 0.4724)). According to the ROC index, the Bagging-GA model (AUC = 0.935) was the most accurate in flood susceptibility modeling, followed by the RF-GA (AUC = 0.904), the Bagging (AUC = 0.872), and the RF (AUC = 0.847) models. The studys identification of high -risk flood zones and the most significant factors contributing to flooding make it a helpful resource for flood manage-ment.
WOS:000953270400001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="24">
<title>Forest Fire Susceptibility and Risk Mapping Using Social/Infrastructural Vulnerability and Environmental Variables</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/fire2030050</url>
<snippet>Forests fires in northern Iran have always been common, but the number of forest fires has been growing over the last decade. It is believed, but not proven, that this growth can be attributed to the increasing temperatures and droughts. In general, the vulnerability to forest fire depends on infrastructural and social factors whereby the latter determine where and to what extent people and their properties are affected. In this paper, a forest fire susceptibility index and a social/infrastructural vulnerability index were developed using a machine learning (ML) method and a geographic information system multi-criteria decision making (GIS-MCDM), respectively. First, a forest fire inventory database was created from an extensive field survey and the moderate resolution imaging spectroradiometer (MODIS) thermal anomalies product for 2012 to 2017. A forest fire susceptibility map was generated using 16 environmental variables and a k-fold cross-validation (CV) approach. The infrastructural vulnerability index was derived with emphasis on different types of construction and land use, such as residential, industrial, and recreation areas. This dataset also incorporated social vulnerability indicators, e.g., population, age, gender, and family information. Then, GIS-MCDM was used to assess risk areas considering the forest fire susceptibility and the social/infrastructural vulnerability maps. As a result, most high fire susceptibility areas exhibit minor social/infrastructural vulnerability. The resulting forest fire risk map reveals that 729.61 ha, which is almost 1.14&#37; of the study areas, is categorized in the high forest fire risk class. The methodology is transferable to other regions by localisation of the input data and the social indicators and contributes to forest fire mitigation and prevention planning.
WOS:000697566600014
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="25">
<title>Transition Is a Process: Pair-to-Video Change Detection Networks for Very High Resolution Remote Sensing Images</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TIP.2022.3226418</url>
<snippet>As an important yet challenging task in Earth observation, change detection (CD) is undergoing a technological revolution, given the broadening application of deep learning. Nevertheless, existing deep learning-based CD methods still suffer from two salient issues: 1) incomplete temporal modeling, and 2) space-time coupling. In view of these issues, we propose a more explicit and sophisticated modeling of time and accordingly establish a pair-to-video change detection (P2V-CD) framework. First, a pseudo transition video that carries rich temporal information is constructed from the input image pair, interpreting CD as a problem of video understanding. Then, two decoupled encoders are utilized to spatially and temporally recognize the type of transition, and the encoders are laterally connected for mutual promotion. Furthermore, the deep supervision technique is applied to accelerate the model training. We illustrate experimentally that the P2V-CD method compares favorably to other state-of-the-art CD approaches in terms of both the visual effect and the evaluation metrics, with a moderate model size and relatively lower computational overhead. Extensive feature map visualization experiments demonstrate how our method works beyond making contrasts between bi-temporal images. Source code is available at https://github.com/Bobholamovic/CDLab.
WOS:000902111900005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="26">
<title>Current and Future Status of GIS-based Landslide Susceptibility Mapping: A Literature Review</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.7780/kjrs.2019.35.1.12</url>
<snippet>Landslides are one of the most damaging geological hazards worldwide, threating both humans and property. Hence, there have been many efforts to prevent landslides and mitigate the damage that they cause. Among such efforts, there have been many studies on mapping landslide susceptibility. Geographic information system (GIS)-based techniques have been developed and applied widely, and are now the main tools used to map landslide susceptibility. We reviewed the status of landslide susceptibility mapping using GIS by number of papers, year, study area, number of landslides, cause, and models applied, based on 776 articles over the last 20 years (19992018). The number of studies published annually increased rapidly over time. The total study area spanned 65 countries, and 47.7&#37; of study areas were in China, India, South Korea, and Iran, where more than 500 landslides, 27.3&#37; of all landslides, have occurred. Slope (97.6&#37; of total articles) and geology (82.7&#37; of total articles) were most often implicated as causes, and logistic regression (26.9&#37; of total articles) and frequency ratio (24.7&#37; of total article) models were the most widely used models. We analyzed trends in the causes of and models used to simulate landslides. The main causes were similar each year, but machine learning models have increased in popularity over time. In the future, more study areas should be investigated to improve the generalizability and accuracy of the results. Furthermore, more causes, especially those related to topography and soil, should be considered and more machine learning models should be applied. Finally, landslide hazard and risk maps should be studied in addition to landslide susceptibility maps.
WOS:000460062500012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="27">
<title>A comparison of the integrated fuzzy object-based deep learning approach and three machine learning techniques for land use/cover change monitoring and environmental impacts assessment</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/15481603.2021.2000350</url>
<snippet>Recent improvements in the spatial, temporal, and spectral resolution of satellite images necessitate (semi-)automated classification and information extraction approaches. Therefore, we developed an integrated fuzzy object-based image analysis and deep learning (FOBIA-DL) approach for monitoring the land use/cover (LULC) and respective changes and compared it to three machine learning (ML) algorithms, namely the support vector machine (SVM), random forest (RF), and classification and regression tree (CART). We investigated LULC impacts on drought by analyzing Landsat satellite images from 1990 to 2020 for the Urmia Lake area in northern Iran. In the FOBIA-DL approach, following the initial segmentation steps, object features were identified for each LULC class. We then derived their respective attributes using fuzzy membership functions and deep convolutional neural networks (DCNNs), a deep learning method. The Fuzzy Synthetic Evaluation and Dempster-Shafer Theory (FSE-DST) also applied to validate and carryout the spatial uncertainties. Our results indicate that the FOBIA-DL, with an accuracy of 90.1&#37; to 96.4&#37; and a spatial certainty of 0.93 to 0.97, outperformed the other approaches, closely followed by the SVM. Our results also showed that the integration of Fuzzy-OBIA and DCNNs could improve the strength and robustness of the OBIAs decision rules, while the FSE-DST approach notably improved the spatial accuracy of the object-based classification maps. While object-based image analysis (OBIA) is already considered a paradigm shift in GIScience, the integration of OBIA with fuzzy and deep learning creates more flexibility and robust OBIA decision rules for image analysis and classification. This research integrated popular data-driven approaches and developed a novel methodology for image classification and spatial accuracy assessment. From the environmental perspective, the results of this research support lake restoration initiatives by decision-makers and authorities in applications such as drought mitigation, land use management and precision agriculture programs.
WOS:000724069000001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="28">
<title>Use of Mamdani Fuzzy Algorithm for Multi-Hazard Susceptibility Assessment in a Developing Urban Settlement (Mamak, Ankara, Turkey)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijgi9020114</url>
<snippet>Urban areas may be affected by multiple hazards, and integrated hazard susceptibility maps are needed for suitable site selection and planning. Furthermore, geological-geotechnical parameters, construction costs, and the spatial distribution of existing infrastructure should be taken into account for this purpose. Up-to-date land-use and land-cover (LULC) maps, as well as natural hazard susceptibility maps, can be frequently obtained from high-resolution satellite sensors. In this study, an integrated hazard susceptibility assessment was performed for a developing urban settlement (Mamak District of Ankara City, Turkey) considering landslide and flood potential. The flood susceptibility map of Ankara City was produced in a previous study using modified analytical hierarchical process (M-AHP) approach. The landslide susceptibility map was produced using the logistic regression technique in this study. Sentinel-2 images were employed for generating LULC data with the random forest classification method. Topographical derivatives obtained from a high-resolution digital elevation model and lithological parameters were employed for the production of landslide susceptibility maps. For the integrated hazard susceptibility assessment, the Mamdani fuzzy algorithm was considered, and the results are discussed in the present study. The results demonstrate that multi-hazard susceptibility assessment maps for urban planning can be obtained by combining a set of expert-based and ensemble learning methods.
WOS:000522449700054
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="29">
<title>Evaluation of machine learning-based algorithms for landslide detection across satellite sensors for the 2019 Cyclone Idai event, Chimanimani District, Zimbabwe</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10346-022-01912-9</url>
<snippet>Changes in climatic patterns, manifested as intensified cyclones and torrential rainfalls in a warming world will inevitably impact the frequency of landslides. One such climatic extreme, Cyclone Idai (March 2019), caused significant havoc across southeastern Africa, including Mozambique, Malawi, and eastern Zimbabwe, by triggering thousands of landslides and widespread concurrent flooding, both of which resulted in substantial loss of life. The study was conducted in the Chimanimani District of eastern Zimbabwe to understand the impact of Cyclone Idai on landslide initiation, quantify the volume of mobilized hillslope material during the event, and compare the event-triggered material release against the annual erosional yield across the study area using machine learning and remote sensing techniques. We evaluated satellite imagery of various resolutions, namely, PlanetScope (3m/px),RapidEye (5m/px), and Sentinel-2 (tom/px) and three machine learning algorithms: artificial neural network (ANN), random forest (RF), and support vector machine (SVM) to identify landslides and compared the efficacy of the models. A total of nine predictor variables derived from the satellite imagery and a 3o-m ASTER Global Digital Elevation Model were employed to identify landslides and differentiate them from concurrent hydrological flooding. The models classified the study area into three classes: (i) landslides, (ii) flooding, and (iii) unaffected area. The RF model using PlanetScope satellite data attained the highest prediction accuracy of 97.88&#37;, whereas the accuracy of other machine learning model-satellite data combinations ranged between 94.58 and 97.27&#37;. Subsequently, landslide size thresholds were applied on the initially mapped landslides to eliminate noise and uncertainty from the data before estimating the final Cyclone Idai event-triggered landslide volume. A probability density function, which corresponds to a logarithmic plot of non-cumulative landslide frequency against the mapped landslide area, was employed to calculate landslide size thresholds using divergence and rollover point cutoff values. Finally, a landslide area-to-volume power-law scaling relationship was exploited to derive landslide volumes in the study area that ranged between 6.8 x 10(6) to 14.7 x 10(6) m(3) and 9.0 x 10(6) to 19.6 x 10(6) m(3) for divergence and rollover point thresholds, respectively, across the different combinations of machine learning models and satellite sensors. The estimated landslide volume indicates hillslope material liberated by Cyclone Idai was 269 to 345 times greater than the estimated annual average background denudation of the study area computed from a topography-based local erosion model.
WOS:000840286800001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="30">
<title>Assessment of Landslide Susceptibility Combining Deep Learning with Semi-Supervised Learning in Jiaohe County, Jilin Province, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/app10165640</url>
<snippet>Accurate and timely landslide susceptibility mapping (LSM) is essential to effectively reduce the risk of landslide. In recent years, deep learning has been successfully applied to landslide susceptibility assessment due to the strong ability of fitting. However, in actual applications, the number of labeled samples is usually not sufficient for the training component. In this paper, a deep neural network model based on semi-supervised learning (SSL-DNN) for landslide susceptibility is proposed, which makes full use of a large number of spatial information (unlabeled data) with limited labeled data in the region to train the mode. Taking Jiaohe County in Jilin Province, China as an example, the landslide inventory from 2000 to 2017 was collected and 12 metrological, geographical, and human explanatory factors were compiled. Meanwhile, supervised models such as deep neural network (DNN), support vector machine (SVM), and logistic regression (LR) were implemented for comparison. Then, the landslide susceptibility was plotted and a series of evaluation tools such as class accuracy, predictive rate curves (AUC), and information gain ratio (IGR) were calculated to compare the prediction of models and factors. Experimental results indicate that the proposed SSL-DNN model (AUC = 0.898) outperformed all the comparison models. Therefore, semi-supervised deep learning could be considered as a potential approach for LSM.
WOS:000564644700001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="31">
<title>Application of convolutional neural networks based on Bayesian optimization to landslide susceptibility mapping of transmission tower foundation</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10064-023-03069-8</url>
<snippet>The stability of tower foundation slopes is an important factor to maintain the operation of a power system. However, it is time-consuming and expensive to evaluate tower foundation slopes one by one due to the large area. The aim of this study is to investigate the performance of CNNs with different architectures and training options for transmission tower foundation landslide spatial prediction (LSP) by Bayesian optimization. Accordingly, fourteen influencing factors related to landslide evaluated by gain ratio technique are considered and 424 historical landslide locations in Luoding and Xinyi Counties (Guangdong Province, China) are randomly divided into 80&#37; for training and 20&#37; for testing the CNNs. The CNN performances are investigated by permutating and combining different numbers of convolutional layers, pooling layers and learning rate strategy. In 59 Bayesian optimized cases, three conclusions are drawn: (a) the CNNs yielded the best result with 3 convolution layers, (b) the CNN without a pooling layer performs best, and 
WOS:000914933900001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="32">
<title>Flood susceptible prediction through the use of geospatial variables and machine learning methods</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jhydrol.2023.129121</url>
<snippet>Floods are one of the most perilous natural calamities that cause property destruction and endanger human life. The spatial patterns of flood susceptibility were assessed in this study using six applied machine learning (ML) models including Decision Tree (DT), Random Forest (RF), Multilayer Perceptron Neural Network (MLP-NN), Adaptive Boosting (AdaBoost), Logistic Regression (LR), and Support Vector Machines (SVM). A flood inventory map was provided using 180 flood points and 180 non-flood points. Both flood and non-flood locations were randomly partitioned into training and testing datasets with the ratio of 70:30. Sixteen various meteorological, hydrological, and geospatial variables were considered in the flood susceptibility assessment. The multi-collinearity analysis was performed to measure the intensity of correlations between the variables and deter-mine whether factors can be included in the flood susceptibility assessment. From a total of sixteen variables, thirteen were chosen based on the multi-collinearity study. The five statistical indices Receiver Operating Characteristics curve (ROC), Jaccard index, F1 score, Overall Accuracy (OA), and Kappa coefficient (K) were used to evaluate models performance. Regarding the results of accuracy criteria, the RF model had the best predictive potential. Flood conditioning factors were reclassified using Quantile classification method and the importance of each class from a given flood conditioning factor was evaluated using the Frequency Ratio (FR) method. Additionally, the spatial relationship between the flood conditioning factors and the flood susceptibility map was investigated using the correlation matrix based on the Spearman correlation analysis. Findings of the correlation matrix revealed that the most important flood conditioning factors, in order of importance, were lithology, drainage density, distance from rivers, soil, rainfall, land cover, and Normalized Difference Moisture Index (NDMI). The flood susceptibility map, as the principal output of this study, was produced in five classes ranging from very low to very high susceptibility. The flood susceptibility map provided using the RF model (i.e., the model with the highest accuracy) indicated that the flood susceptibility is very high in 19.73&#37; of the study area, high in 15.49&#37;, moderate in 16.15&#37;, low in 18.72&#37;, and very low in 29.91&#37;. Findings of this research might be an invaluable resource for better management of flooding since it specifically emphasized the primary causes of flooding as well as locations of heightened flood susceptibility.
WOS:000931437600001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="33">
<title>GIS-based landslide susceptibility mapping using ensemble methods for Fengjie County in the Three Gorges Reservoir Region, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s13762-021-03572-z</url>
<snippet>Various landslide susceptibility models can be available in the literature, and each model has its unique advantages and limitations. Previous studies have shown that no single model performs best across diverse geoenvironmental conditions. To seek better prediction accuracy and reliability, this study proposes three different ensemble methods to take advantage of multiple landslide susceptibility models: qualitative matrix ensemble method, semi-quantitative partition ensemble method, and quantitative probability-weighted ensemble method. To illustrate the effectiveness of the three ensemble methods proposed, a case study is carried out in Fengjie County in the Three Gorges Reservoir Region, China. First, with the support of geographic information system, a total of 1550 historical landslides and the associated 12 conditioning factors are compiled, which are used for the training and validation of four selected single landslide susceptibility models, including two statistical approaches (i.e. frequency ratio and fuzzy assessment) and two machine learning approaches (i.e. backpropagation neural network and support vector machine). Then, the three ensemble methods are applied to integrate the outcomes of the four single models. Finally, an extensive comparative analysis is performed between the ensemble methods and single models using the receiver operating characteristics curve and information entropy. The results demonstrate that all the three ensemble methods achieve higher overall prediction accuracy (&gt; 80&#37;) than the four single models (&lt; 80&#37;), and the matrix ensemble method provides the best improvement. Besides, the ensemble methods can also enhance reliability by reducing the statistical discrepancy between distinct single models.
WOS:000680794800001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="34">
<title>Geospatial modeling using hybrid machine learning approach for flood susceptibility</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12145-022-00872-x</url>
<snippet>Advanced methods for flood susceptibility mapping are required to minimize hazards in the watershed. Here, Partial Least Square-Structural Equation Model (PLS-SEM) was introduced to analyze the impact of flood influencing factors. PLS-SEM integrated with four Machine Learning (ML) methods as Multi-Layer Perceptron Neural Network (MLPNN), K Nearest Neighbor (KNN), Support Vector Machine (SVM) and Radial Basis Function Neural network (RBFN). In addition, significant flood influencing factors from PLS-SEM analysis was taken as the input of ML models. Then SVM, MLPNN, KNN, and RBFN integrated with the PLS-SEM classifier to develop hybrid models for constructing FSM. The performance of models is assessed in terms of standard statistical methods. The performance of the achieved model is good having AUROC &gt; 0.8 and PLS-SEM-SVM (AUROC = 0.978) perform superior than others. Thus, hybrid SVM model can be best utilized for flood susceptibility. This study provides the importance of mechanism for flood influencing factors and extends the application of proposed hybrid ML models to minimize flood risk.
WOS:000864530900001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="35">
<title>Deep learning and benchmark machine learning based landslide susceptibility investigation, Garhwal Himalaya (India)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.qsa.2023.100075</url>
<snippet>Garhwal Himalaya is the worst affected landslide prone region in Indian subcontinent mainly due to its complex geological settings and active tectonic activities. The data showed that every year, around 400 fatalities occur in Himalayan terrain due to landslide. In the current study, we have mapped the landslide susceptibility zones in the segment of Garhwal Himalaya using robust machine and deep learning algorithms. Individual machine and deep learning models have its own limitations like low generation capacity with nonlinear functions to describe the intricate relationship among predictors. In this study total five models i.e., SVM (Support Vector Machine), RF (Random Forest), bagging, ANN (Artificial Neural Network), DLNN (Deep Learning Neural Network) have been used along with twenty landslide controlling factors. Here, the principal objective of the study is to precisely delineate landslide susceptibility zones of the Garhwal Himalaya. The selecting factors have been considered through multi-collinearity test and information gain ratio statistics and the previous landslide points have been taken as training (70&#37;) and testing (30&#37;) dataset. According to area under curve value (AUC), the DLNN technique has high capability (AUC = 0.925) and accuracy for landslide area demarcation. The approach of integrated physical and social factors creates more precise prediction aptitude that can support large scale landslide management. These high precision models identified most of the parts of Rudraprayag and Tehri Garhwal as a very high landslide susceptibility zone. The generated maps can assist to policy makers for micro scale landslide management and sustainable land use planning particularly in Himalayan terrain.
WOS:000953558800001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="36">
<title>Spatial prediction of shallow landslide using Bat algorithm optimized machine learning approach: A case study in Lang Son Province, Vietnam</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.aei.2019.100978</url>
<snippet>This study develops a machine learning method that hybridizes the Least Squares Support Vector Classification (LSSVC) and Bat Algorithm (BA), named as BA-LSSVC, for spatial prediction of shallow landslide. To construct and verify the hybrid method, a Geographic Information System (GIS) database for the study area of Lang Son province (Vietnam) has been employed. LSSVC is used to separate data samples in the GIS database into two categories of non-landslide (negative class) and landslide (positive class). The BA metaheuristic is employed to assist the LSSVC model selection process by fine-tuning its hyper-parameters: the regularization coefficient and the kernel function parameter. Experimental results point out that the hybrid BA-LSSVC can help to achieve a desired prediction with an accuracy rate of more than 90&#37;. The performance of BA-LSSVC is also better than those of benchmark methods, including the Convolutional Neural Network, Relevance Vector Machine, Artificial Neural Network, and Logistic Regression. Hence, the newly developed model is a capable tool to assist local authority in landslide hazard mitigation and management.
WOS:000501389000046
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="37">
<title>AI-Based Susceptibility Analysis of Shallow Landslides Induced by Heavy Rainfall in Tianshui, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/rs13091819</url>
<snippet>Groups of landslides induced by heavy rainfall are widely distributed on a global basis and they usually result in major losses of human life and economic damage. However, compared with landslides induced by earthquakes, inventories of landslides induced by heavy rainfall are much less common. In this study we used high-precision remote sensing images before and after continuous heavy rainfall in southern Tianshui, China, from 20 June to 25 July 2013, to produce an inventory of 14,397 shallow landslides. Based on the results of landslide inventory, we utilized machine learning and the geographic information system (GIS) to map landslide susceptibility in this area and evaluated the relative weight of various factors affecting landslide development. First, 18 variables related to geomorphic conditions, slope material, geological conditions, and human activities were selected through collinearity analysis; second, 21 selected machine learning models were trained and optimized in the Python environment to evaluate the susceptibility of landslides. The results showed that the ExtraTrees model was the most effective for landslide susceptibility assessment, with an accuracy of 0.91. This predictive ability means that our landslide susceptibility results can be used in the implementation of landslide prevention and mitigation measures in the region. Analysis of the importance of the factors showed that the contribution of slope aspect (SA) was significantly higher than that of the other factors, followed by planar curvature (PLC), distance to river (DR), distance to fault (DTF), normalized difference vehicle index (NDVI), distance to road (DTR), and other factors. We conclude that factors related to geomorphic conditions are principally responsible for controlling landslide susceptibility in the study area.
WOS:000650738500001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="38">
<title>Location-allocation modeling for emergency evacuation planning with GIS and remote sensing: A case study of Northeast Bangladesh</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.gsf.2020.09.022</url>
<snippet>This work developed models to identify optimal spatial distribution of emergency evacuation centers (EECs) such as schools, colleges, hospitals, and fire stations to improve flood emergency planning in the Sylhet region of northeastern Bangladesh. The use of location-allocation models (LAMs) for evacuation in regard to flood victims is essential to minimize disaster risk. In the first step, flood susceptibility maps were developed using machine learning models (MLMs), including: Levenberg-Marquardt back propagation (LM-BP) neural network and decision trees (DT) and multi-criteria decision making (MCDM) method. Performance of the MLMs and MCDM techniques were assessed considering the area under the receiver operating characteristic (AUROC) curve. Mathematical approaches in a geographic information system(GIS) for four well-known LAM problems affecting emergency rescue time are proposed: maximal covering location problem (MCLP), the maximize attendance (MA), p-median problem (PMP), and the location set covering problem(LSCP). The results showed that existing EECs were not optimally distributed, and that some areas were not adequately served by EECs (i.e., not all demand points could be reached within a 60-min travel time). We concluded that the proposed models can be used to improve planning of the distribution of EECs, and that application of the models could contribute to reducing human casualties, property losses, and improve emergency operation. (C) 2021 ChinaUniversity of Geosciences (Beijing) and Peking University. Production and hosting by Elsevier B.V.
WOS:000636463500013
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="39">
<title>Landslide Susceptibility Assessment Using an Optimized Group Method of Data Handling Model</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijgi9100566</url>
<snippet>Landslides can cause considerable loss of life and damage to property, and are among the most frequent natural hazards worldwide. One of the most fundamental and simple approaches to reduce damage is to prepare a landslide hazard map. Accurate prediction of areas highly prone to future landslides is important for decision-making. In the present study, for the first time, the group method of data handling (GMDH) was used to generate landslide susceptibility map for a specific region in Uzbekistan. First, 210 landslide locations were identified by field survey and then divided randomly into model training and model validation datasets (70&#37; and 30&#37;, respectively). Data on nine conditioning factors, i.e., altitude, slope, aspect, topographic wetness index (TWI), length of slope (LS), valley depth, distance from roads, distance from rivers, and geology, were collected. Finally, the maps were validated using the testing dataset and receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve analysis. The findings showed that the "optimized" GMDH model (i.e., using the gray wolf optimizer [GWO]) performed better than the standalone GMDH model, during both the training and testing phase. The accuracy of the GMDH-GWO model in the training and testing phases was 94&#37; and 90&#37;, compared to 85&#37; and 82&#37;, respectively, for the standard GMDH model. According to the GMDH-GWO model, the study area included very low, low, moderate, high, and very high landslide susceptibility areas, with proportions of 14.89&#37;, 10.57&#37;, 15.00&#37;, 35.12&#37;, and 24.43&#37;, respectively.
WOS:000586864100001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="40">
<title>Breaking Limits of Remote Sensing by Deep Learning From Simulated Data for Flood and Debris-Flow Mapping</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/TGRS.2020.3035469</url>
<snippet>We propose a framework that estimates the inundation depth (maximum water level) and debris-flow-induced topographic deformation from remote sensing imagery by integrating deep learning and numerical simulation. A water and debris-flow simulator generates training data for various artificial disaster scenarios. We show that regression models based on Attention U-Net and LinkNet architectures trained on such synthetic data can predict the maximum water level and topographic deformation from a remote sensing-derived change detection map and a digital elevation model. The proposed framework has an inpainting capability, thus mitigating the false negatives that are inevitable in remote sensing image analysis. Our framework breaks limits of remote sensing and enables rapid estimation of inundation depth and topographic deformation, essential information for emergency response, including rescue and relief activities. We conduct experiments with both synthetic and real data for two disaster events that caused simultaneous flooding and debris flows and demonstrate the effectiveness of our approach quantitatively and qualitatively. Our code and data sets are available at https://github.com/nyokoya/dlsim.
WOS:000726094900004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="41">
<title>Landslide susceptibility zonation using statistical and machine learning approaches in Northern Lecco, Italy</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-021-05083-z</url>
<snippet>This study deals with landslide susceptibility mapping in the northern part of Lecco Province, Lombardy Region, Italy. In so doing, a valid landslide inventory map and thirteen predisposing factors (including elevation, slope aspect, slope degree, plan curvature, profile curvature, distance to waterway, distance to road, distance to fault, soil type, land use, lithology, stream power index, and topographic wetness index) form the spatial database within geographic information system. The used predictive models comprise a bivariate statistical approach called frequency ratio (FR) and two machine learning tools, namely multilayer perceptron neural network (MLPNN) and adaptive neuro-fuzzy inference system (ANFIS). These models first use landslide and non-landslide records for comprehending the relationship between the landslide occurrence and predisposing factors. Then, landslide susceptibility values are predicted for the whole area. The accuracy of the produced susceptibility maps is measured using area under the curve (AUC) index, according to which, the MLPNN (AUC = 0.916) presented the most accurate map, followed by the ANFIS (AUC = 0.889) and FR (AUC = 0.888). Visual interpretation of the susceptibility maps, FR-based correlation analysis, as well as the importance assessment of predisposing factors, all indicated the significant contribution of the road networks to the crucial susceptibility of landslide. Lastly, an explicit predictive formula is extracted from the implemented MLPNN model for a convenient approximation of landslide susceptibility value.
WOS:000716901600001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="42">
<title>A Subpixel Mapping Method for Urban Land Use by Reducing Shadow Effects</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2023.3243895</url>
<snippet>Urban land use classification is significant for urban development planning. Considering complex environments of urban surface features, traditional semantic segmentation methods are difficult to solve the problems of mixed pixels and limited spatial resolution of images. The subpixel mapping technology is an effective method to solve the above problems in urban land use classification. However, traditional subpixel mapping methods are sensitive to mountain shadow, high-rise building shadow and impermeable surface heterogeneity, resulting in false classification. Therefore, we propose a subpixel mapping method that can reduce the shadow effect. This method uses a multi-index feature fusion strategy to optimize the abundance of the shadow errors in the abundance image, and uses a super-resolution reconstruction neural network model to reconstruct the optimized abundance image for the subpixel mapping of urban land use. Experiments were conducted on sentinel-2 images obtained over Yuelu District of Changsha City, Hunan Province, China. The experimental results show that the method proposed in this article can effectively overcome the influence of building shadows and mountain shadows in urban land cover classification and is superior to traditional subpixel/pixel spatial attraction model, radial basis function, super-resolution subpixel mapping, and other methods in the effect and accuracy of urban land use subpixel mapping.
WOS:000942401000005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="43">
<title>A new strategy to map landslides with a generalized convolutional neural network</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1038/s41598-021-89015-8</url>
<snippet>Rapid mapping of event landslides is crucial to identify the areas affected by damages as well as for effective disaster response. Traditionally, such maps are generated with visual interpretation of remote sensing imagery (manned/unmanned airborne systems or spaceborne sensors) and/or using pixel-based and object-based methods exploiting data-intensive machine learning algorithms. Recent works have explored the use of convolutional neural networks (CNN), a deep learning algorithm, for mapping landslides from remote sensing data. These methods follow a standard supervised learning workflow that involves training a model using a landslide inventory covering a relatively small area. The trained model is then used to predict landslides in the surrounding regions. Here, we propose a new strategy, i.e., a progressive CNN training relying on combined inventories to build a generalized model that can be applied directly to a new, unexplored area. We first prove the effectiveness of CNNs by training and validating on event landslides inventories in four regions after earthquakes and/or extreme meteorological events. Next, we use the trained CNNs to map landslides triggered by new events spread across different geographic regions. We found that CNNs trained on a combination of inventories have a better generalization performance, with a bias towards high precision and low recall scores. In our tests, the combined training model achieved the highest (Matthews correlation coefficient) MCC score of 0.69 when mapping landslides in new unseen regions. The mapping was done on images from different optical sensors, resampled to a spatial resolution of 6 m, 10 m, and 30 m. Despite a slightly reduced performance, the main advantage of combined training is to overcome the requirement of a local inventory for training a new deep learning model. This implementation can facilitate automated pipelines providing fast response for the generation of landslide maps in the post-disaster phase. In this study, the study areas were selected from seismically active zones with a high hydrological hazard distribution and vegetation coverage. Hence, future works should also include regions from less vegetated geographic locations.
WOS:000656988100030
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="44">
<title>Landslide Susceptibility Mapping Using Feature Fusion-Based CPCNN-ML in Lantau Island, Hong Kong</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2021.3066378</url>
<snippet>Landslide susceptibility mapping (LSM) is an effective way to predict spatial probability of landslide occurrence. Existing convolutional neural network (CNN)-based methods apply self-built CNN with simple structure, which failed to reach CNNs full potential on high-level feature extraction, meanwhile ignored the use of numerical predisposing factors. For the purpose of exploring feature fusion based CNN models with greater reliability in LSM, this study proposes an ensemble model based on channel-expanded pre-trained CNN and traditional machine learning model (CPCNN-ML). In CPCNN-ML, pre-trained CNN with mature structure is modified to excavate high-level features of multichannel predisposing factor layers. LSM result is generated by traditional machine learning (ML) model based on hybrid feature of high-level features and numerical predisposing factors. Lantau Island, Hong Kong is selected as study area; temporal landslide inventory is used for model training and evaluation. Experimental results show that CPCNN-ML has ability to predict landslide occurrence with high reliability, especially the CPCNN-ML based on random forest. Contrast experiments with self-built CNN and traditional ML models further embody the superiority of CPCNN-ML. It is worth noting that coastal regions are newly identified landslide-prone regions compared with previous research. This finding is of great reference value for Hong Kong authorities to formulate appropriate disaster prevention and mitigation policies.
WOS:000640757900003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="45">
<title>Convolutional neural network and long short-term memory algorithms for groundwater potential mapping in Anseong, South Korea</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ejrh.2022.100990</url>
<snippet>Study region: The study area was the Anseong-si area that located in the southernmost part of Gyeonggi-do Province at 127 degrees 19 E, 36 degrees 82 N. Anseong has a transitional climate between that the north and the south regions. Its climate is characterized by the geographical conditions of forming expansive plains that stretch from the Charyeong Range. The entire area of the city is surrounded by many high and low mountains to the south and the west, late-middle age and old age hills are spread, while there are many plains due to the development of rivers. Study focus: In this study, machine learning algorithms were used based on convolutional neural network (CNN) and long short-term memory (LSTM) to generate a groundwater potential map in Anseong, South Korea. A total of 295 wells locations were divided by the median value of transmissivity data (T) and produced "1" point with high groundwater productivity data and "0" as the point with the low groundwater productivity and divided into 70:30 for training and validation the model. 14 groundwater potential related factors were used in this study such as topo-hydrological and geo-environmental factors to define the spatial correlation with the high groundwater productivity data. The validation of the model is evaluated using the receiver operating characteristics (ROC) curve analysis method. The area under the ROC curve (AUC) is calculated to test the model. New hydrological insight for the region: The results shows a good accuracy, as the AUC values were all higher than 0.8. Finally, the groundwater potential maps generated by CNN and LSTM can be used to analyze the areas that potentially provided groundwater in Anseong, South Korea. This study could help the local environment to manage groundwater resources and can be used to assist development planners and decision-makers in groundwater sustainability planning.
WOS:000783312200003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="46">
<title>Feature-Based Constraint Deep CNN Method for Mapping Rainfall-Induced Landslides in Remote Regions With Mountainous Terrain: An Application to Brazil</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2022.3161383</url>
<snippet>Landslides have caused tremendous damage to human lives and property safety. However, the complex environment of mountain landslides and the vegetation coverage around landslides make it difficult to identify landslides quickly and efficiently using high-resolution images. To address this challenge, this article presents a feature-based constraint deep U-Net (FCDU-Net) method to detect rainfall-induced mountainous landslides. Usually, the vegetation in the landslide area is severely damaged, and the vegetation coverage can indirectly reflect the spatial extent of the landslide. Meanwhile, the texture features of high-resolution images can characterize the surface environment of landslide hazards to a certain extent. We first introduce auxiliary features of normalized difference vegetation index and gray-level co-occurrence matrix into the proposed method to further improve the detection performance. Then, to minimize the information redundancy of these features and the image, we combine Relief-F and Deep U-Net to screen the optimal features to effectively identify accurate and detailed landslide boundaries. Compared with traditional semantic segmentation methods, the FCDU-Net method can capture fine-grained details in high-resolution images and produce more accurate segmentation results. We conducted experiments by applying the proposed method and other most popular semantic segmentation methods to a high-resolution RapidEye image in Rio de Janeiro, Brazil. The results demonstrate that the FCDU-Net method can achieve better landslide detection results than the other semantic segmentation methods, and the evaluation measures of Precision, F1 score, and mean Intersection-over-Union are as high as 88.87&#37;, 81.17&#37;, and 83.19&#37;, respectively. Furthermore, we quantitatively analyze the effect of the convolution input window size on the performance of FCDU-Net in detecting landslides. We believe that FCDU-Net can serve as a reliable tool for fast and accurate regional landslide hazard surveys.
WOS:000779605200003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="47">
<title>Landslide Detection and Susceptibility Modeling on Cameron Highlands (Malaysia): A Comparison between Random Forest, Logistic Regression and Logistic Model Tree Algorithms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/f11080830</url>
<snippet>We used remote sensing techniques and machine learning to detect and map landslides, and landslide susceptibility in the Cameron Highlands, Malaysia. We located 152 landslides using a combination of interferometry synthetic aperture radar (InSAR), Google Earth (GE), and field surveys. Of the total slide locations, 80&#37; (122 landslides) were utilized for training the selected algorithms, and the remaining 20&#37; (30 landslides) were applied for validation purposes. We employed 17 conditioning factors, including slope angle, aspect, elevation, curvature, profile curvature, stream power index (SPI), topographic wetness index (TWI), lithology, soil type, land cover, normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI), distance to river, distance to fault, distance to road, river density, fault density, and road density, which were produced from satellite imageries, geological map, soil maps, and a digital elevation model (DEM). We used these factors to produce landslide susceptibility maps using logistic regression (LR), logistic model tree (LMT), and random forest (RF) models. To assess prediction accuracy of the models we employed the following statistical measures: negative predictive value (NPV), sensitivity, positive predictive value (PPV), specificity, root-mean-squared error (RMSE), accuracy, and area under the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve (AUC). Our results indicated that the AUC was 92&#37;, 90&#37;, and 88&#37; for the LMT, LR, and RF algorithms, respectively. To assess model performance, we also applied non-parametric statistical tests of Friedman and Wilcoxon, where the results revealed that there were no practical differences among the used models in the study area. While landslide mapping in tropical environment such as Cameron Highlands remains difficult, the remote sensing (RS) along with machine learning techniques, such as the LMT model, show promise for landslide susceptibility mapping in the study area.
WOS:000567172400001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="48">
<title>Insights into spatial differential characteristics of landslide susceptibility from sub-region to whole-region cased by northeast Chongqing, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/19475705.2023.2190858</url>
<snippet>Landslides have differential characteristics in different regions. This study explores landslide susceptibility mapping (LSM) based on different evaluation units and proposes a strategy for landslides differential characteristics in different sub-regions. Based on data of lithology, elevation, and historical landslides, terrain units (TUs) and slope units (SUs) were obtained. LSM was developed using the Random Forest (RF) model and Light Gradient Boosting Machine (LGBM) model. The LGBM-TUs showed the highest performance and were therefore, selected to obtain LSM. The study area was divided into four sub-regions using the geographically weighted regression (GWR) model, along with spatial differential characteristics of topography conditions. The distribution and characteristics of landslides within each sub-region were assessed using GeoDetector. The results illustrated the reliability of the LGBM-TUs model. Lithology, elevation, and average annual rainfall were the dominant factors, while the influence of other factors on the occurrence of landslides was strengthened only when these factors interacted. This study proposed a new method for LSM research to insight the spatial differential characteristics of landslides in various sub-regions. Our results provide novel insights into landslide mitigation.
WOS:000955372900001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="49">
<title>An ensemble random forest tree with SVM, ANN, NBT, and LMT for landslide susceptibility mapping in the Rangit River watershed, India</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-022-05360-5</url>
<snippet>This study examined landslide susceptibility, an increasingly common problem in mountainous regions across the world as a result of urbanization, deforestation, and various natural processes. The Rangit River watershed in Sikkim Himalaya is one of the most landslide-prone areas in India. The main objective of this study was to produce landslide susceptibility maps of the Rangit River watershed using novel ensembles of random forest tree (RFT) with support vector machine (RFT-SVM), artificial neural network (RFT-ANN), naive Bayes tree (RFT-NBT), and logistic model tree (RFT-LMT). An inventory of landslides was created using historical landslide data, government and scientific studies, and Google Earths high-resolution satellite images. The landslide/non-landslide locations were split 70/30 for training and validating the models, respectively. Eleven landslide conditioning factors were selected based on their predictive ability, determined using the information gain method, and each factors importance was derived. A landslide susceptibility index was then estimated by weighted overlay using a model builder in a GIS (Geographic Information System) environment. Based on the area under the curve and statistical metrics, RFT-LMT was identified as the best model. The results showed that approximately 40&#37; of the Rangit River watershed has high to very high susceptibility to landslides. This studys findings will be useful for policy-makers and land use planners in managing and mitigating future landslides in the study area.
WOS:000795209700002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="50">
<title>Debris flows modeling using geo-environmental factors: developing hybridized deep-learning algorithms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10106049.2021.1912194</url>
<snippet>Although the prediction of debris flow-prone areas represents a key step towards reducing damages, modeling debris flow susceptibility is complicated. In addition, the role of debris flow causal drivers in forested mountain landscapes is still poorly understood. To gain a holistic view of the causes of debris flows in the Umyeonsan, Seoul, South Korea region, we coupled the convolutional neural network (CNN) with two evolutionary optimization algorithms - grey wolf optimization (GWO) and cuckoo optimization algorithm (COA). Applying geoinformatics to debris flow factors, debris-flow susceptibility maps were generated and their validities were assessed with receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves. The results reveal that three causative factors seem to contribute most to debris flows in the study area. The evolutionary optimization algorithms achieved higher goodness-of-fit and predictive power than the standalone CNN model. The goodness-of-fit and predictive skill measures of the CNN susceptibility map were 0.76 and 0.73. The values of CNN hybridized with GWO were 0.81 and 0.81 and hybridized with COA were 0.83 and 0.82. Slope degree, tree age, stream power index, geographical class, and soil drainage were the factors most affecting debris flow likelihood. The CNN-COA is the superior model and it predicted that 40.6&#37; of the study area (i.e., 1844.96 km2) is highly and very highly susceptible to debris flows. The methodology can be applied for analysis of other region to improve risk management and guide development and land use planning.
WOS:000647391400001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="51">
<title>Hybrid meta-heuristic machine learning methods applied to landslide susceptibility mapping in the Sahel-Algiers</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ijsrc.2022.04.003</url>
<snippet>Landslides are considered as one among many phenomena jeopardizing human beings as well as their constructions. To prevent this disastrous problem, researchers have used several approaches for landslide susceptibility modeling, for the purpose of preparing accurate maps marking landslide prone areas. Among the most frequently used approaches for landslide susceptibility mapping is the Artificial Neural Network (ANN) method. However, the effectiveness of ANN methods could be enhanced by using hybrid metaheuristic algorithms, which are scarcely applied in landslide mapping. In the current study, nine hybrid metaheuristic algorithms, genetic algorithm (GA)-ANN, evolutionary strategy (ES)-ANN, ant colony optimization (ACO)-ANN, particle swarm optimization (PSO)-ANN, biogeography based optimization (BBO)-ANN, gravitational search algorithm (GHA)-ANN, particle swarm optimization and gravitational search algorithm (PSOGSA)-ANN, grey wolves optimization (GWO)-ANN, and probability based incremental learning (PBIL)-ANN have been used to spatially predict landslide susceptibility in Algiers Sahel, Algeria. The modeling phase was done using a database of 78 landslides collected utilizing Google Earth images, field surveys, and six conditioning factors (lithology, elevation, slope, land cover, distance to stream, and distance to road). Initially, a gamma test was used to decrease the input variable numbers. Furthermore, the optimal inputs have been modeled by the mean of hybrid metaheuristic ANN techniques and their performance was assessed through seven statistical indicators. The comparative study proves the effectiveness of the co-evolutionary PSOGSA-ANN model, which yielded higher performance in predicting landslide susceptibility compared to the other models. Sensitivity analysis using the step-by-step technique was done afterward, which revealed that the distance to the stream is the most influential factor on landslide susceptibility, followed by the slope factor which ranked second. Lithology and the distance to road have demonstrated a moderate effect on landslide susceptibility. Based on these findings, an accurate map has been designed to help land-use managers and decision-makers to mitigate landslide hazards. 
WOS:000823397900006
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="52">
<title>Rainfall-Induced Shallow Landslide Susceptibility Mapping at Two Adjacent Catchments Using Advanced Machine Learning Algorithms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijgi9100569</url>
<snippet>Landslides impact on human activities and socio-economic development, especially in mountainous areas. This study focuses on the comparison of the prediction capability of advanced machine learning techniques for the rainfall-induced shallow landslide susceptibility of Deokjeokri catchment and Karisanri catchment in South Korea. The influencing factors for landslides, i.e., topographic, hydrologic, soil, forest, and geologic factors, are prepared from various sources based on availability, and a multicollinearity test is also performed to select relevant causative factors. The landslide inventory maps of both catchments are obtained from historical information, aerial photographs and performed field surveys. In this study, Deokjeokri catchment is considered as a training area and Karisanri catchment as a testing area. The landslide inventories contain 748 landslide points in training and 219 points in testing areas. Three landslide susceptibility maps using machine learning models, i.e., Random Forest (RF), Extreme Gradient Boosting (XGBoost) and Deep Neural Network (DNN), are prepared and compared. The outcomes of the analyses are validated using the landslide inventory data. A receiver operating characteristic curve (ROC) method is used to verify the results of the models. The results of this study show that the training accuracy of RF is 0.756 and the testing accuracy is 0.703. Similarly, the training accuracy of XGBoost is 0.757 and testing accuracy is 0.74. The prediction of DNN revealed acceptable agreement between the susceptibility map and the existing landslides, with a training accuracy of 0.855 and testing accuracy of 0.802. The results showed that the DNN model achieved lower prediction error and higher accuracy results than other models for shallow landslide modeling in the study area.
WOS:000586922700001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="53">
<title>Random Forest-Based Landslide Susceptibility Mapping in Coastal Regions of Artvin, Turkey</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijgi9090553</url>
<snippet>Natural disasters such as landslides often occur in the Eastern Black Sea region of Turkey owing to its geological, topographical, and climatic characteristics. Landslide events occur nearly every year in the Arhavi, Hopa, and Kemalpasa districts located on the Black Sea coast in the Artvin province. In this study, the landslide susceptibility map of the Arhavi, Hopa, and Kemalpasa districts was produced using the random forest (RF) model, which is widely used in the literature and yields more accurate results compared with other machine learning techniques. A total of 10 landslide-conditioning factors were considered for the susceptibility analysis, i.e., lithology, land cover, slope, aspect, elevation, curvature, topographic wetness index, and distances from faults, drainage networks, and roads. Furthermore, 70&#37; of the landslides on the landslide inventory map were used for training, and the remaining 30&#37; were used for validation. The RF-based model was validated using the area under the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve. Evaluation results indicated that the success and prediction rates of the model were 98.3&#37; and 97.7&#37;, respectively. Moreover, it was determined that incorrect land-use decisions, such as transforming forest areas into tea and hazelnut cultivation areas, induce the occurrence of landslides.
WOS:000580126700001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="54">
<title>An integrated approach based earthquake risk assessment of a seismically active and rapidly urbanizing area in Northern Pakistan</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10106049.2022.2105404</url>
<snippet>Earthquake risk in urban areas has recently taken quite a lot of attention. Risk is a cross-cutting combination of vulnerability and hazard. Abbottabad district, a rapidly growing district, is an earthquake-prone area in the north of Pakistan. In 2005, the region suffered enormous casualties due to a significant earthquake (M-w = 7.6). The various regional behaviours, including social, physical, and economic behaviours, are causing a vulnerable situation. At the same time, the high seismicity has the potential to invite earthquake hazard, thus ensuing a possible risk situation in the region. Consequently, this study proposes an integrated approach involving an artificial neural network (ANN), convolutional neural network (CNN), and analytic network process (ANP) to carry out the seismic risk analysis of the Abbottabad district. The proposed two integrated frameworks are ANP-ANN and ANP-CNN. This kind of methodology has not been applied before in this area. The geographic information system is used to formulate a broad range of contributing factors depicting the hazard and vulnerability of the area and potentially contributing to the seismic risk. A total of 16 contributing factors are chosen for this study. The selected factors are weighed using the ANP, and training and testing databases are generated to train and test the models, thus producing the areas earthquake risk maps (ERMs). As per the ERMs, the northwestern regions and the borderline regions from the southeast, covering an area of 30&#37;, possess a greater earthquake risk. The rest of the 70&#37; of the area has less risk exposure. The AUC values of ANN and CNN are found to be 0.843 and 0.878, respectively, exhibiting a good performance by the models. The study paves the way for the concerned authorities to match and redefine their policies for developing, expanding, and managing the regions structural, health care, and disaster management facilities.
WOS:000835069100001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="55">
<title>LANDSLIDE SUSCEPTIBILITY MAPPING USING LOGISTIC REGRESSION AND FREQUENCY RATIO APPROACHES, CASE STUDY FROM SOUK AHRAS REGION, N E ALGERIA</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.4408/IJEGE.2020-01.O-04</url>
<snippet>Landslides are the most active process of soil erosion and landscape evolution; it is controlled by a set of non-linear factors. Therefore, a large amount of spatial data must be considered and analyzed in order to achieve some degree of prediction about it. Landslide susceptibility assessment (LSA) is carried out using various statistical modeling techniques among which figures the logistic regression (LR) and the Frequency Ratio (FR) models. This work allowed producing landslide susceptibility maps (LSMs) on a geographic information system (GIS) platform using LR and FR methods in the Northwest of Souk Ahras region, N E of Algeria. Landslide inventory map was established from visual interpretation of satellite images and field survey data. Slope instability phenomena in this region are related to a large variety of factors pertaining to the geological, geomorphological, hydrological and climate characteristics of the terrain. Consequently, a spatial database of seven causal factors were identified and used for predicting landslide prone areas. LSMs produced using LR and FR statistical models subdivided into five classes according to their degree of susceptibility to landslides: very low, low, moderate, high and very high. These rasters based LSMs was compared and verified with both training and testing inventory datasets. The AUC (area under the curve) was used for model evaluation. Results showed that the LR model provides a higher prediction accuracy of the LS mapping than the FR model with an AUC based on success rate equal 90.45 &#37; and that based on prediction rate was 91.81 &#37;. In addition, the results showed that about 30&#37; to 37&#37; of the study area was located in high and very high hazard classes. The resulting LSMs play an indispensable role in the region management and can be used in sustainable development planning.
WOS:000571902300005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="56">
<title>A Hybrid Model Consisting of Supervised and Unsupervised Learning for Landslide Susceptibility Mapping</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/rs13081464</url>
<snippet>Landslides cause huge damage to social economy and human beings every year. Landslide susceptibility mapping (LSM) occupies an important position in land use and risk management. This study is to investigate a hybrid model which makes full use of the advantage of supervised learning model (SLM) and unsupervised learning model (ULM). Firstly, ten continuous variables were used to develop a ULM which consisted of factor analysis (FA) and k-means cluster for a preliminary landslide susceptibility map. Secondly, 351 landslides with "1" label were collected and the same number of non-landslide samples with "0" label were selected from the very low susceptibility area in the preliminary map, constituting a new priori condition for a SLM, and thirteen factors were used for the modeling of gradient boosting decision tree (GBDT) which represented for SLM. Finally, the performance of different models was verified using related indexes. The results showed that the performance of the pretreated GBDT model was improved with sensitivity, specificity, accuracy and the area under the curve (AUC) values of 88.60&#37;, 92.59&#37;, 90.60&#37; and 0.976, respectively. It can be concluded that a pretreated model with strong robustness can be constructed by increasing the purity of samples.
WOS:000644674500001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="57">
<title>Establishing a GIS-based evaluation method considering spatial heterogeneity for debris flow susceptibility mapping at the regional scale</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-022-05487-5</url>
<snippet>Susceptibility mapping is an effective means of preventing debris flow disasters. However, previous studies have failed to solve spatial heterogeneity well, especially at the regional scale. The main objective of this study is to solve the spatial heterogeneity of regional-scale debris flow susceptibility (DFS) mapping by establishing a geographic information system (GIS)-based processing framework. The framework was realized by integrating the determination factor (DFactor) model with machine learning models. The DFactor model established different combinations of evaluation factors in each local region and clarified the differing contributions of influencing factors to DFS. To test the feasibility of the framework, the support vector machine (SVM) and two-dimensional convolutional neural network (CNN) were integrated with the DFactor model (DFactor-SVM and DFactor-CNN) to evaluate DFS in Jilin Province, China. The individual models (SVM and CNN) were also used to map the DFS for comparison with the integrated models. For debris flow modeling, 868 debris flow samples were collected and randomly divided into two datasets: 70&#37; of the samples were used for training and the result was used for verification. The results of the receiver operating characteristic curve showed that the integrated models performed better. The DFactor-CNN model had the highest predictive accuracy, followed by the DFactor-SVM, CNN and SVM models. In general, the GIS-based processing framework maximizes the contribution of the influencing factors to debris flows and enhances the prediction ability of models. Furthermore, it provides a reliable means to predict debris flows at the regional scale.
WOS:000836767500005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="58">
<title>A comparative modeling of landslides susceptibility at a meso-scale using frequency ratio and analytic hierarchy process models in geographic information system: the case of African Alpine Mountains (Rif, Morocco)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s40808-022-01605-1</url>
<snippet>Landslides represent a major natural hazard for all countries in the world. The Rif mountains in Morocco suffer from different types of landslides. Some of them are very active and present a significant risk to urban areas and transport systems. Consequently, in terms of sustainable development, landslide susceptibility mapping is essential to assess the levels of danger posed by these phenomena. This study aims at evaluating landslide susceptibility using two different approaches based on a statistical method (Frequency Ratio, FR) and on a heuristic method (Analytic Hierarchy Process, AHP). The second purpose is to compare them to select the most relevant and reproducible one with a view to applying it to areas having a similar geomorphological context. This study includes a precise inventory map representing the spatial distribution of three landslide categories within 892 sites. Rock falls, flows and landslides were studied using field survey and satellite imagery. Nine thematic layers of predisposing factors controlling landslides occurrence were prepared. The final result is presented in the form of six susceptibility maps of rockfalls, flows and landslides for FR and AHP models. The result of the success rates (AUC) indicates that the FR method is better with an AUC of 88&#37; for rock fall, 89&#37; for flows and 87&#37; for landslides, while the AUC is 83&#37;, 84&#37; and 76&#37;, respectively for the AHP method. Moreover, the results indicate which method to use for similar regions to produce indicative mapping and help users select priority areas prone to landslides.
WOS:000886818800003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="59">
<title>A bibliometric and content analysis of research trends on GIS-based landslide susceptibility from 2001 to 2020</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11356-022-23732-z</url>
<snippet>To assess the status of hotspots and research trends on geographic information system (GIS)-based landslide susceptibility (LS), we analysed 1142 articles from the Thomas Reuters Web of Science Core Collection database published during 2001-2020 by combining bibliometric and content analysis. The paper number, authors, institutions, corporations, publication sources, citations, and keywords are noted as sub/categories for the bibliometric analysis. Thematic LS data, including the study site, landslide inventory, conditioning factors, mapping unit, susceptibility models, and mode fit/prediction performance evaluation, are presented in the content analysis. Then, we reveal the advantages and limitations of the common approaches used in thematic LS data and summarise the development trends. The results indicate that the distribution of articles shows clear clusters of authors, institutions, and countries with high academic activity. The application of remote sensing technology for interpreting landslides provides a more convenient and efficient landslide inventory. In the landslide inventory, most of the sample strategies representing the landslides are point and polygon, and the most frequently used sample subdividing strategy is random sampling. The scale effects, lack of geographic consistency, and no standard are key problems in landslide conditioning factors. Feature selection is used to choose the factors that can improve the models accuracy. With advances in computing technology and artificial intelligence, LS models are changing from simple qualitative and statistical models to complex machine learning and hybrid models. Finally, five future research opportunities are revealed. This study will help investigators clarify the status of LS research and provide guidance for future research.
WOS:000871328400015
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="60">
<title>Application of artificial neural networks and geographic information system to provide hazard susceptibility maps for rockfall failures</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-022-10603-6</url>
<snippet>The presented article attempted to analysis rockfalls susceptibility mapping which is considered as one the most important type of the land-slides with high frequent occurrence. The machine learning based multiple-layer perceptron (MLP) model was used to provide the pridicive model and hazard risk maps for studied area. This artificial neural network (ANN) was received significant success in susceptibility assessment for landslides and rockfall. The predictive model was conducted on a dataset containing 15 main triggering factors which concluded 10 regular (e.g., precipitation, slope aspect, slope angle, weathering, lithology, distance to river, main faults unsafe radius, landslide-prone areas, distance to roads, and distance to the cities), 5 specific (e.g., RQD, Q(slope), GSI, SMR, and RHRS), and 57 historical landslides which represent different aspects of the rockfall failures at Alborz province in Iran. To susceptibility assessment, the dataset that used in ANN-based analysis was randomly divided into training (70&#37;) and testing (30&#37;) sets and utilized to predict the risk-able area.. The predictive model was comparatively justified by using benchmark learning classifiers concluded support-vector machine (SVM), decision tree (DT), and random forest(RF) algorithms. The confusion matrix and receiver operating characteristic curves (ROC) were used for performance analysis and obtaining models accuracy. According to the susceptibility results, the north part of the studied region has high risks for rockfall failures. As machine learning-based performance analysis, the MLP-based model by 0.82 accuracy/0.85 precision reached the highest rank more than other classifiers such asSVM (accuracy = 0.78/precision = 0.78), DT (accuracy = 0.70/precision = 0.73), and RF (accuracy = 0.68/precision = 0.70). Also, overall accuracy obtained from ROC, the main model MLP (AUC = 0.811) is higher than SVM (AUC = 0.780), DT (AUC = 0.740), and RF (AUC = 0.500). MLP model provide more conservative results than other classifier and RF is estimated the risk rate less than others.
WOS:000862410500001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="61">
<title>Unsupervised Deep Learning for Landslide Detection from Multispectral Sentinel-2 Imagery</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/rs13224698</url>
<snippet>This paper proposes a new approach based on an unsupervised deep learning (DL) model for landslide detection. Recently, supervised DL models using convolutional neural networks (CNN) have been widely studied for landslide detection. Even though these models provide robust performance and reliable results, they depend highly on a large labeled dataset for their training step. As an alternative, in this paper, we developed an unsupervised learning model by employing a convolutional auto-encoder (CAE) to deal with the problem of limited labeled data for training. The CAE was used to learn and extract the abstract and high-level features without using training data. To assess the performance of the proposed approach, we used Sentinel-2 imagery and a digital elevation model (DEM) to map landslides in three different case studies in India, China, and Taiwan. Using minimum noise fraction (MNF) transformation, we reduced the multispectral dimension to three features containing more than 80&#37; of scene information. Next, these features were stacked with slope data and NDVI as inputs to the CAE model. The Huber reconstruction loss was used to evaluate the inputs. We achieved reconstruction losses ranging from 0.10 to 0.147 for the MNF features, slope, and NDVI stack for all three study areas. The mini-batch K-means clustering method was used to cluster the features into two to five classes. To evaluate the impact of deep features on landslide detection, we first clustered a stack of MNF features, slope, and NDVI, then the same ones plus with the deep features. For all cases, clustering based on deep features provided the highest precision, recall, F1-score, and mean intersection over the union in landslide detection.
WOS:000771958500022
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="62">
<title>Shallow Landslide Susceptibility Models Based on Artificial Neural Networks Considering the Factor Selection Method and Various Non-Linear Activation Functions</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/rs12071194</url>
<snippet>Landslide susceptibility mapping is well recognized as an essential element in supporting decision-making activities for preventing and mitigating landslide hazards as it provides information regarding locations where landslides are most likely to occur. The main purpose of this study is to produce a landslide susceptibility map of Mt. Umyeon in Korea using an artificial neural network (ANN) involving the factor selection method and various non-linear activation functions. A total of 151 historical landslide events and 20 predisposing factors consisting of Geographic Information System (GIS)-based morphological, hydrological, geological, and land cover datasets were constructed with a resolution of 5 x 5 m. The collected datasets were applied to information gain ratio analysis to confirm the predictive power and multicollinearity diagnosis to ensure the correlation of independence among the landslide predisposing factors. The best 11 predisposing factors that were selected in this study were randomly divided into a 70:30 ratio for training and validation datasets, which were used to produce ANN-based landslide susceptibility models. The ANN model used in this study had a multi-layer perceptron (MLP) structure consisting of an input layer, one hidden layer, and an output layer. In the output layer, the logistic sigmoid function was used to represent the result value within the range of 0 to 1, and six non-linear activation functions were used for the hidden layer. The performance of the landslide susceptibility models was evaluated using the receiver operating characteristic curve, Kappa index, and five statistical indices (sensitivity, specificity, accuracy, positive predictive value (PPV), negative predictive value (NPV)) with the training dataset. In addition, the landslide susceptibility models were validated using the aforementioned measures with the validation dataset and were compared using the Friedman test to check the significant differences among the six developed models. The optimal number of neurons was determined based on the aforementioned performance evaluation and validation results. Overall, the model with the best performance was the MLP model with the logistic sigmoid activation function in the output layer and the hyperbolic tangent sigmoid activation function with five neurons in the hidden layer. The validation results of the best model showed a sensitivity of 82.61&#37;, specificity of 78.26&#37;, accuracy of 80.43&#37;, PPV of 79.17&#37;, NPV of 81.82&#37;, a Kappa index of 0.609, and AUC of 0.879. The results of this study highlight the effectiveness of selecting an optimal MLP model structure for shallow landslide susceptibility mapping using an appropriate predisposing factor section method.
WOS:000537709600144
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="63">
<title>Spatial variation in the frequency and magnitude of mass movement in a semiarid, complex-terrain agricultural watershed on the Loess Plateau of China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/ldr.3296</url>
<snippet>The previous inventory datasets of mass movement typically include large-sized mass movements (e.g., landslides), whereas small ones are often missing due to either being too small to be interpreted from remote sensing images or too time-consuming to measure them in the field. Thus, the relative significance of different-sized mass movement in sediment production remains unknown. In this study, first, a total of 547 recent mass movements, with a volume ranging from 0.3 to 19,000 m(3), are surveyed in a small complex-terrain watershed on the Loess Plateau of China; then, sediment contributions by mass movement of different magnitude and frequency are evaluated; furthermore, the effects of causative factors on both mass movement frequency and magnitude are examined and compared; finally, Geographic Information Systems (GIS) and statistical methods are employed to assess mass movement susceptibility and erosion risk. The results showed that majority of the mass movements are very small (&lt;10 m(3)). Even though a large mass movement can produce a disproportionally high amount of debris on a per event basis, small- and medium-sized mass movements (&lt;1,000 m(3)) are overall more important in sediment production in the watershed. The GIS-based modeling results also demonstrate that there is significant difference in spatial variation between the susceptibility and erosion risk of mass movements. Therefore, although the mass movement susceptibility map is very useful in prioritizing hazard prevention and mitigation, it should be combined with the mass movement erosion risk map in erosion control planning and design, which has not been done in the past.
WOS:000470932100007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="64">
<title>A Holistic Analysis for Landslide Susceptibility Mapping Applying Geographic Object-Based Random Forest: A Comparison between Protected and Non-Protected Forests</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/rs12030434</url>
<snippet>Despite recent progress in landslide susceptibility mapping, a holistic method is still needed to integrate and customize influential factors with the focus on forest regions. This study was accomplished to test the performance of geographic object-based random forest in modeling the susceptibility of protected and non-protected forests to landslides in northeast Iran. Moreover, it investigated the influential conditioning and triggering factors that control the susceptibility of these two forest areas to landslides. After surveying the landslide events, segment objects were generated from the Landsat 8 multispectral images and digital elevation model (DEM) data. The features of conditioning factors were derived from the DEM and available thematic layers. Natural triggering factors were derived from the historical events of rainfall, floods, and earthquake. The object-based image analysis was used for deriving anthropogenic-induced forest loss and fragmentation. The layers of logging and mining were obtained from available historical data. Landslide samples were extracted from field observations, satellite images, and available database. A single database was generated including all conditioning and triggering object features, and landslide samples for modeling the susceptibility of two forest areas to landslides using the random forest algorithm. The optimal performance of random forest was obtained after building 500 trees with the area under the receiver operating characteristics (AUROC) values of 86.3 and 81.8&#37; for the protected and non-protected forests, respectively. The top influential factors were the topographic and hydrologic features for mapping landslide susceptibility in the protected forest. However, the scores were loaded evenly among the topographic, hydrologic, natural, and anthropogenic triggers in the non-protected forest. The topographic features obtained about 60&#37; of the importance values with the domination of the topographic ruggedness index and slope in the protected forest. Although the importance of topographic features was reduced to 36&#37; in the non-protected forest, anthropogenic and natural triggering factors remarkably gained 33.4&#37; of the importance values in this area. This study confirms that some anthropogenic activities such as forest fragmentation and logging significantly intensified the susceptibility of the non-protected forest to landslides.
WOS:000515393800093
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="65">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping on the islands of Vulcano and Lipari (Aeolian Archipelago, Italy), using a multi-classification approach on conditioning factors and a modified GIS matrix method for areas lacking in a landslide inventory</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10346-019-01148-0</url>
<snippet>In areas prone to landslides, the identification of potentially unstable zones has a decisive impact on the risk assessment and development of mitigation plans. Active volcanic islands are particularly prone to instability phenomena as they are always in the early stage of dynamic unrest. A historical example of slope instability is the landslide which occurred in 1988 along the northwestern flank of La Fossa Cone on the island of Vulcano (Aeolian Archipelago). Based on this past activity, a susceptibility assessment using the bivariate technique of the GIS matrix method (GMM) was carried out on the islands of Lipari and Vulcano. Nevertheless, this case is congruent with those where a part of the surface was not assigned to stable or unstable areas, since a comprehensive inventory was only available for the island of Lipari. Some of the implemented steps of the susceptibility matrix method were modified to enable the model developed in the Lipari area to be applied to both islands. Considering the important role that the classification of conditioning factors plays in susceptibility analysis, the degree of association with landslide spatial distribution for the multiple classifications of each factor was assessed. Furthermore, an innovative clustering approach based on text and data mining techniques (self-organizing map neural network) was applied and compared with a heuristic classification of the categorical variable of lithology units. In addition to the extensive contingency analysis, up to 14 factor combinations were submitted to the GMM, validated and compared so as to select the one that best explains the susceptibility zoning. The effects of these incorporated processes in the previous phase of classification were discussed and preliminary susceptibility map was generated for both islands. After the validation of the susceptibility assessment, it is shown that the highest classes (High and Very High) matched 76.9&#37; (relative accuracy) of the test inventory, while the lower susceptibility classes (Very Low and Low) resulted in a degree of fit of 14.39&#37; (relative error).
WOS:000466495400007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="66">
<title>A novel hybrid approach for landslide susceptibility mapping integrating analytical hierarchy process and normalized frequency ratio methods with the cloud model</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2018.10.024</url>
<snippet>Landslides, which could cause huge losses of lives or property damages, result from several different environmental factors whose influences on landslides are very complex. Therefore, it is essential to understand the relationships between these environmental factors and landslides. Thus, the integration of the analytical hierarchy process (AHP) with the normalized frequency ratio (NFR) is evaluated for landslide susceptibility analyses. However, in addition to these complex relationships, the randomness and fuzziness always affect landslide susceptibility mapping. This study introduces the cloud model (CM) to improve the integrated AHP-NFR method, and proposes a novel hybrid AHP-NFR-CM method for landslide susceptibility analyses, which can better address issues of the randomness and fuzziness. Firstly, ten environmental parameters are selected as landslide impact factors, and their values for all the landslides identified in the study area are obtained through the remote sensing (RS) and geographical information system (GIS) technologies. The AHP method is used to obtain the weight of each landslide impact factor, and the NFR method is used to obtain the weight of each subclass in each landslide impact factor, which can reflect the relationship between the landslide impact factor and landslide occurrence. After applying an appropriate compositional operation between the weights of the landslide impact factors and the weights of the subclasses of the impact factors, a landslide susceptibility index (LSI) for each grid divided via the attribution-based spatial information multi-grid method (ASIMG) can be computed. To solve the inevitable issues of randomness and fuzziness in landslide susceptibility analyses, a cloud model that uses three numerical features (expectation, entropy and hyper-entropy) to represent the intension of the concept, is adopted to improve the methods of AHP and NFR. The relative importance of two landslide impact factors is scaled with the cloud model rather than the Saaty criteria. Pair-wise comparison matrixes of landslide impact factors given by each expert are described by the normal cloud model, and the floating cloud model is used to aggregate all experts judgments. The weight of each landslide impact factor is also expressed with the cloud model rather than a certain value. In improving the NFR, the weight of each subclass of each landslide impact factor is expressed with the cloud model rather than a certain value. In the improvement of the landslide susceptibility results, the domain of landslide risk assessment results is also displayed with the cloud model instead of a series of definite intervals. As the study area examined is large, several grids would need to be divided, meaning that it would take a considerable amount time to subject the entire study area to landslide susceptibility mapping. Thus, we propose a new attribute-based spatial information multi-grid (ASIMG) division method and introduce grid-computing technology to improve the calculation efficiency during the process. Finally, the proposed hybrid AHP-NFR-CM-ASIMG approach is validated and applied in the study area. Its concluded that the new integration of AHP and NFR methods with the cloud model can consider both randomness and fuzziness and therefore can increase the robustness of landslide susceptibility analyses, while the ASIMG technology can enhance the calculation efficiency in regional landslide susceptibility mapping. (C) 2018 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000456491600012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="67">
<title>Landsifier v1.0: a Python library to estimate likely triggers of mapped landslides</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.5194/nhess-22-3751-2022</url>
<snippet>Landslide hazard models aim at mitigating landslide impact by providing probabilistic forecasting, and the accuracy of these models hinges on landslide databases for model training and testing. Landslide databases at times lack information on the underlying triggering mechanism, making these inventories almost unusable in hazard models. We developed a Python-based unique library, Landsifier, that contains three different machine-Learning frameworks for assessing the likely triggering mechanisms of individual landslides or entire inventories based on landslide geometry. Two of these methods only use the 2D landslide planforms, and the third utilizes the 3D shape of landslides relying on an underlying digital elevation model (DEM). The base method extracts geometric properties of landslide polygons as a feature space for the shallow learner - random forest (RF). An alternative method relies on landslide planform images as an input for the deep learning algorithm - convolutional neural network (CNN). The last framework extracts topological properties of 3D landslides through topological data analysis (TDA) and then feeds these properties as a feature space to the random forest classifier. We tested all three interchangeable methods on several inventories with known triggers spread over the Japanese archipelago. To demonstrate the effectiveness of developed methods, we used two testing configurations. The first configuration merges all the available data for the k-fold cross-validation, whereas the second configuration excludes one inventory during the training phase to use as the sole testing inventory. Our geometric-feature-based method performs satisfactorily, with classification accuracies varying between 67 &#37; and 92 &#37;. We have introduced a more straightforward but data-intensive CNN alternative, as it inputs only landslide images without manual feature selection. CNN eases the scripting process without losing classification accuracy. Using topological features from 3D landslides (extracted through TDA) in the RF classifier improves classification accuracy by 12 &#37; on average. TDA also requires less training data. However, the landscape autocorrelation could easily bias TDA-based classification. Finally, we implemented the three methods on an inventory without any triggering information to showcase a real-world application.
WOS:000890930400001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="68">
<title>Review on remote sensing methods for landslide detection using machine and deep learning</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/ett.3998</url>
<snippet>Landslide, one of the most critical natural hazards, is caused due to specific compositional slope movement. In the past decades, due to inflation of urbanized area and climate change, a compelling expansion in landslide prevalence took place which is also termed as mass/slope movement and mass wasting, causing extensive collapse around the world. The principal reason for its pursuance is a reduction in the internal resistance of soil and rocks, classified as a slide, topple, fall, and flow. Slopes can be differentiated based on earth material and the nature of its movements. The downward flow of landslides occurs due to excessive rainfall, snowmelt, earthquake, volcanic eruption, and so on. This review article revisits the conventional approaches for identification of landslides, predicting future risk, associated with slope failures, followed by emphasizing the advantages of modern geospatial techniques such as aerial photogrammetry, satellite remote sensing images (ie, panchromatic, multispectral, radar images), Terrestrial laser scanning, and High-Resolution Digital Elevation Model (HR-DEM) in updating landslide inventory maps. Machine learning techniques like Support Vector Machine, Artificial neural network, deep learning has been extensively used with geographical data producing effective results for assessment of natural hazard/resources and environmental research. Based on recent studies, deep learning is a reliable tool addressing remote sensing challenges such as trade-off in imaging system producing poor quality investigation, in addition, to expedite consequent task such as image recognition, object detection, classification, and so on. Conventional methods, like pixel and object-based machine learning methods, have been broadly explored. Advanced development in deep learning technique like CNN (Convolutional neural network) has been extensively successful in information extraction from an image and has exceeded other traditional approaches. Over the past few years, minor attempts have been made for landslide susceptibility mapping using CNN. In addition, small sample sizes for training purpose will be major drawback and notably remarkable while using deep learning techniques. Also, assessment of the models performance with diverse training and testing proportion other than commonly utilized ratio, that is, 70/30 needs to be explored further. The review article briefly highlights the remote sensing methods for landslide detection using machine learning and deep learning.
WOS:000542033600001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="69">
<title>Integrating Multivariate (GeoDetector) and Bivariate (IV) Statistics for Hybrid Landslide Susceptibility Modeling: A Case of the Vicinity of Pinios Artificial Lake, Ilia, Greece</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/land10090973</url>
<snippet>Over the last few years, landslides have occurred more and more frequently worldwide, causing severe effects on both natural and human environments. Given that landslide susceptibility (LS) assessments and mapping can spatially determine the potential for landslides in a region, it constitutes a basic step in effective risk management and disaster response. Nowadays, several LS models are available, with each one having its advantages and disadvantages. In order to enhance the benefits and overcome the weaknesses of individual modeling, the present study proposes a hybrid LS model based on the integration of two different statistical analysis models, the multivariate Geographical Detector (GeoDetector) and the bivariate information value (IV). In a GIS-based framework, the hybrid model named GeoDIV was tested to generate a reliable LS map for the vicinity of the Pinios artificial lake (Ilia, Greece), a Greek wetland. A landslide inventory of 60 past landslides and 14 conditioning (morphological, hydro-lithological and anthropogenic) factors was prepared to compose the spatial database. An LS map was derived from the GeoDIV model, presenting the different zones of potential landslides (probability) for the study area. This map was then validated by success and prediction rates-which translate to the accuracy and prediction ability of the model, respectively. The findings confirmed that hybrid modeling can outperform individual modeling, as the proposed GeoDIV model presented better validation results than the IV model.
WOS:000699831800001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="70">
<title>Evaluating the Effects of Digital Elevation Models in Landslide Susceptibility Mapping in Rangamati District, Bangladesh</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/rs12172718</url>
<snippet>Digital elevation models (DEMs) are the most obvious data sources in landslide susceptibility assessment. Many landslide casual factors are often generated from DEMs. Most studies on landslide susceptibility assessments rely on freely available DEMs. However, very little is known about the performance of different DEMs with varying spatial resolutions on the accurate assessment of landslide susceptibility. This study compared the performance of four different DEMs including 30 m Advanced Spaceborne Thermal Emission and Reflection Radiometer (ASTER) Global Digital Elevation Model (GDEM), 30-90 m Shuttle Radar Topographic Mission (SRTM), 12.5 m Advanced Land Observation Satellite (ALOS) Phased Array Type L band Synthetic Aperture Radar (PALSAR), and 25 m Survey of Bangladesh (SOB) DEM in landslide susceptibility assessment in the Rangamati district in Bangladesh. This study used three different landslide susceptibility assessment techniques: modified frequency ratio (bivariate model), logistic regression (multivariate model), and random forest (machine-learning model). This study explored two scenarios of landslide susceptibility assessment: using only DEM-derived causal factors and using both DEM-derived factors as well as other common factors. The success and prediction rate curves indicate that the SRTM DEM provides the highest accuracies for the bivariate model in both scenarios. Results also reveal that the ALOS PALSAR DEM shows the best performance in landslide susceptibility mapping using the logistics regression and the random forest models. A relatively finer resolution DEM, the SOB DEM, shows the lowest accuracies compared to other DEMs for all models and scenarios. It can also be noted that the performance of all DEMs except the SOB DEM is close (72&#37;-84&#37;) considering the success and prediction accuracies. Therefore, anyone of the three global DEMs: ASTER, SRTM, and ALOS PALSAR can be used for landslide susceptibility mapping in the study area.
WOS:000569714500001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="71">
<title>DEM resolution effects on machine learning performance for flood probability mapping</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.jher.2021.10.002</url>
<snippet>Floods are among the devastating natural disasters that occurred very frequently in arid regions during the last decades. Accurate assessment of the flood susceptibility mapping is crucial in sustainable development. It helps respective authorities to prevent as much as possible their irreversible consequences. The Digital Elevation Model (DEM) spatial resolution is one of the most crucial base layer factors for modeling Flood Probability Maps (FPMs). Therefore, the main objective of this study was to assess the influence of the spatial resolution of the DEMs 12.5 m (ALOS PALSAR) and 30 m (ASTER) on the accuracy of flood probability prediction using three machine learning models (MLMs), including Random Forest (RF), Artificial Neural Network (ANN), and Generalized Linear Model (GLM). This study selected 14 causative factors in the flood as independent variables, and 220 flood locations were selected as dependent variables. Dependent variables were divided into training (70&#37;) and validation (30&#37;) for flood susceptibility modeling. The Receiver Operating Characteristic Curve (ROC), Kappa index, accuracy, and other statistical criteria were used to evaluate the models accuracy. The results showed that resolving the DEM alone cannot significantly affect the accuracy of flood probability prediction regardless of the applied MLM and independently of the statistical model used to assess the performance accuracy. In contrast, the factors such as altitude, precipitation, and distance from the river have a considerable impact on floods in this region. Also, the evaluation results of the models showed that the RF (AUC(12.5,30m) = 0.983, 0.975) model is more accurate in preparing the FPM than the ANN (AUC(12.5,30m) = 0.949, 0.93) and GLM (AUC(12.5,30m) = 0.965, 0.949) models. This studys solution-oriented findings might help water managers and decision-makers to make the most effective adaptation and mitigation measures against potential flooding.
WOS:000747870400001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="72">
<title>A Novel Hybrid Method for Landslide Susceptibility Mapping-Based GeoDetector and Machine Learning Cluster: A Case of Xiaojin County, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijgi10020093</url>
<snippet>Landslide susceptibility mapping (LSM) could be an effective way to prevent landslide hazards and mitigate losses. The choice of conditional factors is crucial to the results of LSM, and the selection of models also plays an important role. In this study, a hybrid method including GeoDetector and machine learning cluster was developed to provide a new perspective on how to address these two issues. We defined redundant factors by quantitatively analyzing the single impact and interactive impact of the factors, which was analyzed by GeoDetector, the effect of this step was examined using mean absolute error (MAE). The machine learning cluster contains four models (artificial neural network (ANN), Bayesian network (BN), logistic regression (LR), and support vector machines (SVM)) and automatically selects the best one for generating LSM. The receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve, prediction accuracy, and the seed cell area index (SCAI) methods were used to evaluate these methods. The results show that the SVM model had the best performance in the machine learning cluster with the area under the ROC curve of 0.928 and with an accuracy of 83.86&#37;. Therefore, SVM was chosen as the assessment model to map the landslide susceptibility of the study area. The landslide susceptibility map demonstrated fit with landslide inventory, indicated the hybrid method is effective in screening landslide influences and assessing landslide susceptibility.
WOS:000622593200001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="73">
<title>Comparison of LiDAR- and UAV-derived data for landslide susceptibility mapping using Random Forest algorithm</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10346-022-02001-7</url>
<snippet>Earthquakes, extreme rainfall, or human activity can all cause landslides. Several landslides occur each year around the world, often resulting in casualties and economic consequences. Landslide susceptibility mapping is considered to be the main technique for predicting the likelihood of an event based on the characteristics of the physical environment. Digital Terrain Model (DTM) is one of the fundamental data of modeling and is used to derive important conditional factors for detailed scale landslide susceptibility analyses. With this in mind, this study aimed to compare landslide susceptibility maps generated by Random Forest (RF) machine learning algorithm with data from Light Detection and Range (LiDAR) and Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV). To this end, the performance achieved in prediction was evaluated using statistical evaluation measures based on training and validation datasets. The obtained results showed that the accuracy of both models is greater than 0.70, the area under the curve (AUC) is greater than 0.80, and the model generated from the LiDAR data is more accurate. The results also showed that the data from UAV have potential to use in landslide susceptibility mapping on an intra-urban scale, contributing to studies in risk areas without available data.
WOS:000918123500001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="74">
<title>An Automated Snow Mapper Powered by Machine Learning</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/rs13234826</url>
<snippet>Snow preserves fresh water and impacts regional climate and the environment. Enabled by modern satellite Earth observations, fast and accurate automated snow mapping is now possible. In this study, we developed the Automated Snow Mapper Powered by Machine Learning (AutoSMILE), which is the first machine learning-based open-source system for snow mapping. It is built in a Python environment based on object-based analysis. AutoSMILE was first applied in a mountainous area of 1002 km(2) in Bome County, eastern Tibetan Plateau. A multispectral image from Sentinel-2B, a digital elevation model, and machine learning algorithms such as random forest and convolutional neural network, were utilized. Taking only 5&#37; of the study area as the training zone, AutoSMILE yielded an extraordinarily satisfactory result over the rest of the study area: the producers accuracy, users accuracy, intersection over union and overall accuracy reached 99.42&#37;, 98.78&#37;, 98.21&#37; and 98.76&#37;, respectively, at object level, corresponding to 98.84&#37;, 98.35&#37;, 97.23&#37; and 98.07&#37;, respectively, at pixel level. The model trained in Bome County was subsequently used to map snow at the Qimantag Mountain region in the northern Tibetan Plateau, and a high overall accuracy of 97.22&#37; was achieved. AutoSMILE outperformed threshold-based methods at both sites and exhibited superior performance especially in handling complex land covers. The outstanding performance and robustness of AutoSMILE in the case studies suggest that AutoSMILE is a fast and reliable tool for large-scale high-accuracy snow mapping and monitoring.
WOS:000735166300001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="75">
<title>Landslide susceptibility zonation around Dharamshala, Himachal Pradesh, India: an artificial intelligence model-based assessment</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10064-022-02806-9</url>
<snippet>Landslide susceptibility zonation (LSZ) is a prerequisite for sustainable development and disaster management, especially in mountainous settings. In recent landslide literature, due to the shortcomings of qualitative, statistical, and probabilistic approaches, artificial intelligence (AI) techniques are widely applied for geographic information system-based LSZ. Dharamshala, state capital of Himachal, is one of Indias fastest-growing tourist hotspots in Himalaya where developmental activities are taking place at a rapid pace. Increased pressure of urbanization and re-occurrence of slope instability problems demand systemic landslide hazard evaluation in this area. In this respect, GIS-based LSZ has been attempted for this area using different AI models: fuzzy set procedure (FSP), the fuzzy expert system (FES), and artificial neural network (ANN). To create the landslide susceptibility map (LSM), 9 causative factors and landslide inventory were defined using remote sensing and field data. A total of 12 LSMs were generated, then validated and compared statistically with the help of area under the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve and frequency ratio (FR) analysis, and also in terms of spatial distribution quality to depict an accurate map for the study area. The comparative analysis shows that ANN performs better than the other two models, and LSM-ANN-I is the best map for the research area. The northern section, made of metamorphic rocks like slate and phyllite, with a high slope, is more prone to landslides, whereas the southern part, comprised sandstone, shale, on gentle slopes, has minimal landslide susceptibility.
WOS:000824909300001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="76">
<title>Evaluation of neural network models for landslide susceptibility assessment</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/17538947.2022.2062467</url>
<snippet>Identifying and assessing the disaster risk of landslide-prone regions is very critical for disaster prevention and mitigation. Owning to their special advantages, neural network algorithms have been widely used for landslide susceptibility mapping (LSM) in recent decades. In the present study, three advanced neural network models popularly used in relevant studies, i.e. artificial neural network (ANN), one dimensional convolutional neural network (1D CNN) and recurrent neural network (RNN), were evaluated and compared for LSM practice over the Qingchuan County, Sichuan province, China. Extensive experimental results demonstrated satisfactory performances of these three neural network models in accurately predicting susceptible regions. Specifically, ANN and 1D CNN models yielded quite consistent LSM results but slightly differed from those of RNN model spatially. Nevertheless, accuracy evaluations revealed that the RNN model outperformed the other two models both qualitatively and quantitatively but its complexity was relatively high. Experiments concerning training hyper-parameters on the performance of neural network models for LSM suggested that relatively small batch size values with Tanh activation function and SGD optimizer are essential to improve the performance of neural network models for LSM, which may provide a thread to help those who apply these advanced algorithms to improve their efficiency.
WOS:000812794800001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="77">
<title>Research on Landslide Risk Assessment Based on Convolutional Neural Network</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/LGRS.2022.3185052</url>
<snippet>Landslide risk assessment (LRA) is of great significance to reduce the loss of landslide disaster and improve the effect of disaster prevention and reduction. At present, there are few studies on LRA, and the theories and methods need to be innovated. In view of this, convolutional neural network (CNN) is applied to LRA. Based on nine landslide hazard conditioning factors and five vulnerability conditioning factors, a CNN framework suitable for LRA (LR-CNN framework) was constructed by using the Bayesian method to optimize the CNN hyperparameters. In order to obtain more stable model and assessment results, a five-fold cross-validation method was adopted. The LR-CNN framework and the risk expression of the United Nations Department of Humanitarian Affairs (risk expression of UNDHA) method were applied to Tumen, China, and the two methods were analyzed and compared. From the rationality test results, both methods meet the rationality test standard. From the landslide risk mapping, both methods can obtain better LRA results. From the area within each risk class, the LR-CNN framework is slightly inferior to risk expression of UNDHA method, but from the perspective of landslide distribution and landslide density, the LR-CNN framework is superior to risk expression of UNDHA method. It can be seen that the application of CNN to LRA is feasible and superior to the risk expression of UNDHA method to a certain extent.
WOS:000819823700007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="78">
<title>Landslide Detection Mapping Employing CNN, ResNet, and DenseNet in the Three Gorges Reservoir, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2021.3117975</url>
<snippet>Landslide detection mapping (LDM) is the basis of the field of landslide disaster prevention; however, it has faced certain difficulties. The Three Gorges Reservoir area of the Yangtze River has been one of the most intensively evaluated areas for landslide prevention in the world, due to the high frequency of landslide disasters here. In this article, we constructed an accurate LDM model based on convolutional neural networks, residual neural networks, and dense convolutional neural networks (DenseNets) that considers "ZY-3" high spatial resolution (HSR) data and conditioning factors (CFs). In this article, 19 factors based on remote sensing (RS) images, topographical and geological data associated with historical landslide locations were randomly divided into training (70&#37; of total) and testing (30&#37;) datasets. The experimental results show that the accuracy (ACC) of these three LDM models is above 0.95, indicating that the deep neural networks aimed at landslide detection performed well. Furthermore, DenseNet with RS images and CFs can accurately detect landslides. Specifically, DenseNet with RS images and CFs outperforms the other five models by considering the evaluation metrics, which exhibited Kappa coefficient improvements of 0.01-0.04 and ACC improvements of 0.02-0.3&#37;. Among all the factors, elevation factor has a high importance of 0.727, which is the most important factors found in this landslide model construction experiment.
WOS:000720519100011
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="79">
<title>COMPARISON OF DATA-DRIVEN LANDSLIDE SUSCEPTIBILITY ASSESSMENT USING WEIGHT OF EVIDENCE, INFORMATION VALUE, FREQUENCY RATIO AND CERTAINTY FACTOR METHODS</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.13168/AGG.2021.0021</url>
<snippet>Landslide susceptibility assessment is essential for development activities and disaster management in the mountainous regions to identify the landslide-prone areas. The present study aimed to evaluate and compare the efficacy of data driven quantitative models of landslide susceptibility assessment using geospatial tools in Jhelum valley of the Himalayas. This area suffers from extreme rainfall events due to the local climate and has experienced significant and widespread landslide events in recent years. Four probabilistic data-driven models are employed for this purpose, which includes the weight of evidence (WOE), information value method (IVM), frequency ratio (FR), and certainty factor (CF). These assessed models are based on integrating landslide contributing factors and a ground truthing-based landslide inventory of 437 landslides. The landslide susceptibility maps were presented by categorizing the study area into very low to very high susceptibility zone by Jenks natural breaks method. The performance of models was evaluated by a sensitivity analysis using Receiver Operator Curve (ROC) method. The ROC validated results of success rate curves for WOE, IVM, FR and CF were 80 &#37;, 78 &#37;, 77 &#37;, and 76 &#37; respectively. The prediction rate curve of WOE, IVM, FR, and CF was 78 &#37;, 77 &#37;, 75 &#37;, and 78 &#37; respectively. The results showed the reasonable efficiency of applied models for landslide susceptibility assessment in the study area and applicable to regions with similar geomorphological conditions. Conclusively, the comparison of applied models revealed the promising results of used approaches.
WOS:000729653600002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="80">
<title>Machine learning methods for landslide susceptibility studies: A comparative overview of algorithm performance</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.earscirev.2020.103225</url>
<snippet>Landslides are one of the catastrophic natural hazards that occur in mountainous areas, leading to loss of life, damage to properties, and economic disruption. Landslide susceptibility models prepared in a Geographic Information System (GIS) integrated environment can be key for formulating disaster prevention measures and mitigating future risk. The accuracy and precision of susceptibility models is evolving rapidly from opinion-driven models and statistical learning toward increased use of machine learning techniques. Critical reviews on opinion-driven models and statistical learning in landslide susceptibility mapping have been published, but an overview of current machine learning models for landslide susceptibility studies, including background information on their operation, implementation, and performance is currently lacking. Here, we present an overview of the most popular machine learning techniques available for landslide susceptibility studies. We find that only a handful of researchers use machine learning techniques in landslide susceptibility mapping studies. Therefore, we present the architecture of various Machine Learning (ML) algorithms in plain language, so as to be understandable to a broad range of geoscientists. Furthermore, a comprehensive study comparing the performance of various ML algorithms is absent from the current literature, making an assessment of comparative performance and predictive capabilities difficult. We therefore undertake an extensive analysis and comparison between different ML techniques using a case study from Algeria. We summarize and discuss the algorithms accuracies, advantages and limitations using a range of evaluation criteria. We note that tree-based ensemble algorithms achieve excellent results compared to other machine learning algorithms and that the Random Forest algorithm offers robust performance for accurate landslide susceptibility mapping with only a small number of adjustments required before training the model.
WOS:000556899700018
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="81">
<title>Application of Support Vector Regression and Metaheuristic Optimization Algorithms for Groundwater Potential Mapping in Gangneung-si, South Korea</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/rs13061196</url>
<snippet>The availability of groundwater is of concern. The demand for groundwater in Korea increased by more than 100&#37; during the period 1994-2014. This problem will increase with population growth. Thus, a reliable groundwater analysis model for regional scale studies is needed. This study used the geographical information system (GIS) data and machine learning to map groundwater potential in Gangneung-si, South Korea. A spatial correlation performed using the frequency ratio was applied to determine the relationships between groundwater productivity (transmissivity data from 285 wells) and various factors. This study used four topography factors, four hydrological factors, and three geological factors, along with the normalized difference wetness index and land use and soil type. Support vector regression (SVR) and metaheuristic optimization algorithms-namely, grey wolf optimization (GWO), and particle swarm optimization (PSO), were used in the construction of the groundwater potential map. Model validation based on the area under the receiver operating curve (AUC) was used to determine model accuracy. The AUC values of groundwater potential maps made using the SVR, SVR_GWO, and SVR_PSO algorithms were 0.803, 0.878, and 0.814, respectively. Thus, the application of optimization algorithms increased model accuracy compared to the standard SVR algorithm. The findings of this study improve our understanding of groundwater potential in a given area and could be useful for policymakers aiming to manage water resources in the future.
WOS:000651982700001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="82">
<title>Examining the Spatially Varying Relationships between Landslide Susceptibility and Conditioning Factors Using a Geographical Random Forest Approach: A Case Study in Liangshan, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/rs15061513</url>
<snippet>Landslide susceptibility assessment is an important means of helping to reduce and manage landslide risk. The existing studies, however, fail to examine the spatially varying relationships between landslide susceptibility and its explanatory factors. This paper investigates the spatial variation in such relationships in Liangshan, China, leveraging a spatially explicit model, namely, geographical random forest (GRF). By comparing with random forest (RF), we found that GRF achieves a higher performance with an AUC of 0.86 due to its consideration of the spatial heterogeneity among variables. GRF also provides a higher-quality landslide susceptibility map than RF by correctly placing 92.35&#37; of the landslide points in high-susceptibility areas. The local feature importance derived from GRF allows us to understand that the impact of conditioning factors varies across space, which can provide implications for policy development by local governments to place different levels of attention on different conditioning factors in specific counties to prevent and mitigate landslides. To account for the spatial dependence among the data in the model performance assessment, we use spatial cross-validation (CV) to split the data into subsets spatially rather than randomly for model training and testing. The results show that spatial CV can effectively address the over-optimistic bias in model error evaluation.
WOS:000958190300001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="83">
<title>Mapping landslides through a temporal lens: an insight toward multi-temporal landslide mapping using the u-net deep learning model</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/15481603.2023.2182057</url>
<snippet>Repeated temporal mapping of landslides is essential for investigating changes in landslide movements, legacy effects of the landslide triggering events, and susceptibility changes in the area. However, in order to perform such investigations, multi-temporal (MT) inventories of landslides are required. The traditional approach of visual interpretation from cloud-free optical remote sensing imageries is time consuming and expensive. Recent endeavors exploring Convolutional Neural Networks and deep learning models have made rapid and accurate mapping of landslides feasible but have not been applied for multi-temporal landslide mapping in the Himalayas, yet. Earlier models used a standard supervised learning approach, with a small landslide inventory over a limited area used for training, which is then utilized to predict landslides in nearby areas. We propose a new strategy, using geographically separate training samples to design a standard approach which can be utilized to create multi-temporal landslide inventories. RapidEye images of 5-meters spatial resolution are used to generate MT landslide inventories in the study area of Rasuwa district, Nepal. We test the effectiveness of the model by training with only 55 landslides and predicting for a different area. Then, using the weights attained from this first training phase, we use transfer learning to map landslides over a time period between 2013 and 2019 in the Rasuwa district attaining an average F1-score of 0.69 for the study area. We also perform a spatial comparison between the manual (observed) and predicted inventories to evaluate the differences between landslide densities and overall landslide statistics of landslide area distribution. The benefit of a transfer learning-based model training is that it circumvents the need for generating annual inventories for training a deep learning. A single event-based inventory is enough to generate landslide inventories over a number of years, at least until landslide conditioning factors do not change significantly. This application can enable automated workflows to generate MT landslide inventories of particular areas as the basis for landslide evolution and movement change analysis.
WOS:000948627500001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="84">
<title>Mine landslide susceptibility assessment using IVM, ANN and SVM models considering the contribution of affecting factors</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0215134</url>
<snippet>The fragile ecological environment near mines provide advantageous conditions for the development of landslides. Mine landslide susceptibility mapping is of great importance for mine geo-environment control and restoration planning. In this paper, a total of 493 landslides in Shangli County, China were collected through historical landslide inventory. 16 spectral, geomorphic and hydrological predictive factors, mainly derived from Landsat 8 imagery and Global Digital Elevation Model (ASTER GDEM), were prepared initially for landslide susceptibility assessment. Predictive capability of these factors was evaluated by using the value of variance inflation factor and information gain ratio. Three models, namely artificial neural network (ANN), support vector machine (SVM) and information value model (IVM), were applied to assess the mine landslide sensitivity. The receiver operating characteristic curve (ROC) and rank probability score were used to validate and compare the comprehensive predictive capabilities of three models involving uncertainty. Results showed that ANN model achieved higher prediction capability, proving its advantage of solve nonlinear and complex problems. Comparing the estimated landslide susceptibility map with the ground-truth one, the high-prone area tends to be located in the middle area with multiple fault distributions and the steeply sloped hill.
WOS:000464095000042
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="85">
<title>Deep convolutional neural network-based pixel-wise landslide inventory mapping</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10346-020-01557-6</url>
<snippet>This paper reports a feasible alternative to compile a landslide inventory map (LIM) from remote sensing datasets using the application of an artificial intelligence-driven methodology. A deep convolutional neural network model, called LanDCNN, was developed to generate segmentation maps of landslides, and its performance was compared with the benchmark model, named U-Net, and other conventional object-based methods. The landslides that occurred in Lantau Island, Hong Kong, were taken as the case study, in which the pre- and post-landslide aerial images, and a rasterized digital terrain model (DTM) were used. The assessment reveals that LanDCNN trained with bitemporal images and DTM yields the smoothest and most semantically meaningfully LIM, compared to other methods. This LIM is the most balanced segmentation results, represented by the highest F-1 measure among all analyzed cases. With the encoding capability of LanDCNN, the application of DTM as the input renders better LIM production, especially when the landslide signatures are relatively subtle. With the computational setup used in this study, LanDCNN requires similar to 3 min to map landslides from the datasets of approximately 25 km(2) in area and with a resolution of 0.5 m. In short, the proposed landslide mapping framework, featured LanDCNN, is scalable to handle the vast amount of remote sensing data from different types of measurements within a short processing period.
WOS:000584932700001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="86">
<title>Evaluation of different DEMs for gully erosion susceptibility mapping using in-situ field measurement and validation</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoinf.2021.101425</url>
<snippet>The spatial variability in any kind of geomorphic studies based on terrain attributes are the most important issues. This terrain attributes and their respective characteristics play a significant role in the formation and expansion of ephemeral gullies. Therefore, nowadays, the accuracy of terrain based geomorphic studies has been mostly dependent on the resolution and quality of the DEM (digital elevation model) data. As the rate of erosional power of water flow is dependent on the terrain characteristics, therefore the extraction of several terrain features from DEM data is necessary in the study of gully erosion. This case study investigates the scaledependence of DEM-derived terrain factors in gully erosion susceptibility (GES). This work on Garhbeta-I C.D. Block has focused on the comparison among the predicted GES maps through five types of DEM i.e. Shuttle Radar Topography Mission (SRTM), Advanced Spaceborne Thermal Emission and Reflection Radiometer (ASTER), Cartosat-1, ALOS World 3D-30 m (AW3D30) and Advanced Land Observation satellite (ALOS) coupled with the machine learning modelling approach of artificial neural network (ANN), convolution neural network (CNN) and deep learning neural network (DLNN) algorithm. A total of sixteen conditioning factors were chosen for GES assessment based on the topographical, hydro-climatological conditions and multi-collinearity analysis. Here, importance variables are measured by mean decrease accuracy (MDA) method of random forest (RF) algorithm and the result is shown that elevation is the most important factor for gully occurrences. Validation result of receiver operating characteristics-area under curve (ROC-AUC) has been indicates that DLNN model in ALOS DEM (AUC = 0.958) gives the most optimal accuracy in GES assessment. The output maps can assist in identifying gully-prone risk areas, and several suitable with sustainable managements should be taken for conservation accordingly.
WOS:000704529300003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="87">
<title>A comparative study of composite kernels for landslide susceptibility mapping: A case study in Yongxin County, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.catena.2019.104217</url>
<snippet>In this study, an effective kernel-based learning framework for landslide susceptibility mapping (LSM) is presented through an implementation of support vector machines (SVMs) with different composite kernels. Kernel-based classification methods are very popular in statistical classification and regression analysis because they can effectively address intractable issues such as the curse of dimensionality, limited known samples and noise corruption. The most representative of such methods is the SVM technique. Although SVMs have recently been widely used in LSM, they were defined using only the attribute value of each influencing factor and did not consider the high dependency between the adjacent vector-valued grid cells. This caused a labelling uncertainty. To solve this problem, it is necessary to combine both the influencing factors attribute features and spatial dependency information in the SVM. In this work, we present two forms of composite kernels to combine the two aforementioned types of information: 1) constructed through a single kernel with stacked vectors; 2) built through summation kernels under different restrictions. The main advantages of the proposed framework are twofold. First, the integration of the two types of information can improve the predictive capability of the SVMs by removing the isolated class noise in the LSM results. Second, other useful information can be extracted from the spatial domain, such as the structural features of grid cells within and outside of landslide areas. The SVM comparisons were based on data from Yongxin County, China, containing 364 past landslide occurrences that were separated randomly into a training set (70&#37;) and a validation set (30&#37;). The geo-environmental setting of the study area was analysed and sixteen influencing factors were selected. The validation of these SVMs was performed using the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) and the area under the ROC curve (AUC). Experimental results demonstrate that all the SVM-based landslide susceptibility maps have similar spatial distributions upon visual inspection. Specifically, the mountainous zones in the north and south of the study area are characterized by high and very high susceptibility values, respectively, whereas the central part of the study area is categorized as the least susceptible zone. Meanwhile, the composite kernel-based learning framework can achieve a better prediction accuracy than the original SVM. From quantitative analysis, the four SVMs with a summation kernel obtain the AUC values above 0.8900, which is 0.0117 higher than that of the original SVM. Furthermore, a weighted scheme in the summation kernel can result in AUC values that are at least 0.0014 higher than a directional scheme.
WOS:000488417700031
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="88">
<title>Impact of Land Use/Land Cover Change on Landslide Susceptibility in Rangamati Municipality of Rangamati District, Bangladesh</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijgi11020089</url>
<snippet>Landslide susceptibility depends on various causal factors such as geology, land use/land cover (LULC), slope, and elevation. Unlike other factors that are relatively stable over time, LULC is a dynamic factor associated with human activities. This study evaluates the impact of LULC change on landslide susceptibility in the Rangamati municipality of Rangamati district, Bangladesh, based on three LULC scenarios-the existing (2018) LULC, the proposed LULC (proposed in 2010, but not yet implemented), and the simulated LULC of 2028-using artificial neural network (ANN)-based cellular automata. The random forest model was used for landslide susceptibility mapping. The model showed good accuracy for all three LULC scenarios (existing: 82.7&#37;; proposed: 81.4&#37;; and 2028: 78.3&#37;) and strong positive correlations (&gt;0.8) between different landslide susceptibility maps. LULC is either the third or fourth most important factor in these scenarios, suggesting that is has a moderate impact on landslide susceptibility. Future LULC changes will likely increase landslide susceptibility, with up to 14.5&#37; increases in the high susceptibility zone for both the proposed and simulated LULC scenarios. These findings may help policymakers carry out proper urban planning and highlight the importance of considering landslide susceptibility in LULC planning.
WOS:000769019200001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="89">
<title>Spatial prediction of groundwater potential and driving factor analysis based on deep learning and geographical detector in an arid endorheic basin</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ecolind.2022.109256</url>
<snippet>Substantial mineral resources are enriched in the arid endorheic basins; however, due to environmental constraints, these areas face water shortages as well as its extremely uneven spatiotemporal distribution, which restricts the development of local industry and agriculture. Identifying these areas of the high groundwater potential are useful for groundwater supply and its sustainable planning. In this study, the Qaidam Basin in Northwest China was taken as an example. We collected 17 conditioning factors (i.e., precipitation, evaporation, geology, soil, Topographic Wetness Index, Fractional Vegetation Cover, distance to rivers, river density, distance to roads, road density, distance to faults, fault density, slope, curvature, residential density, landcover, and geomorphology) affecting groundwater resources in arid areas. We also collected 139 groundwater samples and used random forest (RF), deep neural network (DNN) and convolutional neural network (CNN) (associated with one-hot encoding) to predict the groundwater potential in this area. The Qaidam Basin was discretized into 420,000 sample points calculated in turn by the above three models. Receiver operating characteristic (ROC) and area under the curve (AUC) were used to test the accuracy of the three methods. Results indicated that the prediction scores for the three methods were 0.742, 0.790, and 0.817, and the AUC was 0.783, 0.811, and 0.846, respectively. The result provided by CNN was more precise than the results provided by RF and DNN. Additionally, this study aims to investigate the effects of the aforementioned factors on groundwater potential. A total of 17 factors were combined with the Geodetector model to quantify their impacts and interactions on the groundwater potential of the Qaidam Basin. Results revealed that the critical factors affecting groundwater potential in the Qaidam Basin were geomorphology (0.183) and evaporation (0.144), and their combined contribution was 0.457. The influence of arbitrary two-factors on groundwater potential is larger than that of themselves, demonstrating linear or nonlinear enhancement between them and confirming that the factor selections were sensible. The method based on CNN-Geodetector provides a novel approach for calculating groundwater potential, selecting appropriate evaluation indicators and quantifying the driving factors in the arid endorheic basins.
WOS:000872003000001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="90">
<title>Artificial neural networks applied to landslide susceptibility: The effect of sampling areas on model capacity for generalization and extrapolation</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.apgeog.2021.102598</url>
<snippet>Artificial neural networks (ANNs) have been used to identify areas susceptible to landslides and constitute one of the most widely used methods for this purpose. Several factors can interfere in the performance of the models and their resulting maps (especially sampling). This research evaluated the influence of sampling areas on landslide susceptibility modelling and the capacity for generalization and spatial extrapolation of data. Based on an inventory of landslide scars, distributed in five areas of southern Brazil, non-occurrence samples were defined by means of different buffers (2-40 km) in relation to the landslides in order to test the effect of the spatial distribution of the non-occurrence samples on the modeling results. A total of 16 morphometric attributes of the terrain (extracted from a digital elevation model) were used as input variables of the model. Multilayered network training was carried out using a backpropagation algorithm and accuracy was calculated by means of the Area Under the Receiver Operating Characteristic Curve (AUROC). Model accuracy was between 0.739 and 0.931. This variation was explained mainly by the buffer used. The susceptibility map resulting from the model of greater accuracy was obtained with a 40-km buffer in order to collect non-occurrence samples. The great distance between the occurrence and non-occurrence samples facilitates the modelling, since it increases the morphometric differences between the sampling groups. When we used samples from only one of the sample areas, the spatial extrapolation of the susceptibility map to the other areas showed high performance. We conclude that the ANN model for landslides susceptibility mapping can be extrapolated spatially, considering the limits of the geomorphological unit or numerical domain of the data.
WOS:000720473700005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="91">
<title>Flood Uncertainty Estimation Using Deep Ensembles</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/w14192980</url>
<snippet>We propose a probabilistic deep learning approach for the prediction of maximum water depth hazard maps at high spatial resolutions, which assigns well-calibrated uncertainty estimates to every predicted water depth. Efficient, accurate, and trustworthy methods for urban flood management have become increasingly important due to higher rainfall intensity caused by climate change, the expansion of cities, and changes in land use. While physically based flood models can provide reliable forecasts for water depth at every location of a catchment, their high computational burden is hindering their application to large urban areas at high spatial resolution. While deep learning models have been used to address this issue, a disadvantage is that they are often perceived as "black-box" models and are overconfident about their predictions, therefore decreasing their reliability. Our deep learning model learns the underlying phenomena a priori from simulated hydrodynamic data, obviating the need for manual parameter setting for every new rainfall event at test time. The only inputs needed at the test time are a rainfall forecast and parameters of the terrain such as a digital elevation model to predict the maximum water depth with uncertainty estimates for complete rainfall events. We validate the accuracy and generalisation capabilities of our approach through experiments on a dataset consisting of catchments within Switzerland and Portugal and 18 rainfall patterns. Our method produces flood hazard maps at 1 m resolution and achieves mean absolute errors as low as 21 cm for extreme flood cases with water above 1 m. Most importantly, we demonstrate that our approach is able to provide an uncertainty estimate for every water depth within the predicted hazard map, thus increasing the models trustworthiness during flooding events.
WOS:000867389400001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="92">
<title>Comparison of Statistical Analysis Models for Susceptibility Assessment of Earthquake-Triggered Landslides: A Case Study from 2015 Earthquake in Lefkada Island</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/geosciences9080350</url>
<snippet>The main purpose of this study is to comparatively assess the susceptibility of earthquake-triggered landslides in the island of Lefkada (Ionian Islands, Greece) using two different statistical analysis models, a bivariate model represented by frequency ratio (FR), and a multivariate model represented by logistic regression (LR). For the implementation of the models, the relationship between geo-environmental factors contributing to landslides and documented events related to the 17th November 2015 earthquake was investigated by geographic information systems (GIS)-based analysis. A landslide inventory with events attributed to the specific earthquake was prepared using satellite imagery interpretation and field surveys. Eight factors: Elevation, slope angle, slope aspect, distance to main road network, distance to faults, land cover, geology, and peak ground acceleration (PGA), were considered and used as thematic data layers. The prediction capability of the models and the accuracy of the resulting susceptibility maps were tested by a standard validation method, the receiver operator characteristic (ROC) analysis. Based on the validation results, the output map with the highest reliability could potentially constitute an ideal basis for use within regional spatial planning as well as for the organization of emergency actions by local authorities.
WOS:000482981000007
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="93">
<title>Radon potential mapping in Jangsu-gun, South Korea using probabilistic and deep learning algorithms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.envpol.2021.118385</url>
<snippet>The adverse health effects associated with the inhalation and ingestion of naturally occurring radon gas produced during the uranium decay chain mean that there is a need to identify high-risk areas. This study detected radon-prone areas using a geographic information system (GIS)-based probabilistic and machine learning methods, including the frequency ratio (FR) model and a convolutional neural network (CNN). Ten influencing factors, namely elevation, slope, the topographic wetness index (TWI), valley depth, fault density, lithology, and the average soil copper (Cu), calcium oxide (Cap), ferric oxide (Fe2O3), and lead (Pb) concentrations, were analyzed. In total, 27 rock samples with high activity concentration index values were divided randomly into training and validation datasets (70:30 ratio) to train the models. Areas were categorized as very high, high, moderate, low, and very low radon areas. According to the models, approximately 40&#37; of the study area was classified as very high or high risk. Finally, the radon potential maps were validated using the area under the receiver operating characteristic curve (AUC) analysis. This showed that the CNN algorithm was superior to the FR method; for the former, AUC values of 0.844 and 0.840 were obtained using the training and validation datasets, respectively. However, both algorithms had high predictive power. Slope, lithology, and TWI were the best predictors of radon-affected areas. These results provide new information regarding the spatial distribution of radon, and could inform the development of new residential areas. Radon screening is important to reduce public exposure to high levels of naturally occurring radiation.
WOS:000711677600003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="94">
<title>A robust discretization method of factor screening for landslide susceptibility mapping using convolution neural network, random forest, and logistic regression models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/17538947.2023.2174192</url>
<snippet>The selection of discretization criteria and interval numbers of landslide-related environmental factors generally fails to quantitatively determine or filter, resulting in uncertainties and limitations in the performance of machine learning (ML) methods for landslide susceptibility mapping (LSM). The aim of this study is to propose a robust discretization criterion (RDC) to quantify and explore the uncertainty and subjectivity of different discretization methods. The RDC consists of two steps: raw classification dataset generation and optimal dataset extraction. To evaluate the robustness of the proposed RDC method, Lushan County of Sichuan Province in China was chosen as the study area to generate the LSM based on three datasets (optimal dataset, original dataset with continuous values, and statistical dataset) using three popular ML methods, namely, convolution neural network, random forest, and logistic regression. The results show that the areas under the receiver operating characteristic curve (AUCs) of the optimal dataset for the abovementioned ML models are 0.963, 0.961, and 0.930 which are higher than those of the original dataset (0.938, 0.947, and 0.900) and statistical dataset (0.948, 0.954, and 0.897). In conclusion, the RDC method can extract the more representative features from environmental factors and outperform the other conventional discretization methods.
WOS:000940225400001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="95">
<title>Recognition and Mapping of Landslide Using a Fully Convolutional DenseNet and Influencing Factors</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2021.3101203</url>
<snippet>The recognition and mapping of landslide (RML) is an important task in hazard and risk research and can provide a scientific basis for the prevention and control of landslide disasters. However, traditional RML methods are inefficient, costly, and not intuitive. With the rapid development of computer vision, methods based on convolutional neural networks have attracted great attention due to their numerous advantages. However, problems such as insufficient feature extraction, excessive parameters, and slow model testing have restricted the development of this technology. This research proposes a new RML framework based on a new semantic segmentation network termed the fully convolutional DenseNet (FC-DenseNet). In this network, the features extracted from each layer are repeatedly used in a dense connection, and the parameters are controlled by a bottle-neck structure. Meanwhile, the structure of the encoder-decoder solves the problem of the slowness of model testing. Finally, the landslide influencing factors are added, which enriches the training data. To verify the effectiveness of the proposed method, we focused on several deep networks for comparison and analysis. The results show that FC-DenseNet can better recognize the boundary and interior of landslides, and there are fewer missing and excessive recognition results. The kappa value of the new method is 94.72&#37; in Site 1, which is 6&#37; and 4&#37; higher than that of U-Net and ResU-Net, respectively, and 94.56&#37; in Site 2, which is 6&#37; and 3&#37; higher than that of U-Net and ResU-Net, respectively, indicating that FC-DenseNet has great potential in RML applications.
WOS:000686757500008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="96">
<title>Application of a two-step sampling strategy based on deep neural network for landslide susceptibility mapping</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10064-022-02615-0</url>
<snippet>The selection of nonlandslide samples is a key issue in landslide susceptibility modeling (LSM). In view of the potential subjectivity and randomness in random sampling, this paper considers LSM as a positive-unlabeled (PU) learning problem and proposes a two-step deep neural network framework (T-DNN). Through the Spy technique and iteratively training binary classifiers, negative samples with high confidence were identified from the random subsamples with unlabeled sets. Based on the framework and traditional random sampling, we used logistic regression (LR), support vector machine (SVM), and deep neural network (DNN) models for testing and validation. Taking the Changbai Mountain Area in Jilin Province, China, as an example, according to the regional landslide list and the metrological, geographical, and human factors of frequent disasters, landslide susceptibility was evaluated. Results show that the proposed T-DNN method can enhance the selection of negative samples and make the results of landslide susceptibility assessment more reliable and accurate; the area under the receiver operating characteristic curve (AUC) reaches 0.953. In addition, compared with traditional random negative sample sampling, the optimized sample set shows more stable and superior prediction performance in different classifiers.
WOS:000768826600003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="97">
<title>The influence of DEM spatial resolution on landslide susceptibility mapping in the Baxie River basin, NW China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-020-03899-9</url>
<snippet>The selection of an appropriate map resolution is highly important for landslide susceptibility assessment. No consistent objective criteria, however, are currently applied to the choice of map resolution. This research, in conjunction with slope units, explores the effect of digital elevation model (DEM) resolution on susceptibility modelling using three statistical models (frequency ratio, index of entropy, and weight of evidence). Seven different spatial resolutions (30, 40, 50, 60, 70, 80, and 90 m) and three statistical models are investigated. For each resolution, we compare the performance of the three models using area under curve (AUC) analysis. The results show that, independent of the statistical models, the best performances are produced at 70 m DEM resolution. This highlights that finer resolutions do not necessarily lead to higher predictive accuracy in landslide susceptibility mapping. Rather, the frequency ratio model seems to be optimal for the coarser resolutions (i.e. 70, 80, and 90 m).
WOS:000520808000002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="98">
<title>Comparative review of data-driven landslide susceptibility models: case study in the Eastern Andes mountain range of Colombia</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-022-05339-2</url>
<snippet>Estimating the likelihood of landslides has proven to be critical for development and protection of infrastructure (e.g. pipelines, roads) and urban settlements. Currently, for regional studies of landslide susceptibility only qualitative or statistical evaluations are possible due to the large spatial variability of geological properties, topography, rainfall patterns, etc. In this paper, we explore an alternative to these approaches using data-driven methodologies to determine landslide susceptibility. We give special attention to the use of geographical information systems, machine learning and statistical techniques to build landslide susceptibility maps. These methods have input as fourteen key causative factors that might influence landslides occurrence. Additionally, feature extraction and feature selection are performed to evaluate if dimensionality reduction increases the prediction accuracy of the machine learning models. The models were compared using a case study in the Eastern Cordillera of Colombia, where the best performing model achieved a predictive performance of 93.07&#37;.
WOS:000778087100002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="99">
<title>Landslide Detection Using Densely Connected Convolutional Networks and Environmental Conditions</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2021.3079196</url>
<snippet>A complete and accurate landslide map is necessary for landslide susceptibility and risk assessment. Currently, deep learning faces the dilemma of insufficient application, scarce samples, and poor efficiency in landslide recognition. This article utilizes the advantages of dense convolutional networks (DenseNets) and their modified technique to solve the three proposed problems. For this purpose, we created a new landslide sample library. On the original remote sensing image, 12 geological, topographic, hydrological and land cover factors that can directly or indirectly reflect the landslide are superimposed. Then, landslide detection was carried out in the three Gorges reservoir area in China to test the performance of the improved method. The quantitative evaluation of the landslide detection map shows that the combination of environmental factors and DenseNet can improve the accuracy of the detection model. Compared with the optical image, kappa and F1 increased by 9.7&#37; and 9.1&#37; respectively. Compared with other traditional neural networks and machine learning algorithms, DenseNet has the highest kappa and F1 values. Based on the base Densenet, through data augmentation and fine-tuning optimization technology, the kappa and F1 values reach the highest values of 0.9474 and 0.9505, respectively. The proposed method has promising applicability in large area landslide identification scenarios.
WOS:000658340600008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="100">
<title>TCIANet: Transformer-Based Context Information Aggregation Network for Remote Sensing Image Change Detection</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2023.3241157</url>
<snippet>Change detection based on remote sensing data is an important method to detect the earth surface changes. With the development of deep learning, convolutional neural networks have excelled in the field of change detection. However, the existing neural network models are susceptible to external factors in the change detection process, leading to pseudo change and missed detection in the detection results. In order to better achieve the change detection effect and improve the ability to discriminate pseudo change, this article proposes a new method, namely, transformer-based context information aggregation network for remote sensing image change detection. First, we use a filter-based visual tokenizer to segment each temporal feature map into multiple visual semantic tokens. Second, the addition of the progressive sampling vision transformer not only effectively excludes the interference of irrelevant changes, but also uses the transformer encoder to obtain compact spatiotemporal context information in the token set. Then, the tokens containing rich semantic information are fed into the pixel space, and the transformer decoder is used to acquire pixel-level features. In addition, we use the feature fusion module to fuse low-level semantic feature information to complete the extraction of coarse contour information of the changed region. Then, the semantic relationships between object regions and contours are captured by the contour-graph reasoning module to obtain feature maps with complete edge information. Finally, the prediction model is used to discriminate the change of feature information and generate the final change map. Numerous experimental results show that our method has more obvious advantages in visual effect and quantitative evaluation than other methods.
WOS:000940195200003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="101">
<title>Effect of time and space partitioning strategies of samples on regional landslide susceptibility modelling</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10346-021-01627-3</url>
<snippet>Assessment of the spatial probability of future landslide occurrences for disaster risk reduction is done through landslide susceptibility modelling. In this study, we investigated the effect of time and space partitioning strategies of samples on the performance of regional landslide susceptibility models on macro-scale mapping in the state of Mizoram, India, covering 21,087 km(2) area. We used landslide inventory data of 2014 and 2017 periods consisting of 1205 and 2265 landslides, respectively, to train and test the models with four sampling strategies such as spatial, temporal, temporal (size constrained) and temporal (geographic constrained). We used five commonly inherited models such as multiclass weighted overlay (MCWO), information value (IV), weights of evidence (WoE), logistic regression (LR) and artificial neural network (ANN) to evaluate the effect of sampling strategies on the model performance for regional landslide susceptibility mapping. Validation of model performance was done using receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve. Traditional spatial sampling strategy applied to landslides in 2014 with a random split in 70:30 proportion provided a high performance of all the five models but failed to predict landslides in 2017. The landslide incidences in 2017, when used for model validation either entirely or in different split conditions (both size and geographic constrained), provided consistent performance, even though the testing sample size is large or have a different spatial disposition, if the training was carried out with non-linear susceptibility models such as LR and ANN using landslide incidences in 2014. Results show the importance of sample selection during validation of landslide susceptibility models on a regional scale.
WOS:000612890400002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="102">
<title>Landslide Susceptibility Mapping Using GIS-Based Data Mining Algorithms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/w11112292</url>
<snippet>The aim of this study was to apply data mining algorithms to produce a landslide susceptibility map of the national-scale catchment called Bandar Torkaman in northern Iran. As it was impossible to directly use the advanced data mining methods due to the volume of data at this scale, an intermediate approach, called normalized frequency-ratio unique condition units (NFUC), was devised to reduce the data volume. With the aid of this technique, different data mining algorithms such as fuzzy gamma (FG), binary logistic regression (BLR), backpropagation artificial neural network (BPANN), support vector machine (SVM), and C5 decision tree (C5DT) were employed. The success and prediction rates of the models, which were calculated by receiver operating characteristic curve, were 0.859 and 0.842 for FG, 0.887 and 0.855 for BLR, 0.893 and 0.856 for C5DT, 0.891 and 0.875 for SVM, and 0.896 and 0.872 for BPANN that showed the highest validation rates as compared with the other methods. The proposed approach of NFUC proved highly efficient in data volume reduction, and therefore the application of computationally demanding algorithms for large areas with voluminous data was feasible.
WOS:000502264500094
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="103">
<title>Integration of an InSAR and ANN for Sinkhole Susceptibility Mapping: A Case Study from Kirikkale-Delice (Turkey)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/ijgi10030119</url>
<snippet>Suitable route determination for linear engineering structures is a fundamental problem in engineering geology. Rapid evaluation of alternative routes is essential, and novel approaches are indispensable. This study aims to integrate various InSAR (Interferometric Synthetic Aperture Radar) techniques for sinkhole susceptibility mapping in the Kirikkale-Delice Region of Turkey, in which sinkhole formations have been observed in evaporitic units and a high-speed train railway route has been planned. Nine months (2019-2020) of ground deformations were determined using data from the European Space Agencys (ESA) Sentinel-1A/1B satellites. A sinkhole inventory was prepared manually using satellite optical imagery and employed in an ANN (Artificial Neural Network) model with topographic conditioning factors derived from InSAR digital elevation models (DEMs) and morphological lineaments. The results indicate that high deformation areas on the vertical displacement map and sinkhole-prone areas on the sinkhole susceptibility map (SSM) almost coincide. InSAR techniques are useful for long-term deformation monitoring and can be successfully associated in sinkhole susceptibility mapping using an ANN. Continuous monitoring is recommended for existing sinkholes and highly susceptible areas, and SSMs should be updated with new results. Up-to-date SSMs are crucial for the route selection, planning, and construction of important transportation elements, as well as settlement site selection, in such regions.
WOS:000633711500001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="104">
<title>Data Integration for Lithological Mapping Using Machine Learning Algorithms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12145-022-00826-3</url>
<snippet>The aim of this study is to compare and evaluate the performances of different classification algorithms (Maximum Likelihood Classification [MLC], Random Forest [RF], Support Vector Machine [SVM], and Neural Network [NN]) with data integration for lithological classification in partly vegetated areas. The optical (ASTER), SAR (Sentinel-1) images and Digital Elevation Model (DEM) data were used as classification inputs. The study area used in this work is located in the western part of Antalya Province of Turkey and is characterized by relatively high relief and good exposure of numerous lithological classes. Five data sets were used for input to the classifiers: (1) Sentinel-1 image with its polarimetric bands (i.e. VV, HH, VH, HV), (2) ASTER image, (3) ASTER image with DEM, (4) the integration of ASTER and Sentinel-1 images, and (5) the integration of ASTER, DEM and Sentinel-1 data. Classification of the five input data sets by each of the four classifiers generated a total of 20 output images. The SVM algorithm produced the best overall classification accuracies (averaging 94.18&#37; of three models for all data integrated) and the MLC algorithm produced the worst classification accuracy (averaging 35.75&#37; of three models when using the Sentinel-1 polarimetric images as input). Regardless of the classifier algorithms, the accuracy values obtained in the classification using only ASTER data were found to be between 81.34&#37; and 88.09&#37; for averaging all models. On the other hand, when Sentinel-1 and DEM data were added to the optical data sets, the classification accuracies for the average of all models increased to values between 90.18&#37; and 94.18&#37;.
WOS:000821993900002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="105">
<title>Mapping of earthquake hotspot and coldspot zones for identifying potential landslide hotspot areas in the Himalayan region</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10064-022-02761-5</url>
<snippet>Landslide and earthquake are two of the dangerous natural hazards in the Himalayan mountainous ranges. This study focused on small-scale landslide susceptibility (LS) maps as well as hotspot zones of earthquake and landslide on the Himalayas. Remote sensing, geological, and hydrological data were collected and processed using the geographic information system (GIS) for this purpose. Seventeen landslide influential causative factors (LICFs) were used, which included slope, aspect, elevation, profile curvature, plan curvature, topographic wetness index (TWI), stream power index (SPI), terrain ruggedness index (TRI), drainage density, distance to drainage, seismic zone, soil texture, geology, and land use and land cover (LULC). The machine learning (ML) neural network and deep learning models, namely, linear discriminant analysis (LDA), quadratic discriminant analysis (QDA), artificial neural network (ANN), deep learning neural network (DLNN), and Getis-Ord GI*, have been applied for landslide susceptibility (LS) maps, and earthquake and landslide hotspot maps respectively of the Himalayas. The LS maps were compared with the earthquake and landslide hotspot zones, and there is valid agreement among these. The results of the susceptibility mapping were validated by the confusion matrix table and sensitivity, specificity, accuracy, precession, F score, and kappa statistical indices. The validation result showed that all the landslide susceptibility models (LSMs) have a near 90&#37; prediction rate. Among the four models, the DLNN models have the highest prediction accuracy followed by LDA, QDA, and ANN. The small-scale LS maps of the Himalayas may help planners and developers for macro-scale mitigation of landslide hazard and land use planning.
WOS:000805929700001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="106">
<title>Slide type landslide susceptibility assessment of the Buyuk Menderes watershed using artificial neural network method</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11356-022-19248-1</url>
<snippet>The Buyuk Menderes watershed is the largest drainage watershed in Western Anatolia with an area of approximately 26,000 km(2). In the study area, almost 863 landslides occurred, extending over 222 km(2) with a mean landslide area of 0.21 km(2). In this study, landslide susceptibility assessments were carried out using artificial neural network method, which is one of the data-driven methods. In this study, that will contribute to the mitigation or control of the landslides caused by the reasons controlling the spatial and temporal distribution of landslides created in the GIS and MATLAB environment by using scientific and technological approaches within the framework. Since derivative activation function is also used in back-propagation artificial neural networks, its derivative is easily calculated in order not to slow down the calculation. Levenberg-Marquardt back-propagation (LM), resilient back propagation back-propagation (trainrp), scaled conjugate gradient back-propagation (trainscg), conjugate gradient with Powell/Beale restarts back-propagation (traincgb), and Fletcher-Powell conjugate gradient back-propagation (traincgf) algorithms are used, which constantly interrogate the link between the input parameter and the result output, and at least one cells output is given as an input to any other cell. Geology, digital elevation model, slope, topographic wetness index, roughness index, plan, profile curvatures, and proximity to active faults and rivers were used as landslide conditioning factors. In susceptibility assessments, landslides were separated by 70&#37; analysis, 15&#37; test, and 15&#37; validation datasets by random selection method. The performances of the landslide susceptibility maps were assessed by the area under the ROC curve (AUC), accuracy (ACC), precision, recall, F1 score, Kappa test error histogram, and confusion matrix, respectively. The area under the receiver operating characteristic curves, analysis, testing, validation, landslides, and study areas were found between 0.873 and 0.911. The susceptibility map had a high prediction rate in which high and very high susceptible zones corresponded to 26&#37; of the study area including 82&#37; of the recorded landslides.
WOS:000757202000015
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="107">
<title>GIS-based comparative study of information value and frequency ratio method for landslide hazard zonation in a part of mid-Himalaya in Himachal Pradesh</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s41062-019-0215-2</url>
<snippet>The road network of a developing country plays a vital role in its overall development. It is therefore important to ascertain landslide hazard assessment along a road network. Landslide hazard zonation focuses on preparing landslide hazard map by considering major instability factors causing the landslides. The present study deals with geographical information systems-based landslide hazard zonation of the study area. The study area comes under the mid-Himalayan region of Himachal Pradesh, India. The slope failures create major havoc every year due to high frequency of landslides along the road. Eight major landslide-causing factors have been identified for the study area, which includes slope, relative relief, curvature, aspect, drainage density, lithology, lineament density, and land use/land cover. Corresponding to each landslide causative factor, a layer has been prepared and landslide hazard zonation maps of the study area were evolved by using frequency ratio and information value methods. Approximately, 75&#37; of the total landslides which occurred in the study area were used for training purpose, and remaining 25&#37; were used for the validation of results using the area under curve technique. The developed landslide hazard zonation maps show satisfactory agreement with the landslide inventory of the study area. The success rate curve obtained for frequency ratio method is 77.18&#37;, and for information value method, it is 74.76&#37;. The validation of result illustrates that frequency ratio method is more accurate as compared to information value method for the study area. The present study shows that geographical information system provides a better environment for modelling of the statistical techniques, that is, frequency ratio and information value method in the present study.
WOS:000465252900001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="108">
<title>Landslide Mapping Using Two Main Deep-Learning Convolution Neural Network Streams Combined by the Dempster-Shafer Model</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1109/JSTARS.2020.3043836</url>
<snippet>Beyond the direct hazards of earthquakes, the deposited mass of earthquake-induced landslide (EQIL) in the riverbeds causes the river to thrust upward. The EQIL inventories are generated mostly by the traditional or semisupervised mapping approaches, which required a parameters tuning or binary threshold decision in the practical application. In this study, we investigated the impact of optical data from the PlanetScope sensor and topographic factors from the ALOS sensor on EQIL mapping using a deep-learning convolution neural network (CNN). Thus, six training datasets were prepared and used to evaluate the performance of the CNN model using only optical data and using these data along with each and all topographic factors across the west coast of the Trishuli river in Nepal. For the first time, the Dempster-Shafer (D-S) model was applied for combining the resulting maps from each CNN stream that trained with different datasets. Finally, seven different resulting maps were compared against a detailed and accurate inventory of landslide polygons by a mean intersection-over-union (mIOU). Our results confirm that using the training dataset of the spectral information along with the topographic factor of the slope is helpful to distinguish the landslide bodies from other similar features, such as barren lands, and consequently increases the mapping accuracy. The improvement of the mIOU was a range from approximately zero to more than 17&#37;. Moreover, the D-S model can be considered as an optimizer method to combine the results from different scenarios.
WOS:000607413900015
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="109">
<title>Machine learning and fractal theory models for landslide susceptibility mapping: Case study from the Jinsha River Basin</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2019.106975</url>
<snippet>The quality of "non-landslide" negative samples may result in unreasonable prediction results for machine learning (ML) models. The aim of this study is to improve the performance of ML models by perfecting the quality of "non-landslide" samples in landslide susceptibility modelling so as to produce more reliable susceptibility maps. The middle and lower reaches of Jinsha River basin (MLRJB) were chosen as the study area, and the elevation, slope aspect, curvature, lithology, distance to faults, slope of slope, slope of aspect, precipitation, land use, and NDVI were considered as predisposing factors for landslide susceptibility mapping. Firstly, three "non-landslide" samples are randomly selected from the low-slope area, landslide-free area and very low susceptibility area based on fractal theory (FT) model generation, and then three sample scenarios are constructed with 4445 landslide positive samples. Next, the performance of cross-application of three sample scenarios in the support vector machines (SVM) and naive Bayes (NB) models are compared and evaluated based on the statistical indicators such as accuracy, recall, precision, receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve, and area under the ROC curve (AUC). The evaluation results show that the "non-landslide" negative samples generated on the basis of FT model are more reasonable and that the hybrid method supported by FT and ML models exhibits the highest prediction efficiency, around 94&#37; overall accuracy produced by scenario-FT, followed by scenario-SS (87&#37;) and scenario-RS (65&#37;). Finally, with the validation of landslide and unstable slopes data, the landslide susceptibility map produced by the hybrid method composed of FT model and the SVM model is the ultimate output product for landslide prevention. (C) 2019 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000514254300029
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="110">
<title>Flood Susceptibility Mapping Using Image-Based 2D-CNN Deep Learning: Overview and Case Study Application Using Multiparametric Spatial Data in Data-Scarce Urban Environments</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1155/2023/5672401</url>
<snippet>This study presents results for urban flood susceptibility mapping (FSM) using image-based 2D-convolutional neural networks (2D-CNN). The model input multiparametric spatial data comprised of land-useland-cover (LULC), digital elevation model (DEM), and the topographic and hydrologic conditioning derivatives, precipitation, and soil types. The implemented dropout regularization 2D-CNN with ReLU activation function, categorical cross-entropy loss function, and AdaGrad optimizer produced the case study area FSM with overall accuracy (OA) of 82.5&#37;. The image-based 2D-CNN outperformed the multilayer perceptron (MLP) neural network by 18.4&#37; in terms of overall accuracy and with corresponding lower MAE and higher F1-measures of 10.9&#37; and 0.989, as compared to 25.6&#37; and 0.877, respectively, for MLP-ANN results. The accuracy of the 2D-CNN that produced FSM map and the model efficiency were evaluated using area under the ROC curve (AUC) with respective success and prediction rates of 0.827 and 0.809. Using image-based 2D-CNN, 27&#37; of the 247.7 km(2) of the studied area was mapped with a high risk of flooding, with MLP-ANN overestimating the degree of high flood risk by 4.7&#37;. Based on the gain ratio index analysis of the flood conditioning factors (FCFs), the most significant FCFs were LULC (18.5&#37;), precipitation (14.9&#37;), proximity to river (13.3&#37;), and elevation (12.4&#37;). Soil types contributed 8.6&#37;, slope 9.1&#37;, and the DEM-derived hodological conditioning indicators contributed 23.2&#37;. The study results demonstrate that in urban areas with scarce hydrological monitoring networks, the use of image-based 2D-CNN with multiparametric spatial data can produce high-quality flood susceptibility maps for flood management in urban environments.
WOS:000961734200001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="111">
<title>Flash-flood hazard susceptibility mapping in Kangsabati River Basin, India</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10106049.2021.1953618</url>
<snippet>Flood-susceptibility mapping is an important component of flood risk management to control the effects of natural hazards and prevention of injury. We used a remote-sensing and geographic information system (GIS) platform and a machine-learning model to develop a flood susceptibility map of Kangsabati River Basin, India where flash flood is common due to monsoon precipitation with short duration and high intensity. And in this subtropical region, climate changes impact helps to influence the distribution of rainfall and temperature variation. We tested three models-particle swarm optimization (PSO), an artificial neural network (ANN), and a deep-leaning neural network (DLNN)-and prepared a final flood susceptibility map to classify flood-prone regions in the study area. Environmental, topographical, hydrological, and geological conditions were included in the models, and the final model was selected based on the relations between potentiality of causative factors and flood risk based on multi-collinearity analysis. The model results were validated and evaluated using the area under receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curve (AUC), which is an indicator of the current state of the environment and a value &gt;0.95 implies a greater risk of flash floods. The AUC values for ANN, DLNN, and PSO for training datasets were 0.914, 0.920, and 0.942, respectively. Among these three models, PSO showed the best performance with an AUC value of 0.942. The PSO approach is applicable for flood susceptibility mapping of the eastern part of India, a subtropical region, to allow flood mitigation and help to improve risk management in this region.
WOS:000677741800001
</snippet>
</document>

</searchresult>
