<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<searchresult>
<query>Global</query>
<document id="1">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping at Vaz Watershed (Iran) using an artificial neural network model: a comparison between multilayer perceptron (MLP) and radial basic function (RBF) algorithms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-012-0610-x</url>
<snippet>Landslide susceptibility and hazard assessments are the most important steps in landslide risk mapping. The main objective of this study was to investigate and compare the results of two artificial neural network (ANN) algorithms, i.e., multilayer perceptron (MLP) and radial basic function (RBF) for spatial prediction of landslide susceptibility in Vaz Watershed, Iran. At first, landslide locations were identified by aerial photographs and field surveys, and a total of 136 landside locations were constructed from various sources. Then the landslide inventory map was randomly split into a training dataset 70 &#37; (95 landslide locations) for training the ANN model and the remaining 30 &#37; (41 landslides locations) was used for validation purpose. Nine landslide conditioning factors such as slope, slope aspect, altitude, land use, lithology, distance from rivers, distance from roads, distance from faults, and rainfall were constructed in geographical information system. In this study, both MLP and RBF algorithms were used in artificial neural network model. The results showed that MLP with Broyden-Fletcher-Goldfarb-Shanno learning algorithm is more efficient than RBF in landslide susceptibility mapping for the study area. Finally the landslide susceptibility maps were validated using the validation data (i.e., 30 &#37; landslide location data that was not used during the model construction) using area under the curve (AUC) method. The success rate curve showed that the area under the curve for RBF and MLP was 0.9085 (90.85 &#37;) and 0.9193 (91.93 &#37;) accuracy, respectively. Similarly, the validation result showed that the area under the curve for MLP and RBF models were 0.881 (88.1 &#37;) and 0.8724 (87.24 &#37;), respectively. The results of this study showed that landslide susceptibility mapping in the Vaz Watershed of Iran using the ANN approach is viable and can be used for land use planning.
WOS:000322028400012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="2">
<title>GIS based frequency ratio and index of entropy models to landslide susceptibility mapping (Daguan, China)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-016-5580-y</url>
<snippet>The main goal of this study is to produce landslide susceptibility maps by frequency ratio (FR) and index of entropy (IoE) models based on geographic information system (GIS) for the Daguan county of Yunnan province, China. At first, landslide locations were identified by earlier reports and aerial photographs as well as by carrying out field surveys, and a total of 194 landside locations were constructed from various sources. Then the landslide inventory map was randomly split into a training dataset 70 &#37; (136 landslide locations) for training the FR and IoE models and the remaining 30 &#37; (58 landslides locations) were used for validation purposes. Fifteen landslide conditioning factors were constructed in GIS. The susceptibility maps produced using FR and IoE models were divided into five different susceptibility classes such as very low, low, moderate, high, and very high. Finally, the validation of landslide susceptibility maps was carried out based on training dataset and the validation data using the area under the curve (AUC) method. The success rate curve showed that the area under the curve for FR and IoE models were 0.8191 and 0.8109 accuracy, respectively. Similarly, the validation result showed that the prediction accuracy of the two models was 81.75 &#37; for FR model and 81.44 &#37; for IoE model, respectively. The maps produced by both models exhibits better satisfactory properties. The landslide susceptibility maps may be useful for planning purposes for environmental protection and natural hazard mitigation studies in the near future.
WOS:000376030100057
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="3">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping at Gongliu county, China using artificial neural network and weight of evidence models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12303-016-0003-3</url>
<snippet>The aim of this study was to apply and to verify the use of artificial neural network (ANN) and weight of evidence (WoE) models to landslide susceptibility mapping in the Gongliu county, China, using a geographic information system (GIS). For this aim, in this study, a landslide inventory map was prepared using earlier reports and aerial photographs as well as by carrying out field surveys. A total of 163 landslides (70&#37; out of 233 detected landslides) were randomly selected for model training, and the remaining 70 landslides (30&#37;) were used for the model validation. Then, a total number of twelve landslide conditioning factors, such as slope angle, slope aspect, general curvature, plan curvature, profile curvature, altitude, distance to rivers, distance to roads, lithology, rainfall, normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI), and sediment transport index (STI), were used in the analysis. Landslide hazardous areas were analyzed and mapped using the landslide-occurrence factors by ANN and WoE models. Finally the output maps were validated using the area under the curve (AUC) method. The validation results showed that the ANN model with a success rate of 82.51&#37; and predictive accuracy of 77.31&#37; performs better than WoE (success rate, 79.82&#37;; predictive accuracy, 74.59&#37;) model. Overall, both models showed almost similar results. Therefore, the two landslide susceptibility maps obtained were successful and can be useful for preliminary general land use planning and hazard mitigation purpose.
WOS:000384518800010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="4">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping using LiDAR and DMC data: a case study in the Three Gorges area, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-012-2151-8</url>
<snippet>The objective of this study is to map landslide susceptibility in Zigui segment of the Yangtze Three Gorges area that is known as one of the most landslide-prone areas in China by using data from light detection and ranging (LiDAR) and digital mapping camera (DMC). The likelihood ratio (LR) and logistic regression model (LRM) were used in this study. The work is divided into three phases. The first phase consists of data processing and analysis. In this phase, LiDAR and DMC data and geological maps were processed, and the landslide-controlling factors were derived such as landslide density, digital elevation model (DEM), slope angle, aspect, lithology, land use and distance from drainage. Among these, the landslide inventories, land use and drainage were constructed with both LiDAR and DMC data; DEM, slope angle and aspect were constructed with LiDAR data; lithology was taken from the 1:250,000 scale geological maps. The second phase is the logistic regression analysis. In this phase, the LR was applied to find the correlation between the landslide locations and the landslide-controlling factors, whereas the LRM was used to predict the occurrence of landslides based on six factors. To calculate the coefficients of LRM, 13,290,553 pixels was used, 29.5 &#37; of the total pixels. The logical regression coefficients of landslide-controlling factors were obtained by logical regression analysis with SPSS 17.0 software. The accuracy of the LRM was 88.8 &#37; on the whole. The third phase is landslide susceptibility mapping and verification. The mapping result was verified using the landslide location data, and 64.4 &#37; landslide pixels distributed in "extremely high" zone and "high" zone; in addition, verification was performed using a success rate curve. The verification result show clearly that landslide susceptibility zones were in close agreement with actual landslide areas in the field. It is also shown that the factors that were applied in this study are appropriate; lithology, elevation and distance from drainage are primary factors for the landslide susceptibility mapping in the area, while slope angle, aspect and land use are secondary.
WOS:000323737300019
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="5">
<title>GIS-based landslide susceptibility evaluation using fuzzy-AHP multi-criteria decision-making techniques in the Abha Watershed, Saudi Arabia</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-018-7451-1</url>
<snippet>Landslides are natural geological disasters causing massive destructions and loss of lives, as well as severe damage to natural resources, so it is essential to delineate the area that probably will be affected by landslides. Landslide susceptibility mapping (LSM) is making increasing implications for GIS-based spatial analysis in combination with multi-criteria evaluation (MCE) methods. It is considered to be an effective tool to understand natural disasters related to mass movements and carry out an appropriate risk assessment. This study is based on an integrated approach of GIS and statistical modelling including fuzzy analytical hierarchy process (FAHP), weighted linear combination and MCE models. In the modelling process, eleven causative factors include slope aspect, slope, rainfall, geology, geomorphology, distance from lineament, distance from drainage networks, distance from the road, land use/land cover, soil erodibility and vegetation proportion were identified for landslide susceptibility mapping. These factors were identified based on the (1) literature review, (2) the expert knowledge, (3) field observation, (4) geophysical investigation, and (5) multivariate techniques. Initially, analytical hierarchy process linked with the fuzzy set theory is used in pairwise comparisons of LSM criteria for ranking purposes. Thereafter, fuzzy membership functions were carried out to determine the criteria weights used in the development of a landslide susceptibility map. These selected thematic maps were integrated using a weighted linear combination method to create the final landslide susceptibility map. Finally, a validation of the results was carried out using a sensitivity analysis based on receiver operator curves and an overlay method using the landslide inventory map. The study results show that the weighted overlay analysis method using the FAHP and eigenvector method is a reliable technique to map landslide susceptibility areas. The landslide susceptibility areas were classified into five categories, viz. very low susceptibility, low susceptibility, moderate susceptibility, high susceptibility, and very high susceptibility. The very high and high susceptibility zones account for 15.11&#37; area coverage. The results are useful to get an impression of the sustainability of the watershed in terms of landsliding and therefore may help decision makers in future planning and mitigation of landslide impacts.
WOS:000429985900013
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="6">
<title>Spatial data analysis and application of evidential belief functions to shallow landslide susceptibility mapping at Mt. Umyeon, Seoul, Korea</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10064-016-0919-x</url>
<snippet>Predictive mapping of landslide occurrence at the regional scale was performed at Mt. Umyeon, in the southern part of Seoul, Korea, using an evidential belief function (EBF) model. To generate the landslide susceptibility map, approximately 90 &#37; of 163 actual landslide locations were randomly selected as a training set, and about 10 &#37; of them were used as a validation set. Spatial data sets relevant to landslide occurrence (topographic factors, hydrologic factors, forest factors, soil factors, and geologic factors) were analyzed in a geographic information system environment. In this study, landslide susceptibility was assessed on the basis of mass function assignment (belief, disbelief, uncertainty, and plausibility) and integration within a data-driven approach. The most representative of the resulting integrated susceptibility maps (the belief map) was validated using the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) method. The verification result showed that the model had an accuracy of 74.3 &#37; and a predictive accuracy of 88.1 &#37;. The frequency ratio (FR) model was also used for comparison with the EBF model. Prediction and success rates of 72.1 and 85.9 &#37; were achieved using the FR model. The validation results showed satisfactory agreement between the susceptibility map and the existing landslide location data. The EBF model was more accurate than the FR model for landslide prediction in the study area. The results of this study can be used to mitigate landslide-induced hazards and for land-use planning.
WOS:000413673700004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="7">
<title>Landslide susceptibility delineation in the Ar-Rayth area, Jizan, Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, using analytical hierarchy process, frequency ratio, and logistic regression models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-014-4008-9</url>
<snippet>Mountain areas in the southern western corner of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia (KSA) frequently suffer from various types of landsides induced by rainstorms and anthropogenic activities. To mitigate these problems, landslide susceptibility mapping and classification is important to develop quick and safe mitigation or remediation measures and to help the decision making in future planning by identifying the most vulnerable areas. This paper summarizes the findings of a landslide susceptibility analysis in the Ar-Rayth area, Jizan, KSA, using an analytical hierarchy process (AHP), frequency ratio (FR), and logistic regression (LR) models with the aid of GIS tools and remote sensing data. The landslide inventory map was prepared according to historical data, interpretation of high-resolution satellite images (Geo-Eye 0.5 m resolution and QuickBird 0.6 m resolution), topographic maps (1:10,000), and verified by field investigations. An inventory map with 253 landslides locations was extracted from many sources. The landslide inventory was randomly divided into two datasets: 75 &#37; for training the models and 25 &#37; for validation. An enhanced thematic mapper plus 15 m satellite image acquired in 2006 was used for determining the Normalized Difference Vegetation Index. A contour map (1:10,000 with a 10 m contour interval) was converted to digital elevation model 10 m resolution and subsequently converted to slope, slope aspect, curvature, elevation, and drainage networks. Geological data obtained with the help of satellite images were used to prepare lithological units and lineaments. Roads were digitized from the high-resolution image and a rainfall map was prepared from the rainfall gauges distributed throughout the study area. All these data were used to construct a spatial database using GIS and image processing. Three landslide susceptibility maps were constructed; one on the basis of a heuristic method using an AHP, the other two on the basis of landslide inventories and causative factors, using FR and LR. Furthermore, each causative factors weight was determined according to these three models and landslide susceptibility indices were calculated. For verification, receiver operating characteristic curves were calculated and the areas under the curve (AUC) for success rate are 0.755, 0.828, and 0.749 and for prediction rate are 0.708, 0.781, and 0.727 for the AHP, FR, and LR, respectively. In addition, the percentage of existing training landslides data in high and very high zones of the susceptibility maps is of 73.2, 85.31, and 88.59 &#37; and for the validation landslides data is 73.2, 85.31, and 88.59 &#37; for the AHP, FR, and LR, respectively. The findings indicated that the values of AUC are above 0.7 for both success and prediction rate which indicate these three models are suitable for susceptibility analysis. Also, percent of training and validation landslides data of high and very high zones indicate that LR model is more accurate followed by FR model and AHP model.
WOS:000355142800068
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="8">
<title>Application of analytical hierarchy process, frequency ratio, and certainty factor models for groundwater potential mapping using GIS</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12145-015-0220-8</url>
<snippet>The main goal of this study was to investigate the analytical hierarchy process (AHP), frequency ratio (FR), and certainty factor (CF) models for groundwater potential mapping using geographical information system (GIS) at Varamin Plain, Tehran province, Iran. In the first step, the groundwater conditioning factors such as altitude, slope angle, slope aspect, topographic witness index, rainfall, drainage density, water table level, aquifer thickness, lithology, and distance from rivers were prepared. The groundwater yield dataset was prepared using earlier reports, and extensive field surveys. In total, 71 groundwater data with high potential yield values of a parts per thousand yen40 m(3)/h were collected and mapped in GIS. Out these, 50 (70 &#37;) cases were randomly selected for models training, and the remaining 21 (30 &#37;) cases were used for the validation purposes. Subsequently, groundwater potential maps were produced using AHP, FR, and CF models in ArcGIS 10.2. Finally, the receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves for all the groundwater potential models were constructed and the areas under the curves (AUC) were computed. From the analysis, it is seen that the FR model (AUC = 77.55 &#37;) performs better than AHP (AUC = 73.47 &#37;) and CF (AUC = 65.08 &#37;) models. The results of groundwater potential map can be helpful for future planning in groundwater resource management and land use planning.
WOS:000365266900012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="9">
<title>A GIS-based comparative evaluation of analytical hierarchy process and frequency ratio models for landslide susceptibility mapping</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/02723646.2017.1294522</url>
<snippet>The purpose of this study is to assess the susceptibility of landslides in Wen County, China, using both analytical hierarchy process (AHP) and frequency ratio (FR) models. For this, a total of 529 landslides were identified and randomly split into two groups. The modeling group, which represented approximately 70&#37; of the total landslides, was used as a training set to construct the susceptibility maps. The remaining 30&#37; were used for validation purpose. Eight layers of landslide-related factors were prepared, including slope angle, altitude, distance to rivers, distance to roads, distance to faults, rainfall, lithology, and normalized difference vegetation index. Subsequently, landslide susceptibility maps were produced using the models. For verification, an area under curvature (AUC) and the seed cell area index (SCAI) assessments were applied. The AUC plot estimation results showed that the success rates of the AHP and FR models were 83.55 and 88.42&#37; and the prediction rates were 83.43 and 86.62&#37;, respectively. According to the validation results of the AUC and SCAI evaluations, the map obtained from the FR model is more accurate than that from the AHP model. These landslide susceptibility maps can be used for optimum management by decision makers and land-use planners.
WOS:000402815500002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="10">
<title>Landslide Susceptibility Mapping in Vertical Distribution Law of Precipitation Area: Case of the Xulong Hydropower Station Reservoir, Southwestern China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/w8070270</url>
<snippet>This study focused on landslide susceptibility analysis mapping of the Xulong hydropower station reservoir, which is located in the upstream of Jinsha River, a rapidly uplifting region of the Tibetan Plateau region. Nine factors were employed as landslide conditioning factors in landslide susceptibility mapping. These factors included the slope angle, slope aspect, curvature, geology, distance-to-fault, distance-to-river, vegetation, bedrock uplift and annual precipitation. The rapid bedrock uplift factor was represented by the slope angle. The eight factors were processed with the information content model. Since this area has a significant vertical distribution law of precipitation, the annual precipitation factor was analyzed separately. The analytic hierarchy process weighting method was used to calculate the weights of nine factors. Thus, this study proposed a component approach to combine the normalized eight-factor results with the normalized annual precipitation distribution results. Subsequently, the results were plotted in geographic information system (GIS) and a landslide susceptibility map was produced. The evaluation accuracy analysis method was used as a validation approach. The landslide susceptibility classes were divided into four classes, including low, moderate, high and very high. The results show that the four susceptibility class ratios are 12.9&#37;, 35.06&#37;, 34.11&#37; and 17.92&#37; of the study area, respectively. The red belt in the high elevation area represents the very high susceptibility zones, which followed the vertical distribution law of precipitation. The prediction accuracy was 85.74&#37;, which meant that the susceptibility map was confirmed to be reliable and reasonable. This susceptibility map may contribute to averting the landslide risk in the future construction of the Xulong hydropower station.
WOS:000380764800003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="11">
<title>GIS-based landslide susceptibility assessment in Seoul, South Korea, applying the radius of influence to frequency ratio analysis</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-015-5149-1</url>
<snippet>The objective of this paper is to map landslide susceptibility using a statistical analysis model and the radius of influence within a geographic information systems environment. The statistical analysis included triggering factors (e.g., topography, land cover, forest, and soil properties) of adjacent areas, in addition to the landslide sites themselves. To estimate the probability of landslide occurrence using the radius of influence, and to produce a landslide susceptibility index (LSI), we performed frequency radio (FR) analysis by applying the radius of influence to the domain of specific training sites. Landslide susceptibility maps were generated for each radius of influence, ranging from 0 to 300 m in 30 m increments. We observed enhanced FR index values corresponding to reduced exaggeration of statistical anomalies within the proper radius of influence. It is referred that by adopting the radius of influence the classes that not only affect the landslide occurrence from the adjacent areas but also make anomaly errors can be taken into account in FR analysis. Moreover, comparing the FR values between adopting the optimum radius of influence or not, we inferred that the greater the gap, the bigger influence of adjacent areas the classes have. In the validation stage, we identified the optimum radius of influence by measuring the area beneath the relative operating characteristics curve. We found that the optimum radius of influence in the study area is 240 m, for which the LSI map is 5.95 &#37; points more accurate than when not considering the radius of influence.
WOS:000371393400032
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="12">
<title>A case study for the integration of predictive mineral potential maps</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.2478/s13533-012-0183-y</url>
<snippet>This study aims to elaborate on the mineral potential maps using various models and verify the accuracy for the epithermal gold (Au) - silver (Ag) deposits in a Geographic Information System (GIS) environment assuming that all deposits shared a common genesis. The maps of potential Au and Ag deposits were produced by geological data in Taebaeksan mineralized area, Korea. The methodological framework consists of three main steps: 1) identification of spatial relationships 2) quantification of such relationships and 3) combination of multiple quantified relationships. A spatial database containing 46 Au-Ag deposits was constructed using GIS. The spatial association between training deposits and 26 related factors were identified and quantified by probabilistic and statistical modelling. The mineral potential maps were generated by integrating all factors using the overlay method and recombined afterwards using the likelihood ratio model. They were verified by comparison with test mineral deposit locations. The verification revealed that the combined mineral potential map had the greatest accuracy (83.97&#37;), whereas it was 72.24&#37;, 65.85&#37;, 72.23&#37; and 71.02&#37; for the likelihood ratio, weight of evidence, logistic regression and artificial neural network models, respectively. The mineral potential map can provide useful information for the mineral resource development.
WOS:000340387900009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="13">
<title>Landslide susceptibility assessment using frequency ratio, statistical index and certainty factor models for the Gangu County, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-015-2112-0</url>
<snippet>The purpose of this paper is to produce a reliable susceptibility mapping using frequency ratio (FR), statistical index (SI), and certainty factor (CF) models with the aid of geographic information system (GIS) for the Gangu County, Gansu Province, China. First, a total of 328 landslide locations were detected by literatures, aerial photographs and field surveys; meanwhile, a landslide inventory map was constructed mainly based on landslide locations. Then, 230 (70 &#37;) landslides were randomly selected for modeling, and the remaining 98 (30 &#37;) landslides were used for the model validation. In order to produce a susceptibility map, 12 landslide influencing factors were selected from the database: slope angle, slope aspect, plan curvature, profile curvature, altitude, distance to faults, distance to rivers, distance to roads, NDVI, land use, rainfall, and lithology. Whereafter, the landslide susceptibility maps were mapped using landslide influencing factors based on the FR, SI, and CF models. Finally, the accuracy of the landslide susceptibility maps developed from the three models was validated using area under the curve (AUC) analysis. Through the analysis, it is seen that the prediction accuracy of the three models was 75.62&#37; for FR model, 75.71&#37; for SI model, and 75.56 &#37; for CF model, respectively. According to the results, three models show almost similar results, while SI model performs slightly better than other models and the map produced by SI model represents the most appropriate properties. In addition, the study area was classified into five classes, such as very low, low, moderate, high, and very high. The landslide susceptibility maps can be helpful to select site and mitigate landslide hazards in the study area.
WOS:000371380500002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="14">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping based on GIS and information value model for the Chencang District of Baoji, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-014-1369-z</url>
<snippet>The main objective of this study was to apply a statistical (information value) model using geographic information system (GIS) to the Chencang District of Baoji, China. Landslide locations within the study area were identified using reports and aerial photographs, and a field survey. A total of 120 landslides were mapped, of which 84 (70 &#37;) were randomly selected for building the landslide susceptibility model. The remaining 36 (30 &#37;) were used for model validation. We considered a total of 10 potential factors that predispose an area to a landslide for the landslide susceptibility mapping. These included slope degree, altitude, slope aspect, plan curvature, geomorphology, distance from faults, lithology, land use, mean annual rainfall, and peak ground acceleration. Following an analysis of these factors, a landslide susceptibility map was produced using the information value model with GIS. The resulting landslide susceptibility index was divided into five classes (very high, high, moderate, low, and very low) using the natural breaks method. The corresponding distribution area percentages were 29.22, 25.14, 15.66, 15.60, and 14.38 &#37;, respectively. Finally, landslide locations were used to validate the results of the landslide susceptibility map using areas under the curve (AUC). The AUC plot showed that the susceptibility map had a success rate of 81.79 &#37; and a prediction accuracy of 82.95 &#37;. Based on the results of the AUC evaluation, the landslide susceptibility map produced using the information value model exhibited good performance.
WOS:000344476700004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="15">
<title>The spatial prediction of landslide susceptibility applying artificial neural network and logistic regression models: A case study of Inje, Korea</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1515/geo-2016-0010</url>
<snippet>The aim of this study is to predict landslide susceptibility caused using the spatial analysis by the application of a statistical methodology based on the GIS. Logistic regression models along with artificial neutral network were applied and validated to analyze landslide susceptibility in Inje, Korea. Landslide occurrence area in the study were identified based on interpretations of optical remote sensing data (Aerial photographs) followed by field surveys. A spatial database considering forest, geophysical, soil and topographic data, was built on the study area using the Geographical Information System (GIS). These factors were analysed using artificial neural network (ANN) and logistic regression models to generate a landslide susceptibility map. The study validates the landslide susceptibility map by comparing them with landslide occurrence areas. The locations of landslide occurrence were divided randomly into a training set (50&#37;) and a test set (50&#37;). A training set analyse the landslide susceptibility map using the artificial network along with logistic regression models, and a test set was retained to validate the prediction map. The validation results revealed that the artificial neural network model (with an accuracy of 80.10&#37;) was better at predicting landslides than the logistic regression model (with an accuracy of 77.05&#37;). Of the weights used in the artificial neural network model, slope yielded the highest weight value (1.330), and aspect yielded the lowest value (1.000). This research applied two statistical analysis methods in a GIS and compared their results. Based on the findings, we were able to derive a more effective method for analyzing landslide susceptibility.
WOS:000371283300012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="16">
<title>A comparative study on the landslide susceptibility mapping using logistic regression and statistical index models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-017-2961-9</url>
<snippet>The logistic regression and statistical index models are applied and verified for landslide susceptibility mapping in Daguan County, Yunnan Province, China, by means of the geographic information system (GIS). A detailed landslide inventory map was prepared by literatures, aerial photographs, and supported by field works. Fifteen landslide-conditioning factors were considered: slope angle, slope aspect, curvature, plan curvature, profile curvature, altitude, STI, SPI, and TWI were derived from digital elevation model; NDVI was extracted from Landsat ETM7; rainfall was obtained from local rainfall data; distance to faults, distance to roads, and distance to rivers were created from a 1: 25,000 scale topographic map; the lithology was extracted from geological map. Using these factors, the landslide susceptibility maps were prepared by LR and SI models. The accuracy of the results was verified by using existing landslide locations. The statistical index model had a predictive rate of 81.02&#37;, which is more accurate prediction in comparison with logistic regression model (80.29&#37;). The models can be used to land-use planning in the study area.
WOS:000400266200003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="17">
<title>Application of frequency ratio, statistical index, and index of entropy models and their comparison in landslide susceptibility mapping for the Baozhong Region of Baoji, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-014-1554-0</url>
<snippet>The main goal of this study was to produce landslide susceptibility mapping by frequency ratio (FR), statistical index (SI), and index of entropy (IOE) models based on geographic information system (GIS) for the Baozhong region of Baoji, China. At first, a landslide inventory map was prepared using earlier reports and aerial photographs as well as by carrying out a field survey. A total of 79 landslides were mapped and out of which, 55 (70 &#37;) were randomly selected for building landslide susceptibility models, while the remaining 24 (30 &#37;) were used for validating the models. In this case study, the following landslide conditioning factors were evaluated: slope degree, slope aspect, plan curvature, altitude, geomorphology, lithology, distance from faults, distance from rivers, and precipitation. Subsequently, landslide susceptibility maps were produced using FR, SI, and IOE models. Finally, the validation of landslide susceptibility map was carried out using areas under the curve (AUC). The AUC plot estimation results showed that the susceptibility map using FR model has the highest prediction accuracy of 82.49 &#37;, followed by the SI model (81.43 &#37;) and the IOE model (79.62 &#37;). Similarly, the AUC plot showed that the success rate of the three models was 84.95 &#37; for FR model, 82.37 &#37; for SI model, and 82.05 &#37; for IOE model, respectively. According to the validation results of the AUC evaluation, the map produced by the FR model exhibits the most satisfactory properties. These landslide susceptibility maps can be used for preliminary land use planning and hazard mitigation purpose.
WOS:000352640900001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="18">
<title>A small-scale landslide susceptibility assessment for the territory of Western Carpathians</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-013-0751-6</url>
<snippet>This study presented herein compares the bivariate and multivariate landslide susceptibility mapping methods and presents the landslide susceptibility map of the territory of Western Carpathians in small scale. This study also describes pioneer work for the territory of Western Carpathians, overreaching state borders, using verified sophisticated statistical methods. In the susceptibility mapping, digital elevation model was first constructed using a GIS software, and parameter maps affecting the slope stability such as geology, seismicity, precipitation, topographical elevation, slope angle, slope aspect and land cover were considered. In the last stage of the analyses, landslide susceptibility maps were produced using bivariate and multivariate analyses, and they were then compared by means of their validations. The validation of the bivariate analysis data was performed using the results of bivariate analysis for landslide areas of Slovakia containing five classes of susceptibility in scale 1:500,000. The validation area is the area of Western Carpathians within Slovakia. Eighty-two per cent of area does not differ in more than one class. The validation of the multivariate analysis data was performed using the results from the Kysuce region in the northern part of Slovakia in scale 1:10,000. The raster calculator was used to express the difference between each pair of pixels within these two layers. Seventy-seven per cent of the pixels do not differ in more than 25 &#37;, 94 &#37; of the pixels do not differ in more than 50 &#37;. The maximal possible difference is 100 &#37; (one pixel with value 0 and other with value 1, or vice versa). Receiver operating characteristic analysis was also performed, the area under curve value for bivariate model was calculated to be 0.735, while it was 0.823 for multivariate. The results of the validation can be considered as satisfactory.
WOS:000325101100056
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="19">
<title>Different landslide sampling strategies in a grid-based bi-variate statistical susceptibility model</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2015.10.030</url>
<snippet>This study had three aims. The first was to assess the performance of the weights-of-evidence (WofE) landslide susceptibility model in areas that are very different in terms of size, geoenvironmental settings, and landslide types. The second was to test the appropriate strategies to sample the mapped landslide polygon. The final aim was to evaluate the performance of the method to changes in the landslide sample size used to train the model. The method was applied to two areas: the Fella River basin (eastern Italian Alps) containing debris flows, and Buzau County (Romanian Carpathians) with shallow landslides. The three landslide sampling strategies used were: (1) the landslide scarp centroid, (2) points populating the scarp on a 50-m grid, and (3) the entire scarp polygon. The highest success rates were obtained when sampling shallow landslides as 50-m grid-points and debris flow scarps as polygons. Prediction rates were highest when using the entire scarp polygon method for both landslide types. The sample size test using the landslide centroids showed that a sample of 104 debris flow scarps was sufficient to predict the remaining 941 debris flows in the Fella River basin, while 161 shallow landslides was the minimum required number to predict the remaining 1451 scarps in Buzau County. Below these landslide sample thresholds, model performance was too low. However, using more landslides than the threshold produced a plateau effect with little to no increase in the model performance rates. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000367114100041
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="20">
<title>Exploiting Maximum Entropy method and ASTER data for assessing debris flow and debris slide susceptibility for the Giampilieri catchment (north-eastern Sicily, Italy)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1002/esp.3998</url>
<snippet>This study aims at evaluating the performance of the Maximum Entropy method in assessing landslide susceptibility, exploiting topographic and multispectral remote sensing predictors. We selected the catchment of the Giampilieri stream, which is located in the north-eastern sector of Sicily (southern Italy), as test site. On 1 October 2009, a storm rainfall triggered in this area hundreds of debris flow/avalanche phenomena causing extensive economical damage and loss of life. Within this area a presence-only-based statistical method was applied to obtain susceptibility models capable of distinguishing future activation sites of debris flow and debris slide, which where the main source of failure mechanisms for flow or avalanche type propagation. The set of predictors used in this experiment comprised primary and secondary topographic attributes, derived by processing a high resolution digital elevation model, CORINE land cover data and a set of vegetation and mineral indices obtained by processing multispectral ASTER images. All the selected data sources are dated before the disaster. A spatially random partition technique was adopted for validation, generating 50 replicates for each of the two considered movement typologies in order to assess accuracy, precision and reliability of the models. The debris slide and debris flow susceptibility models produced high performances with the first type being the best fit. The evaluation of the probability estimates around the mean value for each mapped pixel shows an inverted relation, with the most robust models corresponding to the debris flows. With respect to the role of each predictor within the modelling phase, debris flows appeared to be primarily controlled by topographic attributes whilst the debris slides were better explained by remotely sensed derived indices, particularly by the occurrence of previous wildfires across the slope. The overall excellent performances of the two models suggest promising perspectives for the application of presence-only methods and remote sensing derived predictors. Copyright 
WOS:000383616200010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="21">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping using certainty factor, index of entropy and logistic regression models in GIS and their comparison at Mugling-Narayanghat road section in Nepal Himalaya</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-012-0347-6</url>
<snippet>Landslide susceptibility maps are vital for disaster management and for planning development activities in the mountainous country like Nepal. In the present study, landslide susceptibility assessment of Mugling-Narayanghat road and its surrounding area is made using bivariate (certainty factor and index of entropy) and multivariate (logistic regression) models. At first, a landslide inventory map was prepared using earlier reports and aerial photographs as well as by carrying out field survey. As a result, 321 landslides were mapped and out of which 241 (75 &#37;) were randomly selected for building landslide susceptibility models, while the remaining 80 (25 &#37;) were used for validating the models. The effectiveness of landslide susceptibility assessment using GIS and statistics is based on appropriate selection of the factors which play a dominant role in slope stability. In this case study, the following landslide conditioning factors were evaluated: slope gradient; slope aspect; altitude; plan curvature; lithology; land use; distance from faults, rivers and roads; topographic wetness index; stream power index; and sediment transport index. These factors were prepared from topographic map, drainage map, road map, and the geological map. Finally, the validation of landslide susceptibility map was carried out using receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves. The ROC plot estimation results showed that the susceptibility map using index of entropy model with AUC value of 0.9016 has highest prediction accuracy of 90.16 &#37;. Similarly, the susceptibility maps produced using logistic regression model and certainty factor model showed 86.29 and 83.57 &#37; of prediction accuracy, respectively. Furthermore, the ROC plot showed that the success rate of all the three models performed more than 80 &#37; accuracy (i.e. 89.15 &#37; for IOE model, 89.10 &#37; for LR model and 87.21 &#37; for CF model). Hence, it is concluded that all the models employed in this study showed reasonably good accuracy in predicting the landslide susceptibility of Mugling-Narayanghat road section. These landslide susceptibility maps can be used for preliminary land use planning and hazard mitigation purpose.
WOS:000312087100009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="22">
<title>A comparative study on the landslide susceptibility mapping using evidential belief function and weights of evidence models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>The purpose of this study is to produce landslide susceptibility map of a landslide-prone area (Daguan County, China) by evidential belief function (EBF) model and weights of evidence (WoE) model to compare the results obtained. For this purpose, a landslide inventory map was constructed mainly based on earlier reports and aerial photographs, as well as, by carrying out field surveys. A total of 194 landslides were mapped. Then, the landslide inventory was randomly split into a training dataset; 70&#37; (136 landslides) for training the models and the remaining 30&#37; (58 landslides) was used for validation purpose. Then, a total number of 14 conditioning factors, such as slope angle, slope aspect, general curvature, plan curvature, profile curvature, altitude, distance from rivers, distance from roads, distance from faults, lithology, normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI), sediment transport index (STI), stream power index (SPI), and topographic wetness index (TWI) were used in the analysis. Subsequently, landslide susceptibility maps were produced using the EBF and WoE models. Finally, the validation of landslide susceptibility map was accomplished with the area under the curve (AUC) method. The success rate curve showed that the area under the curve for EBF and WoE models were of 80.19&#37; and 80.75&#37; accuracy, respectively. Similarly, the validation result showed that the susceptibility map using EBF model has the prediction accuracy of 80.09&#37;, while for WoE model, it was 79.79&#37;. The results of this study showed that both landslide susceptibility maps obtained were successful and would be useful for regional spatial planning as well as for land cover planning.
WOS:000375930100013
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="23">
<title>Landslide susceptibility zonation in Greece</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s11069-012-0381-4</url>
<snippet>The objective of this study is to perform a preliminary national-scale assessment of the landslide susceptibility in Greece using a landslide inventory derived from historical archives. The effects of controlling factors on landslide susceptibility combined with multivariate statistics have been evaluated using GIS aided mapping techniques. Thousand six hundred thirty-five landslide occurrences, mainly earth slides obtained from Public Authorities archives, covering a long time period were recorded and digitally stored using a spatial relational database management system. Ten landslide predisposing factors (predictors) were identified, while digital thematic maps on the spatial distribution of those factors were generated. The correlation between the landslide locations and predictor classes was analyzed by using the Landslide Relative Frequency. R-mode factor analysis was applied to study the interrelations between predictors (independent variables) while weighting coefficients were determined. Landslide susceptibility was derived from an algorithm which modeled the influence of predictors, and a susceptibility map was compiled. The landslide susceptibility map was verified using a data set of 375 new landslide locations. It is the first comprehensive attempt to illustrate the landslide susceptibility in the total country based on the interpretation of historical data only.
WOS:000312087100030
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="24">
<title>Earthquake induced landslide susceptibility mapping using an integrated ensemble frequency ratio and logistic regression models in West Sumatera Province, Indonesia</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.catena.2014.02.005</url>
<snippet>An 8 Richter Scale (RS) earthquake struck West Sumatra on Wednesday, 30 September 2009, at 17.16 pm which led to huge number of landslides. Hence a comprehensive landslide susceptibility mapping (LSM) should be produced in order to reduce the damages to people and infrastructures. In the international landslide literature, various statistical methods such as frequency ratio (FR) and logistic regression (LR) have been widely used individually for LSM, but they have some weaknesses. FR which is able to perform bivariate statistical analysis (BSA) assesses the influence of classes of each conditioning factor on landslide occurrence. However, the correlation between the factors is mostly neglected. On the other hand, LR is able to analyze the relationship among the factors while it is not capable to evaluate the classes of each landslide conditioning factor. This paper aims to propose an ensemble method of FR and LR in order to overcome their weak points. For LSM, a landslide inventory map with a total of 87 landslide locations was extracted from various sources. Then the landslide inventory was randomly divided into two datasets 70&#37; for training the models and the remaining 30&#37; was used for validation purpose. The landslide conditioning factors consist of: altitude, curvature, river, SPI, rainfall, soil type, soil texture, land use/cover (LULC), peak ground acceleration (PGA), geology, slope, aspect, lineament and topographic wetness index (TWI). Four PGA of 7.5, 8, 8.6 and 9 were acquired and PGA 8 which was related to the 2009 earthquake was used to generate the model. Finally, the produced landslide susceptibility maps were validated using an area under the (ROC) curve method. For the model which was derived by PGA 8, the validation results showed 84&#37; and 78&#37; success and prediction rates respectively. Furthermore, the prediction rates for the models made by PGA 7.2, 8.6 and 9 are 79&#37;, 78&#37; and 81&#37; respectively. The result proved the reasonable efficiency of the proposed method for earthquake induced landslide susceptibility mapping. Also the proposed ensemble method can be used in other hazard studies as it is capable to produce rapid and accurate assessment for disaster management and decision making. (C) 2014 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000347598000012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="25">
<title>A hybrid fuzzy weight of evidence method in landslide susceptibility analysis on the Wuyuan area, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2017.04.002</url>
<snippet>The present study proposed a hybrid fuzzy weight of evidence model for constructing a landslide susceptibility map in the Wuyuan area, China, where disastrous landslide events have occurred. The model combines the knowledge of experts obtained through a fuzzy logic approach and a hybrid weight of evidence method. The estimated knowledge-based fuzzy membership value of each environmental variable is combined with data based conditional probabilities to derive fuzzy posterior probabilities and landslide susceptibility. The developed model was compared with a landslide susceptibility map produced using the data-driven weight of evidence method, based on 510 landslide and non-landslide sites. The sites were identified by analyzing airborne imagery, field investigation and previous studies. Landside susceptibility for these sites was analyzed using 10 geoenvironmental variables: slope, aspect, lithology, soil, rainfall, plan curvature, the normalized difference vegetation index, distance to roads, distance to rivers and distance to faults. The resultant hybrid fuzzy weight of evidence method showed high predictive power, with the area under the success and predictive curves being 0.770 and 0.746, respectively. Additional analyses showed that the developed model could work effectively even with limited data.
WOS:000405056100001
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="26">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping by geographical information system-based multivariate statistical and deterministic models: in an artificial reservoir area at Northern Turkey</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-015-2142-7</url>
<snippet>In Turkey, landslide phenomenon is one of the most important natural hazards. Due to landslide occurrence, several landforms and man-made structures are adversely affected and may cause many injuries and loss of life. In this context, landslide susceptibility assessment is an important task to determine susceptible areas to landslide occurrence. Especially, several dam reservoir areas in Turkey are threatened by landslide phenomena. For this reason, in this study, a dam reservoir area, located in the northern part of Turkey, was selected and investigated in the point of view of landslide susceptibility assessment. A landslide susceptibility assessment for Kurtun Dam reservoir area (Gumushane, North Turkey) was carried out by geographical information system (GIS)-based statistical and deterministic models. For this purpose, logistic regression (LR) and stability index mapping (SINMAP) methodologies were applied. In this context, eight contributing factors such as altitude, lithology, slope gradient, slope aspect, distance to drainage, distance to lineament, stream power index (SPI) and topographical wetness index (TWI) were considered. After assessment of these parameters by LR and SINMAP methods in a GIS environment, two landslide susceptibility maps were obtained. Then, the produced maps were analyzed for validation purpose. For this purpose, area under curvature (AUC) approach was used. At the end of this process, the AUC values of 0.73 and 0.65 were found for LR and SINMAP models, respectively. For the performance of the SINMAP model, statistical results produced by the model were also considered. In this context, landslide density of the stability index (SI) classes were taken into account, and it was determined that 89.5 &#37; of the landslides fall into lower and upper threshold classes which almost correspond to moderate and high susceptibility classes. These two validation values indicate that the accuracy of landslide susceptibility maps is acceptable, and the maps are feasible for further natural hazard management affairs in the area.
WOS:000371380500083
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="27">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping using analytic hierarchy process and information value methods along a highway road section in Constantine, Algeria</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-017-2980-6</url>
<snippet>This research work deals with the landslide susceptibility assessment using Analytic hierarchy process (AHP) and information value (IV) methods along a highway road section in Constantine region, NE Algeria. The landslide inventory map which has a total of 29 single landslide locations was created based on historical information, aerial photo interpretation, remote sensing images, and extensive field surveys. The different landslide influencing geoenvironmental factors considered for this study are lithology, slope gradient, slope aspect, distance from faults, land use, distance from streams, and geotechnical parameters. A thematic layer map is generated for every geoenvironmental factor using Geographic Information System (GIS); the lithological units and the distance from faults maps were extracted from the geological database of the region. The slope gradient, slope aspect, and distance from streams were calculated from the Digital Elevation Model (DEM). Contemporary land use map was derived from satellite images and field study. Concerning the geotechnical parameters maps, they were determined making use of the geotechnical data from laboratory tests. The analysis of the relationships between the landslide-related factors and the landslide events was then carried out in GIS environment. The AUC plot showed that the susceptibility maps had a success rate of 77 and 66&#37; for IV and AHP models, respectively. For that purpose, the IV model is better in predicting the occurrence of landslides than AHP one. Therefore, the information value method could be used as a landslide susceptibility mapping zonation method along other sections of the A1 highway.
WOS:000400266200010
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="28">
<title>Evaluation of different machine learning models for predicting and mapping the susceptibility of gully erosion</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2017.09.006</url>
<snippet>Gully erosion constitutes a serious problem for land degradation in a wide range of environments. The main objective of this research was to compare the performance of seven state-of-the-art machine learning models (SVM with four kernel types, BP-ANN, RF, and BRT) to model the occurrence of gully erosion in the Kashkan-Poldokhtar Watershed, Iran. In the first step, a gully inventory map consisting of 65 gully polygons was prepared through field surveys. Three different sample data sets (S1, S2, and S3), including both positive and negative cells (70&#37; for training and 30&#37; for validation), were randomly prepared to evaluate the robustness of the models. To model the gully erosion susceptibility, 12 geo-environmental factors were selected as predictors. Finally, the goodness-of-fit and prediction skill of the models were evaluated by different criteria, including efficiency percent, kappa coefficient, and the area under the ROC curves (AUC). In terms of accuracy, the RF, RBF-SVM, BRT, and P-SVM models performed excellently both in the degree of fitting and in predictive performance (AUC values well above 0.9), which resulted in accurate predictions. Therefore, these models can be used in other gully erosion studies, as they are capable of rapidly producing accurate and robust gully erosion susceptibility maps (GESMs) for decision-making and soil and water management practices. Furthermore, it was found that performance of RF and RBF-SVM for modelling gully erosion occurrence is quite stable when the learning and validation samples are changed. (C) 2017 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000415771900009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="29">
<title>Assessment of the effects of training data selection on the landslide susceptibility mapping: a comparison between support vector machine (SVM), logistic regression (LR) and artificial neural networks (ANN)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/19475705.2017.1407368</url>
<snippet>Landslide is a natural hazard that results in many economic damages and human losses every year. Numerous researchers have studied landslide susceptibility mapping (LSM), each attempting to improve the accuracy of the final outputs. However, few studies have been published on the training data selection effects on the LSM. Thus, this study assesses the training landslides random selection effects on support vector machine (SVM) accuracy, logistic regression (LR) and artificial neural networks (ANN) models for LSM in a catchment at the Dodangeh watershed, Mazandaran province, Iran. A 160 landslide locations inventory was collected by Geological Survey of Iran for this investigation. Different methods were implemented to define the landslide locations, such as inventory reports, satellite images and field survey. Moreover, 14 landslide conditioning factors were considered in the analysis of landslide susceptibility. These factors include curvature, plan curvature, profile curvature, altitude, slope angle, slope aspect, distance to faults, distance to stream, topographic wetness index, stream power index, terrain roughness index, sediment transport index, lithology and land use. The results show that the random landslide training data selection affected the parameter estimations of the SVM, LR and ANN algorithms. The results also show that the training samples selection had an effect on the accuracy of the susceptibility model because landslide conditioning factors vary according to the geographic locations in the study area. The LR model was found to be less sensitive than the SVM and ANN models to the training samples selection. Validation results showed that SVM and LR models outperformed the ANN model for all scenarios. The average overall accuracy of LR, SVM and ANN models are 81.42&#37;, 79.82&#37; and 70.2&#37;, respectively.
WOS:000428252700004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="30">
<title>APPLICATION OF ARTIFICIAL NEURAL NETWORK SYSTEM BASED ON ANFIS USING GIS FOR PREDICTING FOREST ROAD NETWORK SUITABILITY MAPPING</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/</url>
<snippet>There are different factors which affect the well-planning of forest road networks and originated from both general and regional characteristics. It is necessary to support the decision maker effectively by considering the selected criteria during the process of planning the forest roads in the forest areas which are located in the mountainous regions. So, first of all these factors need to be ranked according to the significance. This study is intended to reveal the forest road network plan alternatives which have a high predictive power in planning by considering the criteria that affect the planning when the forest road planning is made. To this end, the forest management chief, which is the smallest forest management unit within Turkey, has been selected as the sample area. Nine criteria affecting the forest road network planning of this units were evaluated via Geographic Information Systems (GIS) and Adaptive Network Fuzzy Inference System (ANFIS) and six different forest road network models were established. The AUC values of the generated models are between the range of 0,654 and 0,845. The most appropriate ANFIS model was determined as model 4 which comprises elevation, slope, distance village and NDVI criteria. The multi-directional approach was used to reflect the effect of factors on forest network planning via GIS, artificial neural networks and fuzzy logic. Furthermore, the factors employed in the developed models can be diversified at the regional level and utilized by the implementers or decision makers in forest road network planning.
WOS:000429081700039
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="31">
<title>Prioritization of landslide conditioning factors and its spatial modeling in Shangnan County, China using GIS-based data mining algorithms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10064-017-1004-9</url>
<snippet>The main objective of the current study is to apply a random forest (RF) data-driven model and prioritization of landslide conditioning factors according to this method and its comparison to a multivariate adaptive regression spline (MARS) model for landslide susceptibility mapping in China. For this purpose, at first, landslide locations were identified by earlier reports, aerial photographs, and field surveys and a total of 348 landslides were mapped from various sources in GIS. Then, the landslide inventory was randomly split into a training dataset (70&#37; = 244 landslides) and the remaining (30&#37; = 104 landslides) were used for validation. In this study, 12 landslide conditioning factors were applied to detect the most susceptible areas. These factors were slope aspect, altitude, distance to faults, lithology, normalized difference vegetation index, plan curvature, profile curvature, distance to rivers, distance to roads, slope angle, stream power index, and topographic wetness index. The relationship between each conditioning factor and landslide was finalized using a frequency ration (FR) model. Subsequently, landslide-susceptible areas were mapped using the MARS and RF models. The results revealed that the most important conditioning factors according to the accuracy measure (mean decrease) of the RF model are lithology (23.47&#37;), distance to faults (22.21&#37;), and altitude (19.58&#37;). We also notice that altitude (19.04&#37;), distance to faults (18.83&#37;), and distance to roads (15.29&#37;) have the highest importance according to the Gini measure. Finally, the accuracy of the landslide susceptibility maps produced from the two models was verified using a receiver operating characteristics curve. The results showed that the landslide susceptibility map produced using the MARS model has a higher prediction rate than RF by area under the curve values of 87.51 and 77.32&#37;, respectively. According to the validation results, the map produced by the MARS model exhibits the better accuracy and could be proposed for land-use planning in the study area.
WOS:000431300600012
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="32">
<title>A comparative study for landslide susceptibility mapping using GIS-based multi-criteria decision analysis (MCDA), logistic regression (LR) and association rule mining (ARM)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.enggeo.2015.09.007</url>
<snippet>Landslide susceptibility mapping is one of the crucial stages of landslide hazard and risk assessment. Moreover, the susceptibility maps assist planners, local administrations, and decision makers in disaster planning. Various approaches have been applied in the literature to increase the accuracy of landslide susceptibility maps. The determination of suitable susceptibility mapping method plays critical role for obtaining required accuracy. In this study, the performances of three quantitative susceptibility mapping methods are evaluated. The logistic regression (LR) analysis is the typical example of statistical methods, while GIS-based multi-criteria decision analyses (MCDA) and association rule mining (ARM) are the examples of heuristic and data mining methods, respectively. The susceptibility maps based on the three methods are obtained for Savsat in Artvin province (NE Turkey) where the region has intense landslides. The landslide influencing parameters for the study area are lithology, land use/land cover, soil type, erosion, altitude, slope, aspect, distance to drainage, soil depth, distance to fault, distance to road. The models for the three methods are then compared and evaluated by using pixel-based evaluation metrics. Results showed that ARM provides a higher quality percent (QP), whereas percent of damage detection (PDD) is higher for LR method. The lowest QP is obtained by GIS-based MCDA. It is found that LR and ARM methods are better than GIS-based MCDA in modeling the landslide susceptibility and they can be integrated to obtain better performance. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000372688600005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="33">
<title>GIS-based landslide susceptibility mapping with logistic regression, analytical hierarchy process, and combined fuzzy and support vector machine methods: a case study from Wolong Giant Panda Natural Reserve, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10064-015-0786-x</url>
<snippet>Landslides, as one of the most destructive natural phenomena, distribute extensively in Wolong Giant Panda Natural Reserve and cause damage to both humans and endangered species. Therefore, landslide susceptibility zonation (LSZ) mapping is necessary for government agencies and decision makers to select suitable locations for giant pandas. The main purpose of this study is to produce landside susceptibility maps using logistic regression (LR), analytical hierarchy process (AHP), and a combined fuzzy and support vector machine (F-SVM) hybrid method based on geographic information systems (GIS). A total of 1773 landslide scarps larger than one cell (25 9 25 m(2)) were selected in the landslide inventory mapping, 70 &#37; of which were selected at random to be used as test data, and the other 30 &#37; were used as validation. Topographical, geological, and hydrographical data were collected, processed, and constructed into a spatial database. Nine conditioning factors were chosen as influencing factors related to landslide occurrence: slope degree, aspect, altitude, profile curvature, geology and lithology, distance from faults, distance from rivers, distance from roads, and normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI). Landslide susceptible areas were analyzed and mapped using the landslide occurrence factors by different methods. For conventional assessment, weights and rates of the affecting factors were assigned based on experience and knowledge of experts. In order to reduce the subjectivity, a combined fuzzy and SVM hybrid model was generated for LSZ in this paper. In this approach, the rates of each thematic layer were generated by the fuzzy similarity method, and weights were created by the SVM method. To confirm the practicality of the susceptibility map produced by this improved method, a comparison study with LR, AHP was assessed by means of their validation. The outcome indicated that the combined fuzzy and SVM method (accuracy is 85.73 &#37;) is better than AHP (accuracy is 78.84 &#37;), whereas it is relatively similar to LR (accuracy is 84.55 &#37;). The susceptibility map based on combined the fuzzy and SVM approach also shows that 5.8 &#37; of the study area is assigned as very highly susceptible areas, and 17.8 &#37; of the study area is assigned as highly susceptible areas.
WOS:000384816300004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="34">
<title>Mapping landslide susceptibility with frequency ratio, statistical index, and weights of evidence models: a case study in northern Iran</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-017-6839-7</url>
<snippet>The main objective of this study is to investigate potential application of frequency ratio (FR), weights of evidence (WoE), and statistical index (SI) models for landslide susceptibility mapping in a part of Mazandaran Province, Iran. First, a landslide inventory map was constructed from various sources. The landslide inventory map was then randomly divided in a ratio of 70/30 for training and validation of the models, respectively. Second, 13 landslide conditioning factors including slope degree, slope aspect, altitude, plan curvature, stream power index, topographic wetness index, sediment transport index, topographic roughness index, lithology, distance from streams, faults, roads, and land use type were prepared, and the relationships between these factors and the landslide inventory map were extracted by using the mentioned models. Subsequently, the multi-class weighted factors were used to generate landslide susceptibility maps. Finally, the susceptibility maps were verified and compared using several methods including receiver operating characteristic curve with the areas under the curve (AUC), landslide density, and spatially agreed area analyses. The success rate curve showed that the AUC for FR, WoE, and SI models was 81.51, 79.43, and 81.27, respectively. The prediction rate curve demonstrated that the AUC achieved by the three models was 80.44, 77.94, and 79.55, respectively. Although the sensitivity analysis using the FR model revealed that the modeling process was sensitive to input factors, the accuracy results suggest that the three models used in this study can be effective approaches for landslide susceptibility mapping in Mazandaran Province, and the resultant susceptibility maps are trustworthy for hazard mitigation strategies.
WOS:000406241000032
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="35">
<title>Spatial model integration for shallow landslide susceptibility and its runout using a GIS-based approach in Yongin, Korea</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10106049.2016.1155658</url>
<snippet>Rainfall-triggered shallow landslide is very common in Korean mountains and the socioeconomic impact is much higher than in the past due to population pressure in hazardous zones. Present study is an attempt toward the development of a methodology for the integration of shallow landslide susceptibility zones and runout zones that could be reached by mobilized mass. Landslide occurrence areas in Yongin were determined based on the interpretation of aerial photographs and extensive field surveys. Nineteen landslide-related factors maps were collected and analysed in geographic information system environment. Among 109 identified landslides, about 85&#37; randomly selected training landslide data from inventory map was used to generate an evidential belief function model and remaining 15&#37; landslides were used to validate the shallow landslide susceptibility map. The resulting susceptibility map had a success rate of 89.2&#37; and a predictive accuracy of 92.1&#37;. A runout propagation from high susceptible area was obtained from the modified multiple-flow direction algorithm. A matrix was used to integrate the shallow landslide susceptibility classes and the runout probable zone. Thus, each pixel had a susceptibility class in relation to its failure probability and runout susceptibility class. The study of landslide potential and its propagation can be used to obtain a spatial prediction for landslides, which could contribute to landslide risk mitigation.
WOS:000395143900005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="36">
<title>Assessment of Landslide-Prone Areas and Their Zonation Using Logistic Regression, LogitBoost, and NaiveBayes Machine-Learning Algorithms</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.3390/su10103697</url>
<snippet>The occurrence of landslide in the hilly region of South Korea is a matter of serious concern. This study tries to produce landslide susceptibility maps for Jumunjin Country in South Korea. Three machine learning algorithms, namely Logistic Regression (LR), LogitBoost (LB), and NaiveBayes (NB) are used, and their final model outcomes are compared to each other. Firstly, a landslide inventory map and the associated input data layers of the landslide conditioning factors were developed based on field verification, historical records, and high-resolution remote-sensing data in the geographic information system (GIS) environment. Seventeen landslide conditioning factors were prepared, including aspect, slope, altitude, maximum curvature, profile curvature, topographic wetness index (TWI), topographic positioning index (TPI), distance from fault, convexity, forest type, forest diameter, forest density, land use/land cover, lithology, soil, flow accumulation, and mid slope position. The result showed that the area under the curve (AUC) values of LR, LB, and NB models were 84.2&#37;, 70.7&#37;, and 85.2&#37;, respectively. The results revealed that the LR and LB models produced reasonable accuracy than respect to NB model in landslide susceptibility assessment. The final susceptibility maps would be useful for preliminary land-use planning and hazard mitigation purpose.
WOS:000448559400339
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="37">
<title>GIS-based groundwater spring potential assessment and mapping in the Birjand Township, southern Khorasan Province, Iran</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10040-013-1089-6</url>
<snippet>Three statistical models-frequency ratio (FR), weights-of-evidence (WofE) and logistic regression (LR)-produced groundwater-spring potential maps for the Birjand Township, southern Khorasan Province, Iran. In total, 304 springs were identified in a field survey and mapped in a geographic information system (GIS), out of which 212 spring locations were randomly selected to be modeled and the remaining 92 were used for the model evaluation. The effective factors-slope angle, slope aspect, elevation, topographic wetness index (TWI), stream power index (SPI), slope length (LS), plan curvature, lithology, land use, and distance to river, road, fault-were derived from the spatial database. Using these effective factors, groundwater spring potential was calculated using the three models, and the results were plotted in ArcGIS. The receiver operating characteristic (ROC) curves were drawn for spring potential maps and the area under the curve (AUC) was computed. The final results indicated that the FR model (AUC = 79.38 &#37;) performed better than the WofE (AUC = 75.69 &#37;) and LR (AUC = 63.71 &#37;) models. Sensitivity and factor analyses concluded that the bivariate statistical index model (i.e. FR) can be used as a simple tool in the assessment of groundwater spring potential when a sufficient number of data are obtained.
WOS:000334933000009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="38">
<title>A comparison between index of entropy and catastrophe theory methods for mapping groundwater potential in an arid region</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s10661-015-4801-2</url>
<snippet>In this study, index of entropy and catastrophe theory methods were used for demarcating groundwater potential in an arid region using weighted linear combination techniques in geographical information system (GIS) environment. A case study from Badra area in the eastern part of central of Iraq was analyzed and discussed. Six factors believed to have influence on groundwater occurrence namely elevation, slope, aquifer transmissivity and storativity, soil, and distance to fault were prepared as raster thematic layers to facility integration into GIS environment. The factors were chosen based on the availability of data and local conditions of the study area. Both techniques were used for computing weights and assigning ranks vital for applying weighted linear combination approach. The results of application of both modes indicated that the most influential groundwater occurrence factors were slope and elevation. The other factors have relatively smaller values of weights implying that these factors have a minor role in groundwater occurrence conditions. The groundwater potential index (GPI) values for both models were classified using natural break classification scheme into five categories: very low, low, moderate, high, and very high. For validation of generated GPI, the relative operating characteristic (ROC) curves were used. According to the obtained area under the curve, the catastrophe model with 78 &#37; prediction accuracy was found to perform better than entropy model with 77 &#37; prediction accuracy. The overall results indicated that both models have good capability for predicting groundwater potential zones.
WOS:000360313000030
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="39">
<title>Remote sensing and GIS-based landslide susceptibility mapping using frequency ratio, logistic regression, and fuzzy logic methods at the central Zab basin, Iran</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-015-4028-0</url>
<snippet>A remote sensing and geographic information system-based study has been carried out to map areas susceptible to landslides using three statistical models, frequency ratio (FR), logistic regression (LR), and fuzzy logic at the central Zab basin in the mountainsides in the southwest West Azerbaijan province in Iran. Ten factors such as slope, aspect, elevation, lithology, normalized difference vegetation index (NDVI), land cover, precipitation, distance to fault, distance to drainage, and distance to road were considered. Landsat ETM+ images were used for NDVI and land cover maps. A landslide inventory map of the study area was identified by a SPOT 5 satellite after which fuzzy algebraic operators were applied to the fuzzy membership values of landslide susceptibility mapping. In addition, FR and LR models were applied to determine the landslide susceptibility. The three models are validated using the receiver operating characteristic and the area under which curve values were calculated. The validation results showed that the LR model (accuracy is 96 &#37;) has better prediction than fuzzy logic (accuracy is 95 &#37;) and FR (accuracy is 94 &#37;) models. Also, among the fuzzy operators, the gamma operator (lambda = 0.975) showed the best accuracy (94.64 &#37;) while the fuzzy OR operator when applied showed the worst accuracy (85.11 &#37;).
WOS:000355142800079
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="40">
<title>Application of frequency ratio, weights of evidence and evidential belief function models in landslide susceptibility mapping</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1080/10106049.2016.1165294</url>
<snippet>The landslide hazard occurred in Taibai County has the characteristics of the typical landslides in mountain hinterland. The slopes mainly consist of residual sediments and locate along the highway. Most of them are in the less stable state and in high risk during rainfall in flood season especially. The main purpose of this paper is to produce landslide susceptibility maps for Taibai County (China). In the first stage, a landslide inventory map and the input layers of the landslide conditioning factors were prepared in the geographic information system supported by field investigations and remote sensing data. The landslides conditioning factors considered for the study area were slope angle, altitude, slope aspect, plan curvature, profile curvature, distance to faults, distance to rivers, distance to roads, normalized difference vegetation index, lithological unit, rainfall and land use. Subsequently, the thematic data layers of conditioning factors were integrated by frequency ratio (FR), weights of evidence (WOE) and evidential belief function (EBF) models. As a result, landslide susceptibility maps were obtained. In order to compare the predictive ability of these three models, a validation procedure was conducted. The curves of cumulative area percentage of ordered index values vs. the cumulative percentage of landslide numbers were plotted and the values of area under the curve (AUC) were calculated. The predictive ability was characterized by the AUC values and it indicates that all these models considered have relatively similar and high accuracies. The success rate of FR, WOE and EBF models was 0.9161, 0.9132 and 0.9129, while the prediction rate of the three models was 0.9061, 0.9052 and 0.9007, respectively. Considering the accuracy and simplicity comprehensively, the FR model is the optimum method. These landslide susceptibility maps can be used for preliminary land use planning and hazard mitigation purpose.
WOS:000399646500003
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="41">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping based on frequency ratio and logistic regression models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-012-0526-5</url>
<snippet>The aim of this study is to apply and compare a probability model, frequency ratio and statistical model, and a logistic regression to Sajaroud area, Northern Iran using geographic information system. Landslide locations of the study area were detected from interpretation of aerial photographs and field surveys. Landslide-related factors such as elevation, slope gradient, slope aspect, slope curvature, rainfall, distance to fault, distance to drainage, distance to road, land use, and geology were calculated from the topographic and geology map and LANDSAT ETM satellite imagery. The spatial relationships between the landslide location and each landslide-related factor were analyzed and then landslide susceptibility maps were produced using the frequency ratio and forward stepwise logistic regression methods. Finally, the maps were tested and compared using known landslide locations, and success rates were calculated. Predicted accuracy values for frequency ratio (79.48&#37;) and logistic regression models showed that the map obtained from frequency ratio model is more accurate than the logistic regression (77.4&#37;) model. The models used in this study have shown a great deal of importance for watershed management and land use planning.
WOS:000320662000028
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="42">
<title>Landslide hazard zonation using analytical hierarchy process along National Highway-3 in mid Himalayas of Himachal Pradesh, India</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-018-7896-2</url>
<snippet>Landslide zonation studies emphasize on preparation of landslide hazard zonation maps considering major instability factors contributing to occurrence of landslides. This paper deals with geographic information system-based landslide hazard zonation in mid Himalayas of Himachal Pradesh from Mandi to Kullu by considering nine relevant instability factors to develop the hazard zonation map. Analytical hierarchy process was applied to assign relative weightages over all ranges of instability factors of the slopes in study area. To generate landslide hazard zonation map, layers in geographic information system were created corresponding to each instability factor. An inventory of existing major landslides in the study area was prepared and combined with the landslide hazard zonation map for validation purpose. The validation of the model was made using area under curve technique and reveals good agreement between the produced hazard map and previous landslide inventory with prediction accuracy of 79.08&#37;. Thelandslide hazard zonation map was classified by natural break classifier into very low hazard, low hazard, moderate hazard, high hazard and very high landslide hazard classes in geographic information system depending upon the frequency of occurrence of landslides in each class. The resultant hazard zonation map shows that 14.30&#37; of the area lies in very high hazard zone followed by 15.97&#37; in high hazard zone. The proposed model provides the best-fit classification using hierarchical approach for the causative factors of landslides having complex structure. The developed hazard zonation map is useful for landslide preparedness, land-use planning, and social-economic and sustainable development of the region.
WOS:000447506500002
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="43">
<title>Flood hazard mapping in Jamaica using principal component analysis and logistic regression</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-016-5323-0</url>
<snippet>Jamaica, the third largest island in the Caribbean, has been affected significantly by flooding and flood-related damage. Hence assessing the probability of flooding and susceptibility of a place to flood hazard has become a vital part of planning and development. In addition to heavy rainfall from tropical storms and Atlantic hurricanes, several terrestrial factors play significant roles in flooding, including local geology, geomorphology, hydrology and land-use. In this study, a GIS-based multi-criteria statistical methodology was developed to quantify hazard potential and to map flood characteristics. Fourteen factors potentially responsible for flooding were identified and used as initial input in a hybrid model that combined principal component analysis with logistic regression and frequency distribution analysis. Of these factors, seven explained 65 &#37; of the variation in the data: elevation, slope angle, slope aspect, flow accumulation, a topographic wetness index, proximity to a stream network, and hydrostratigraphic units. These were used to prepare the islands first map of flood hazard potential. Hazard potential was classified from very low to very high, nearly one-fifth (19.4 &#37;) of the island was included within high or very high flood hazard zones. Further analysis revealed that areas prone to flooding are often low-lying and flat, or have shallow north-or northwest-facing slopes, are in close proximity to the stream network, and are situated on underlying impermeable lithology. The multi-criteria hybrid approach developed could classify 86.8 &#37; of flood events correctly and produced a satisfactory validation result based on the receiver operating characteristic curve. The statistical method can be easily repeated and refined upon the availability of additional or higher quality data such as a high resolution digital elevation model. Additionally, the approach used in this study can be adopted to evaluate flood hazard in countries with similar characteristics, landscapes and climatic conditions, such as other Caribbean or Pacific Small Island Developing States.
WOS:000372251000016
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="44">
<title>SPATIAL RESOLUTION EFFECTS OF DIGITAL TERRAIN MODELS ON LANDSLIDE SUSCEPTIBILITY ANALYSIS</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.5194/isprsarchives-XLI-B8-33-2016</url>
<snippet>The purposes of this study are to identify the maximum number of correlated factors for landslide susceptibility mapping and to evaluate landslide susceptibility at Sihjhong river catchment in the southern Taiwan, integrating two techniques, namely certainty factor (CF) and artificial neural network (ANN). The landslide inventory data of the Central Geological Survey (CGS, MOEA) in 2004-2014 and two digital elevation model (DEM) datasets including a 5-meter LiDAR DEM and a 30-meter Aster DEM were prepared. We collected thirteen possible landslide-conditioning factors. Considering the multi-collinearity and factor redundancy, we applied the CF approach to optimize these thirteen conditioning factors. We hypothesize that if the CF values of the thematic factor layers are positive, it implies that these conditioning factors have a positive relationship with the landslide occurrence. Therefore, based on this assumption and positive CF values, seven conditioning factors including slope angle, slope aspect, elevation, terrain roughness index (TRI), terrain position index (TPI), total curvature, and lithology have been selected for further analysis. The results showed that the optimized-factors model provides a better accuracy for predicting landslide susceptibility in the study area. In conclusion, the optimized-factors model is suggested for selecting relative factors of landslide occurrence.
WOS:000393156000005
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="45">
<title>Groundwater spring potential mapping using bivariate statistical model and GIS in the Taleghan Watershed, Iran</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12517-013-1161-5</url>
<snippet>The aim of the current study was to produce groundwater spring potential map using a bivariate statistical model (frequency ratio) and geographical information system (GIS) in the Taleghan Watershed, Alborz Province, Iran. Firstly, field surveys were done for identifying and springs inventory mapping. In total, 457 springs were identified and mapped in GIS; out of that, 320 (70 &#37;) locations were selected for training and the remaining 137 (30 &#37;) cases were used for the model validation. The effective factors on the groundwater spring such as: slope percent, slope aspect, altitude, topographic wetness index, stream power index, slope length, plan curvature, distance from rivers, distance from roads, distance from faults, lithology, land use, soil hydrology groups, and drainage density were derived from the spatial database. Using the above effective factors, groundwater spring potential mapping was calculated using FR model as a bivariate statistical model, and the results were plotted in Arc GIS. Eventually, the receiver operating characteristic curve was drawn for spring potential map and the area under the curve (AUC) was figured. Validation of results indicated that the frequency ratio model (AUC=75.99 &#37;) performed fairly good predication accuracy. The results of groundwater spring potential map may be helpful for planners and engineers in water resource management and land use planning.
WOS:000350489900025
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="46">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping based on GIS and support vector machine models for the Qianyang County, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-015-5093-0</url>
<snippet>The main purpose of this study is to produce reliable susceptibility maps using GIS-based support vector machine (SVM) models and compare their performances for the Qianyang County of Baoji City, Shaanxi Province, China. In this paper, with kernel classifiers of linear, polynomial, radial basis function and sigmoid, the four various types were applied in landslide susceptibility mapping. The important input parameters for the landslide susceptibility assessment were acquired from different sources. Firstly, 81 landslide sites were obtained by aerial photographs, earlier reports and field surveys. Then, the landslide inventory was randomly classified into two datasets: 70 &#37; (56 landslides) for training the models and 30 &#37; (25 landslides) for validation purpose. Secondly, 15 landslide conditioning factors were selected (i.e., slope angle, slope aspect, altitude, plan curvature, profile curvature, distance to faults, distance to rivers, distance to roads, NDVI, STI, SPI, TWI, geomorphology, rainfall, and lithology). Subsequently, with four types of kernel function classifiers based on landslide conditioning factors, landslide susceptibility parameters were obtained using SVM models. Finally, the rationality of landslide susceptibility maps was verified using the receiver operating characteristics with both success rate curve and prediction rate curve. The validation results showed that success rates for the four SVM models were 83.15 &#37; (RBF-SVM), 82.72 &#37; (PL-SVM), 81.77 &#37; (LN-SVM), and 79.99 &#37; (SIG-SVM). The prediction rates for the four SVM models were 77.98 &#37; (RBF-SVM), 77.50 &#37; (PL-SVM), 77.07 &#37; (LN-SVM), and 76.08 &#37; (SIG-SVM), respectively. The results showed that the RBF-SVM model had the highest overall performance.
WOS:000372251000025
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="47">
<title>A novel geographical information system-based Ant Miner algorithm model for delineating groundwater flowing artesian well boundary: a case study from Iraqi southern and western deserts</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1007/s12665-017-6876-2</url>
<snippet>The Ant Miner algorithm was compared with the bivariate frequency ratio (FR) and boosted regression trees (BRT) algorithms in terms of its capacity to assess groundwater potential. A geospatial dataset was prepared that contains two components: a flowing well inventory map and eleven factors relevant to groundwater conditions. Average nearest neighbor technique was used to investigate the spatial pattern of flowing wells and to find the appropriate distance between flowing and nonflowing points in the study area. A wrapper approach known as random forest classifier and a filtering approach known as information gain ratio were used to identify the most relevant groundwater factors. The developed models were validated via the area under the operating characteristic curve. Results revealed that the Ant Miner model performed better in terms of both success (0.944) and prediction (0.92) rates compared to FR and BRT. Furthermore, the Ant Miner algorithm derived five simple, easily interpreted rules for predicting groundwater potential that can be used by hydrogeologists for identifying potential groundwater well locations with minimal effort and cost.
WOS:000407545200027
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="48">
<title>Investigation of sinkholes spatial distribution using the weights of evidence method and GIS in the vicinity of Karapinar (Konya, Turkey)</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2015.04.034</url>
<snippet>There are many sinkholes (182) in the vicinity of Karapinar. Approximately 20 large sinkholes (&gt;10 m in diameter) were formed within the Obruk Plateau between 1970 and 2012. The formation of sinkholes is the most important geological hazard in the study area because they can damage engineering structures, settlements, agricultural areas, and eventually be a source of casualties. To date, no study has been conducted on the distribution of sinkholes in this region. In this study, the spatial distribution of the sinkholes and the factors controlling sinkhole development were studied through the use of geographical information systems using a sinkhole inventory and a spatial database containing information on the topography, geology, hydrogeology, and land use. Initially, 182 sinkholes were identified in the area by examining the digital elevation model produced for this study. The sinkholes were verified in the field. Thirty-two factor maps were produced to investigate their relationship with sinkholes using the weights of evidence method. The sinkholes are mainly related to dissolution of the Neogene-age lacustrine Insuyu Formation, consisting of limestone and clayey limestone. Sinkhole frequency increases in the vicinity of drainages (2000-3000 m) and faults (&lt;1000 m) and in areas with lower cover thickness (&lt;50 m). Injuries and property losses caused by sinkhole formation may be prevented or reduced by producing sinkhole susceptibility and risk maps considered the identified controlling factors. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000360511200004
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="49">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping &amp; prediction using Support Vector Machine for Mandakini River Basin, Garhwal Himalaya, India</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2017.06.013</url>
<snippet>In recent years, various machine learning techniques have been applied for landslide susceptibility mapping. In this study, three different variants of support vector machine viz., SVM, Proximal Support Vector Machine (PSVM) and L-2-Support Vector Machine - Modified Finite Newton (L-2-SVM-MFN) have been applied on the Mandakini River Basin in Uttarakhand, India to carry out the landslide susceptibility mapping. Eight thematic layers such as elevation, slope, aspect, drainages, geology/lithology, buffer of thrusts/faults, buffer of streams and soil along with the past landslide data were mapped in GIS environment and used for landslide susceptibility mapping in MATLAB. The study area covering 1625 km(2) has merely 0.11&#37; of area under landslides. There are 2009 pixels for past landslides out of which 50&#37; (1000) landslides were considered as training set while remaining 50&#37; as testing set. The performance of these techniques has been evaluated and the computational results show that L-2-SVM-MFN obtains higher prediction values (0.829) of receiver operating characteristic curve (AUC-area under the curve) as compared to 0.807 for PSVM model and 0.79 for SVM. The results obtained from L-2-SVM-MFN model are found to be superior than other SVM prediction models and suggest the usefulness of this technique to problem of landslide susceptibility mapping where training data is very less. However, these techniques can be used for satisfactory determination of susceptible zones with these inputs.
WOS:000413175000009
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="50">
<title>Quantitative assessment of landslide susceptibility along the Xianshuihe fault zone, Tibetan Plateau, China</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.geomorph.2015.07.012</url>
<snippet>The Xianshuihe fault (XSF) zone is a sinistral-slip fault system on the eastern margin of the Tibetan Plateau, with high Quaternary activity and frequent historic earthquakes. Large landslides along the fault zone have caused substantial damage and are the second-most important regional hazard after earthquakes. A landslide inventory in a 7339-km(2) area along the XSF zone documented 415 landslides and evaluated landslide distribution characteristics using frequency ratio (FR) and weight-of-evidence (WOE) models to map landslide susceptibility. A total of 11 variables were analyzed as input variables: slope angle, slope aspect, altitude, planform curvature, topographic wetness index, distance from active faults, lithology, annual rainfall, distance from rivers, distance from roads, and the NDVI of the study area. Among these factors, the distance from active faults, altitude, slope angle, aspect, lithology, and rainfall were the dominant influencing factors. Assessment of six susceptibility mapping schemes with FR and WOE models using the ROC method showed that, while all six of the model schemes produced good results, on the whole, the FR model performed better than the WOE model. The landslide susceptibility map of the FR model with six variables performed as well as the WOE model with the full 11 variables. Inclusion of more variables did not necessarily translate into a better predictive capability. Several factors typically associated with susceptibility to rainfall-triggered landslides-topographic convergence, rainfall, and topographic wetness index-either did not follow expected patterns (rainfall) or were not good general predictors of landslide locations (topographic convergence and wetness index). In contrast distance to active faults, slope aspect, and topographic divergence were the best predictors as measured by the FR method. This combination points to earthquakes rather than rainfall as the dominant landslide-triggering mechanism in the study area. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000361867900008
</snippet>
</document>

<document id="51">
<title>Landslide susceptibility mapping in Mizunami City, Japan: A comparison between logistic regression, bivariate statistical analysis and multivariate adaptive regression spline models</title>
<url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.catena.2015.08.007</url>
<snippet>Landslides are dangerous natural hazards. Because of their threat, a comprehensive landslide susceptibility map should be produced to reduce the possible damages to people and infrastructure. The quality of landslide susceptibility maps is influenced by many factors, such as the quality of input data and the selection of mathematical models. This study aimed to identify the optimal quantitative method for landslide susceptibility mapping in Mizunami City, Japan. Three mathematical methods, logistic regression (LR), bivariate statistical analysis (BS), and multivariate adaptive regression spline models (MARSplines), were used to create landslide-susceptibility maps by comparing the past landslide distribution and the conditioning factor thematic maps. A landslide inventory map with a total of 222 landslide locations was extracted from aerial photographs provided by NIED (National Research Institute for Earth Science and Disaster Prevention, Japan). Then, the landslide inventory was randomly divided into two datasets: 50&#37; was used for training the models and the remaining 50&#37; for validation purposes. The landslide inventory map provided by NIED and an area under the ROC curve were used to evaluate model performance. We found that the MARSpline method resulted in a better prediction rate (79&#37;) when compared to LR (75&#37;) and BS (77&#37;). In addition, a higher percentage of landslide polygons were found in the high to very high classes using the MARSpline method. Therefore, we concluded that the MARSpline method was the most efficient method for landslide susceptibility mapping in this study area. (C) 2015 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.
WOS:000366225900028
</snippet>
</document>

</searchresult>
